<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Reminders xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <re>
    <c>Think about challenging assumptions - take nothing for granted</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Which parallel worlds do you think can inform your care work?</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Find some time today to reflect back on your ideas so far. Play them back - any new ideas?</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Reflect on which of your enhancements have been effective so far</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Seek to share ideas with your colleagues - play them back to others</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Reflect on an enhancement once you applied it - record further comments on the outcome</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Look to the positives in the ideas - don't be too critical</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>If today you happen to encounter the same problem as yesterday, would you approach it anyhow differently? If yes, it's time to record some ideas!</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Think about how your generated ideas could help your new, inexperienced colleagues</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Ask your colleagues which are their favourite features on the device. Will you discover something new?</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>How about today you share your favourite idea with your best friend at work? </c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Feeling inadequate is good. It means you are out of your comfort zone and becoming creative</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>What is your favourite parallel world? Think about to which situation you are likely to encounter today you may apply it</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Did you recently hear a good story about how your colleague solved a problem with the app? Would you approach it differently? If yes, it's time to record some ideas!</c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Seek to share your enhancement plan via email or Yammer - to do this tap the 'arrow' button in the enhancement plan detail screen. </c>
  </re>
  <re>
    <c>Seek to discover cases from other domains today</c>
  </re>
</Reminders>