"<?xml version=""1.0"" standalone=""yes""?>"
"<MatchedSources responseId=""1"" similarityType=""Eddie"" dataSourceType=""Document"">"
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Late stage dementia and violent outbursts</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Miss Green, a resident experiencing late stage dementia, frequently lashes out at staff (and even relatives) who are supporting her to get washed/eat/drink. There is a risk both to the staff and to the resident herself. Every attempt has been made to find creative ways to stop this behaviour: staff have tried different approaches, tones of voice and routines, but the behaviour continues. External support and advice has also been sought. The behaviour appears not to be an expression of anger directed at any specific aspect of the environment or task being undertaken. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: violent [TreatmentType]: activities [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Violent behaviour; undiagnosed; gentle support; selected support; reduce aggression [SolutionDescription]: Ultimately, in discussion with relatives and outside agencies, it has been agreed that the resident lacked capacity to make decisions, and that, subject to ongoing assessment and exploration of alternative strategies for supporting the resident, a gentle holding down of the arm while the resident is assisted with daily activities was acceptable. Good pratice: study found evidence of staff demonstrating high levels of competence in their ability to reduce aggression, anxiety and distress among residents which, in themselves, had the effect of minimising the need for restraint. Their negotiating, listening and general communication skills were notable. Managers demonstrated how they actively identified members of staff who had personal qualities that the resident responded to positively.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Verbal abuse of other residents</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Charlesworth, a resident with dementia, shouts expletives at other residents on a daily basis. She expresses herself through screaming, and what appear to be aggressive outbursts. The care home is trying to access help from outside agencies to explore the reasons behind this behaviour and is looking at how the environment might be altered to reduce this distressing behaviour. In the meantime, other residents, particularly those with dementia, are becoming distressed and, in some cases, threatening to be violent towards her. There is an identified risk of harm to the resident and to others. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: violent;disruptive;anti-social [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbal abuse; distressed other resident; risk of harm; private area; selected staff; good communication skills [SolutionDescription]: With agreement of the relatives and external agencies (including the safeguarding adults team and DOLS assessor), the resident is encouraged to reside in one area of the care home where other residents cannot hear her; this might require some level of gentle physical encouragement. This is an interim measure while an alternative action is identified with outside support. Good pratice: study found evidence of staff demonstrating high levels of competence in their ability to reduce aggression, anxiety and distress among residents which, in themselves, had the effect of minimising the need for restraint. Their negotiating, listening and general communication skills were notable. Managers demonstrated how they actively identified members of staff who had personal qualities that the resident responded to positively.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Violent behaviour needing restraint</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Townsend had to be physically restrained because he attacked a member of staff and one of the residents. He had to be physically removed from the scene and taken to his room because of the high risk of continued violence. The MCA Code of Practice, section 6.43 would support staff with these actions. Under common law staff are able to take appropriate and necessary action to restrain or remove the person, in order to prevent harm, both to that person and to anyone else. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: violent [TreatmentType]: one-off [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Physical violence; restraint; selected staff; good communication skills [SolutionDescription]: Immediate outside help was requested but the incident was a one-off and did not occur again. Good pratice: study found evidence of staff demonstrating high levels of competence in their ability to reduce aggression, anxiety and distress among residents which, in themselves, had the effect of minimising the need for restraint. Their negotiating, listening and general communication skills were notable. Managers demonstrated how they actively identified members of staff who had personal qualities that the resident responded to positively.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1004</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Accessing resident rooms without permission</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident has dementia and is used to walking around the care home. Despite the best efforts of the home to create purposeful walking where residents gain stimulation from being in certain areas of the home, this resident has the habit of walking into other residents? rooms and urinating on the beds. This is particularly distressing for those residents who are bed bound. Clearly advice needs to be sought to reduce the effects of such behaviour on other residents. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Accessing resident rooms; private spaces; gentle physical persuasion; seeking something [SolutionDescription]: Manual restraint, in the form of ?gentle physical persuasion?, was sometimes perceived as necessary to protect the rights of other residents or the safety of an individual resident. Typically, staff would try to encourage residents to remain in the lounge rather than going to other areas of the home to make it easier for them to monitor their well-being. There was clearly a need to explore why the resident was walking around the home, and whether he was searching for the toilet. There are resources available to help care homes to support purposeful walking. The use of Dementia Care Mapping could be adopted in these cases to really understand why the resident is walking into other people?s rooms.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1005</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Physical intimidation</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A tall male resident with dementia had walked across the lounge and was standing over a slight female resident sitting in a chair. The male resident was scaring the female resident, who, because of arthritis, had no means of escaping him. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Physical intimidation of residents; explanation; distraction; one-to-one resident support [SolutionDescription]: When we talk about good care practice we try to improve the interpersonal skills of the care staff. Instead of manually restraining the resident in the form of physical encouragement, staff might be able to verbally encourage the resident to move away, or to engage with something that might be more interesting to them. In these situations carers need to request specialist advice and support from the local safeguarding adults team. Where residents are putting themselves or others at risk through getting up, or walking into other people?s bedrooms, this may signify the need to request further funding for greater one-to-one support for the resident.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1008</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Risk assessment for mobile residents</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A large female resident used a wheelchair to get around the home and who was adamant that she wished to leave the home unescorted. Outside the home was a large hill, and the manager feared that the resident would lose control of the wheelchair and cause a serious accident to herself or others. The resident was aware of the risk that she was taking, but the manager struggled with the idea of simply allowing the resident to leave on her own, even though she recognised that ultimately the resident was able to make an informed choice. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]: member of staff as escort [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Mobile residents; wheelchair; accident risk; informed choice; staff escort; relative expectations [SolutionDescription]: Ultimately the manager felt that she would have to release a member of staff to escort the resident even if that meant leaving the floor short of staff. For her, restraining people if it is in their own interests of safety was something she felt might have been necessary. In this case, a properly negotiated care plan that spelt out the risks and recorded the outcomes of discussions with the resident may be useful both in reducing the perceived need for restraint and indentifying any underlying reasons why the resident wished to take such high risks. Good practice: Relatives tended to be particularly keen on the need to keep doors locked for the residents? own protection. Relatives told us that one of the reasons for coming into the home was the fact that the resident that they visited had been at major risk of ?wandering? when they were in their own home. Creating a positive dialogue with relatives and residents to help understand these fears and worries and how they might infringe on the rights and freedoms of the resident were seen as critical in resolving this issue.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1009</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Non-compliance with home schedule</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident with physical disabilities wishes to remain in bed until 12.30pm at which time she will require support from two staff to get her up (which takes about 40 minutes). Despite staff efforts to negotiate with her, she is adamant that she will not be happy to be got up any later or any earlier than this time. However, this is lunchtime in the home, and staff are all needed to support other residents. If these two staff are taken away from the dining room, other staff will feel pressurised and lunch will be less of a pleasant and relaxed occasion for other residents. How do we resolve this? Why is this resident so fixed in her desire to get up at a set time? Is there support that she needs? In the short term do we stop the resident from getting up or do we stop other residents from getting to the table at lunchtime? [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: lethargic [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Resident non-compliance; taking away resources; impact on residents; resource trade-offs; needs of other residents [SolutionDescription]: One care home manager felt that her staff needed to act as ?detectives?, always assessing both how the environment was affecting the behaviour of residents and how their own practice might be affecting behaviour. In this case practitioners need to understand the reasons behind why a resident is so adamant that she must get up at a fixed time and how the environment of the care home might be exacerbating the need for this resident to want tight control over her routine. If we are flexible to one resident who is able to articulate powerfully her views, are we more likely to ignore those who are quiet, lacking confidence or the ability to express themselves? At the same time we should acknowledge how challenging these negotiations and decisions are for care staff, given limited staff/resident ratios and the sheer workload placed on care home practitioners.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1010</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Risk assessment about falling over</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is assessed to be at high risk of falling and lacking capacity to make decisions. The resident is therefore encouraged to get up only with support from a member of staff. This means that the individual may spend more time sitting than they would wish, which in turn will lead to more muscle wastage and the longerterm consequences of greater unsteadiness and risk in walking. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: unwell;lethargic [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Risk of falling; seated residents; discourage walking; risks trade-off [SolutionDescription]: With this in mind, where the decision has been taken with residents to discourage unaided walking, the longer-term risks and the much greater risk of falling need to be weighed up. It is clear that risk needs to be explored in the wider context of the quality of life of a resident in a care home.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1014</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Large numbers of safeguarding issues</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs. B was being cared for in a home where they were reporting 6-7 safeguarding issues in a month. On assessment it was noted that Mrs. B was angry, racist, non-compliant to care, verbally and physically abusive to residents and staff with no apparent trigger. While reading through all the documents on file it was noted that Mrs. B was a very independent lady. It was stated that she was sharing a shared room with a lady who was snoring constantly at night. Mrs. B had tried to smother her with a pillow to try and stop the noise. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive;violent [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbal physical abuse; physical assault; settling-in period; resident control; setting a routine; life history [SolutionDescription]: She came to us, we allowed 28 days of settling in which is to observe and put together a management plan. The transition from alternative care or from their own home is such a huge change to take on, so the 28 days settling in period is very, very important. It was decided through observation that we would provide Mrs. B with a routine, allow her choice and control over what was happening with her. Mrs. B when she went to bed at night always felt unsafe and so asked to be able to lock her door. We provided her with a key for her room, but the staff also had a spare. This allowed her some control over how she was feeling. Now here we are 14 months on and Mrs. B does participate in activities really well. It?s been noted that she enjoys helping the other residents with whatever task they are doing. She interacts well with meaningful activities, she likes to fold a little bit of washing. She enjoys doing the dishes and at times she does supervise the kitchen staff with the meals. We have noted a huge reduction in anti-psychotic medications. And in the 14 months that she has been with us we have reduced the safe guarding issues to 3. In the last 6 months, we haven?t had any good practice: an interim care plan is always put in place when a resident comes into a home. Interim care plan being that you take the initial assessment, from talking with family members, from staff that has previously cared for them. It?s important to allow 28 days for settling in, because it gives the resident a chance to orientate to their surroundings, get to know the staff,  and the staff to get to know them. It is then, and only then that you can put in place a person centred care plan. I have to say that the staff being trained in a person centred way allows them to see the bigger picture. The individual and not the condition. The staff are working with the residents and the family members on putting together life stories. We?ve found this measure so helpful in understanding the person. The residents enjoy their life stories and quite often will sit quietly looking through their life story and their photos. The life story doesn?t end when they come to the home, we do another part towards the end of the life story about my life now, incl. Any new activities I?ve taken up any new interests that they are looking forward to.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>5001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Travel disruption in Tokyo due to an earthquake</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Travel[ProblemDescription]: Mr Takahashi had returned to Tokyo from South Korea. However a minor earthquake in Tokyo has disrupted the transport system, and is unable to use the normal train system to return to his home in the city from Narita airport. The airport trains to Tokyo are not running. The limited metro system is overloaded, and people are forming long, orderly queues even to get into the stations. There are very few taxis available. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Transport problems; unable to access transport; group travel; shared solutions [SolutionDescription]: Mr Takahashi used his organizational skills to locate a group of other travelers who need to reach the same part of the city. He used the combined buying power of this traveler group to locate and arrange travel. Mr Takahashi led the group to group-book a large taxi to a car hire company in a town near to Narita. From there he arranged for the group to rent a mini-bus sufficiently large to drive all of the travelers to their destination. An off-duty bus driver, found at the airport by Mr Takahashi, drove the mini-bus until the last traveler had been dropped off.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1011</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing family requests</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: The decision to allow someone to walk around unsupported may have longer-term consequences if they suffer a fall. One relative talked about how she didn?t want her mother to get up and walk around unaided, not because she could fall, but because the fall might lead to the resident requiring a spell in hospital. This relative knew that her mother feared hospitals. A hospital stay would be highly distressing and disorientating and could ultimately lead to her further mental deterioration. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: n/A [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Family request; relative knowledge of resident; risk trade-off [SolutionDescription]: It is clear that risk needs to be explored in the wider context of the quality of life of a resident in a care home.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1013</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Poor resident health</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr. S had been living at home with his only son. 2010 he came to the home with a diagnosis of lung cancer. The symptoms included a huge decrease in weight due to not eating and drinking. He has been with us for 12 months and has put on over 1 stone in weight. He eats and drinks well at the dining room table with the other gentlemen. He?s still a smoker and smokes regularly. He is supported by this by the carers when he requests a cigarette he is given one and the staff will light it for him, and he sits quite happily outside in the smoking area in the home and enjoys all the visitors coming and going. He sits at the front door in his wheel chair. He says that this allows him to greet people as they come into the home. He is on oxygen supply that helps us to monitor his health, as it gives him some control over his care. His son visits regularly and sits outside with him to have morning tea or a cigarette. He interacts very well with the other residents. The lady residents love him. In the afternoon he likes to go to bed to rest and to watch his football with peace and quiet. And then he?ll get up again in the afternoon and attend the evening meal. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: unwell [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Resident health; smoking outside; adapted daily routine [SolutionDescription]: n/A</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1015</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Resident personal interests</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: We have a gentleman who is only just 65 who have come to the home with vascular dementia, he walks with crutches, he?s had a very messy personal background, quite in-depth. He is on anti-depression medication at the moment. On speaking with him and his family, he enjoyed breeding birds and fishing and enjoyed gardening and considered himself to be a bit of a designer or an architect. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: unwell [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Complex personal background; settling-in period; support personal interests; life history added to [SolutionDescription]: After speaking with him we have provided him with a sketchpad and the utensils he needs to help devise a garden. The building team for the organisation are going to build an aviary with which Mr. X will assist. And he?s going to design the summer garden. It just so happens that this aviary is outside his room in the courtyard. He?s so excited about the plans for this. And he?s drawn up many plans and has many ideas about the garden. He?s turned to his daughter, who works with plants, and she is assisting in deciding which plants we should put into the garden once the aviary is completed. Mr. X is now coming to me saying that perhaps he could start a little business where he could on-sell his birds and raise a little money for resident activities. An interim care plan is always put in place when a resident comes into a home. Interim care plan being that you take the initial assessment, from talking with family members, from staff that has previously cared for them. It?s important to allow 28 days for settling in, because it gives the resident a chance to orientate to their surroundings, get to know the staff,  and the staff to get to know them. It is then, and only then that you can put in place a person centred care plan. I have to say that the staff being trained in a person centred way allows them to see the bigger picture. The individual and not the condition. The staff are working with the residents and the family members on putting together life stories. We?ve found this measure so helpful in understanding the person. The residents enjoy their life stories and quite often will sit quietly looking through their life story and their photos. The life story doesn?t end when they come to the home, we do another part towards the end of the life story about my life now, incl. Any new activities I?ve taken up any new interests that they are looking forward to.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing an Applicant`s Difficult Parent</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A parent of an applicant to a university undergraduate degree course was convinced that the applicant`s current school was withholding their child`s results. The parent believed that the results were being withheld for personal reasons. Therefore the parent rang the university continuously to complain. She told staff at the university that school`s failure to disclose results was the fault of the university. The applicant was embarrassed by their parent`s involvement in the process. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Withholding information; privacy; mediation; trust; student-relative conversations [SolutionDescription]: The university staff member decided to play a long game to resolve the situation. She adopted a strategy to befriend all of the participants involved in it. During communications with the parent she pretended to be on the parent`s side in order to gain the parent`s trust and to manage the interactions with her. At the same time the staff member tried to communicate with the school, highlighting the problems that the parent was causing for the university. As a consequence of mediating different conversations, the situation was resolved to the satisfaction of all participants.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Handling a Parent`s Complaint</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A parent of a school pupil complained to the Department of Education. The substance of the complaint was that the requirement to learn the Welsh language was violating the pupil`s human rights. The parent behaviour was aggressive towards the Department`s staff, which in turn alienated the staff towards her complaint. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Aggression towards staff; alienation; communication; permission; explaining procedures [SolutionDescription]: Staff at the Department recommended that she communicate directly with the staff at the pupil`s school to resolve the situation. She was also recommended to communicate directly with her member of parliament. The staff explained to the parent both the current legislative situation and the processes to follow to communicate to school staff and the member of parliament. The staff also made the effort to explain to the parent the advantages to the child of learning another language. In order to resolve the situation the parent was allowed to complain, a process supported by the Department staff.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Supporting a Depressed Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An undergraduate student becomes depressed during the second year and attempted suicide. The university staff were initially uncertain how to handle this situation. The course director was not able to deal with the situation emotionally or strategically. There were concerns about how the student in question would interact with other students on the course. The course director also refused to speak to the parent due to the need to protect the privacy of the student. The student herself was not prepared to initiate the involvement of the parent. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Emotions; depression; managed conversation; individual support; counselling [SolutionDescription]: The situation was resolved by inviting the student to attend the university with one of her parents. The university managed to facilitate a conversation between the student and the parent. This conversation revealed that the underlying problem was an absence of love towards the student during time at university. As a result of the facilitated conversation, the problem was resolved quickly. Support for the student was put in place. The university decided to support regular meetings with the course director to monitor the student, and access to counselling services. Staff tried to give a staff friend to the student to be able to talk to. In addition, staff tried to make important information accessible to the student at all times.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4004</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Supporting a Homeless Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: Security staff reported that an undergraduate student had attacked one of their staff. The student had been living in the 24-hour computing labs. A security staff member on a night-time patrol had encountered the student and challenged him. The university staff were very surprised that the named student would have attacked someone. Whilst attempting to flee, the student had accidently stood on the toes of the security staff, which had triggered the report. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Homelessness; family feuds; mediation; understanding; student support [SolutionDescription]: University staff first located the student on campus. Staff tried to invite the student for an informal meeting with his personal tutor. Care was taken to not inflame the situation. The meeting revealed that the student was homeless. He had left home because he was doing badly in his studies. He left home without reporting his exam results to his strict parents. The problem was resolved by inviting the parents into the university to have a mediated conversation with the personal tutor. The personal tutor asked the parents to not put pressure on the student. He explained that the university would try to put in place mechanisms to help the student. The outcome was improved results that a return to home for the student.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4005</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Mediating between Academic Staff and Students</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student on a field trip to a foreign city missed the return flight home, and was forced to travel back on their own. The student had missed the flight back because was engaged in nocturnal activities in a local brothel, and did not notice the time. The academic in charge of the trip held strong conservative views, and objected to the student`s behaviour. The outcome was a major conflict between the academic and the student that led to physical threats only resolved by keeping the two people in different rooms. As a consequence the university considered abandoning future field trips. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Personal conflicts; power relationships; chaperone; monitored meetings; mediation [SolutionDescription]: The university managed to resolve the situation by providing a chaperone for all meetings between the student and staff member over the subsequent months. The chaperone ensured that the academic and the student were not allowed in the same room together alone. The chaperone also acted as a mediator for communication between the student and staff member.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4006</SourceId>
    <SourceName>The Student Giving Back the Masters Degree</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A postgraduate student who had been awarded their postgraduate degree contacted the university and asked to return their degree. The university replied that this was not possible. Next the student informed the university that he had cheated by committing academic misconduct in his dissertation work. The university double-checked the dissertation for plagiarism, and was unable to detect any misconduct. The student then reported that he had someone else undertake the dissertation work on his behalf.The student explained that he achieving the Masters had given him a superiority complex that was then inhibiting him from obtaining a job. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Guilt; lack of confidence; explanation; self-confidence [SolutionDescription]: The university staff managed to resolve the situation through a lengthy conversation with the student. The staff member tried to respond to each accusation by the student in turn. Eventually the staff member told the student that there was no evidence of this, and that the matter was closed. The student responded that the conversation had allowed the student to offload any guilt that he had about the post-graduate reward. The student was now happy and received the degree. This demonstrates that attempting to talk to the student is sufficient to resolve the situation before it becomes more serious.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4007</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Pairing Students to Manage their Personalities</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was regularly angry in her interactions with the university. She would treat each interaction in simple, black-and-white terms, which would leave her dissatisfied much of the time. The student was diagnosed with borderline personality disorder. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Personality problems; people buddies; individual characteristics [SolutionDescription]: The university staff managed to resolve this situation by providing another student as a buddy for the student. The other student was very shy. The result of the friendship was a change in the behaviour of both students. The student with borderline personality disorder became more calm, and the student who was shy became more confident and outward going. One reason for the success of this friendship was that the shy student was very effective at saying `no` to requests without saying `no` directly, and the other student accepted this way of working. At the end of the course both students were able to graduate from their degree courses.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4008</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing Future Student Expectations</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An applicant to the university had failed to achieved the required A-level grades to enter university, and was very disappointed. The staff managing the entrance process was managing the situation. The applicant, his father and his mother had all rang the university to seek a change of decision. The mother had shouted at the staff, blaming the university for wider social problems associated with youth unemployment. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Angry relatives; understanding; communication; explanation; exploring options [SolutionDescription]: The staff member managed to resolve the situation through continued dialogue with parents. First of all, she tried to allow the parents to vent their frustration so that she would not be interrupted later on. She then explained that the applicant still had many future career options open to him. The options included re-sitting the A-levels, and applying to other universities.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4009</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Helping the Self-Harming Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was self-harming in front of the staff because the university was unable to provide assessment marks to her on demand. She was kicking furniture and banging her head against the office wall. The student said that she needed to have the assessment outcomes to obtain a visa for travel purposes. At first the university staff were uncertain how to manage this situation. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Personal stress; physical violence; exceptional circumstances; additional support; demonstrating care [SolutionDescription]: The staff member managed to contain the immediate situation by first leading the student into a private office out of sight and sound of other students. The university staff then tried to seek a means of meeting the student`s request due to the exceptional circumstances. The university staff did this by locating a member of academic staff with the necessary authority to compute and release the assessment marks. The student was provided with what she needed so desperately within one hour of the situation developing. This shortcut served to calm the student considerably.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4010</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Support for a Sexually-Abused Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student new to the university had attended a social event to the university on a Friday night. On Monday morning the student came to the Department to allege that a sexual assault had taken place on her. She was desperately seeking advice from the university. She had not informed the police beforehand, although some of her friends were concerned that she should. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Sexual assault; police involvement; making a complaint; building trust; prosecution [SolutionDescription]: A member of the Department`s staff managed to provide the student with a private space to discuss what had happened. He recorded the complaint on her behalf. He managed to use the complaint to speak to the Student`s Union and to counselling. The Student`s Union tried to locate the incident and the accused student using its CCTV system. As a result of this information, the student was expelled from the university. Furthermore the information was provided to the police who undertook a prosecution. All of these outcomes were possible because the Department staff led the student through the difficult and challenging process in a trusting way.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1016</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Uncooperative</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Annie Able, a new resident has been refusing to be washed, dressed or assisted any way.  She is verbally abusive to staff when approached.   Carers feel reluctant to approach her for fear of being abused.  Staff members become upset and feel like they want to reply to her comments, and leave her without assisting her. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbal abuse; avoiding; change of environment; reassurance [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Able has been at the home less than a month. She is also suffering from dementia.  It is difficult for her to adjust to a new environment and new people.  Annie has been independent, and has lived alone, since her husband died nearly 30 years ago. Her only child, Angela, lives abroad with her family and rarely visits. She is not used to people being in her home.  She feels anxious and expresses herself in this way.  Also she is in an unfamiliar environment and at times cannot understand why.  She can`t help it, and carers need to give her reassurance and understanding. When residents abuse you, do not take it personally. The incident has been documented, and has been discussed with all staff at handover.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1017</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Lashes out</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs. Bea Bridge, a resident who has been with us for some time, resisted when going to lunch with Nina.  Nina, a new carer, tried to help her up, but when she did, Bea slapped her across the face, and said `No, No.`.  Another carer called for a nurse who promptly arrived.  Other similar incidents have been documented in Mrs Bridge`s notes. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Physical abuse; resistance; greater explanation; patience; doubling-up care [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Bridge suffers from dementia and at times she is can be very confused. They tried to take her back to her room and ask her what was wrong.  It seems that the carer forgot to explain in more detail what she was doing so that Mrs Bridge understands that the carer had come to escort her to lunch, and not feel frightened and unsure of what is happening around her.  Carers acted well when they tried to find someone senior to assist them. They left her for some time and approached her again later on when she was less agitated.  A good suggestion for now might be to have two carers always present when caring for Mrs Jones as she appears to be volatile at times.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1018</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Racism</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Crawford has been resident at the home for just over one year. He is verbally abusive to staff on a regular basis, particularly to black members of staff.  He makes comments at all times of the day and comments are not restricted to certain aspects of his care.  Mr Crawford does apologise to staff after each incident if confronted. He has not been diagnosed with dementia and has been deemed to have mental capacity.  On direct questioning Mr Crawford is unable to explain his behaviour.  Many staff particularly those with darker skin do not want to go into his room as his comments are very offensive. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Racist verbal abuse; mental capacity; avoidance; cognitive impairment; ignore verbal comments [SolutionDescription]: Where possible, ask carers to care for him who are less likely to be subject to such comments However, this is not always possible.  When Mr Crawford makes offensive comments staff leave the room, senior nurses are consulted and then after some time someone will return to his room to speak to him.  Nursing staff are concerned he may have some degree of cognitive impairment which may be responsible for the behaviour. Care staff make sure to always document the patient`s behaviour in his care plan. His family and the doctor have been consulted regarding this matter.  His wife has done her best to talk to her husband.   She tries to understand why he makes such comments to the staff.  Staff are doing their best not to respond to the comments made to him, not to `take it personally`, but if they feel upset, to leave the room.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1019</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Grabbing</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Dean is a lady who is fully mobile.  She is a pleasant lady and has been at the nursing home for some time.  She walks around the ground floor of the home all day and makes a low pitched moaning noise, when a person walks past her she physically grabs their arm and won`t let go.  This is difficult for staff as they are often busy with daily duties and cannot stop so frequently. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Grabbing continuously; fear; anxiety; anti-psychotic drugs; companions; friendship [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Dean is a lady who has been at the home for a few years now.  She suffers from dementia and paranoia.  Her dementia has gradually become worse.  The doctor and family have been consulted regarding her behaviour.   Her constant need for attention is because of  her paranoia. Mrs Dean is afraid that she will die, and that she will be alone.  She is afraid and feels alone.  The doctor is reluctant to prescribe anti-psychotic drugs for her as she is already in a fragile state of health. Staff members do their best to take Mrs Dean to an area of the home where there are other residents / people.  She often sits near the reception desk where she can be near administrative staff and carers.  It is however at times difficult to give her the attention she needs.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1020</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Screaming</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Eccles was admitted to the nursing home 4 months ago.  She is unable to mobilize and requires full nursing care.  She screams all day from when she wakes until she sleeps.  Other residents in neighbouring rooms find the noise disturbing and have made complaints about the situation.  It also makes work more challenging for carers as they try whatever they can to calm Mrs Eccles. She is made as comfortable as possible, has started to eat her meals where she did not when she first arrived here and is toileted regularly.  She also receives regular medication including pain killers. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Screaming; noise disturbance; new environment; anxiety; communication; explanation [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Eccles is a lady who has moved to a strange environment with new people. She will feel distressed, afraid and anxious.  Staff try to note the days where she seems to be especially distressed or days where she is quiet.  In thinking about the reasons behind her behaviour the importance of communication is emphasised.  Carers sit and explain things calmly to Mrs Eccles and try to get to know her a little better so she feels more at home here.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1021</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Swears and Kicks</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Forrest is a new resident, and often has fits of swearing and shouting in her room, and when staff approach she can kick and pull the hair of the staff members. Staff are afraid to approach her as she is unpredictable. She has not made any relationships with other residents or carers, and is disruptive with others. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Shouting; physical abuse; alone; calming massage; toy doll; mirroring technique [SolutionDescription]: Ask her what is troubling her. Reassure her.  She may respond to gentle massage to calm her down. What has also worked for a while is to divert her attention. Mrs Forest particularly liked to hold a small doll, `Billy`, and may respond to choosing clothes for dressing up. If distraction doesn`t work, then a `mirroring` technique may work, where the carer `mirrors` the behaviour, even more pronounced, until they are in control, then brings down the behaviour and the volume, guiding the resident to become calmer,  and gradually stop. This technique would not work in later stage dementia.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1022</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Likes the Uniforms</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Graham often shouts at staff when they go into his room, telling them to get out. As he`s quite deaf, he doesn`t respond to explanations, and won`t stop shouting until they leave. Staff are upset and intimidated, and don`t want to see him as their knocks are often not heard. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Shouting; deaf resident; intimidation; changed uniforms; military background; staff names [SolutionDescription]: Mr Graham, a resident of nearly a year has been confused by the recent change of uniform policy.  Mr Graham was in the Army for some years and is comfortable with uniforms and it helps him to understand your authority when you go into his room.  It is possible to use a number of old uniforms that have been retained in the staff room for the care of Mr Graham. Mr Graham is not the only one to be confused. Although he won`t remember , try to get him to look for the staff badge and to use names.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1023</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Dislikes the Uniforms</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Halford, a resident of some 2 months will become very agitated at certain times, and try to hide.  The sight of an ambulance crews seemed to set this off for the first time, but it`s happened occasionally at other times.  Following a stroke, mobility and speech has become very difficult for Mr Halford, and he`s finding it difficult to express himself.  Medical assessments and treatments are particularly difficult and he seems to have taken a dislike to Dr Peters` nurse, who is often resisted when trying to treat him. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Fear of uniforms; medical uniforms; speech impediment; prisoner; remove uniforms [SolutionDescription]: Mr Halford will be expressing frustration at his inability to express himself, and staff should take time and show patience with him. However, it seems that Mr Halford spent some time in a foreign prison in his younger days and reacts badly to uniforms of any kind. It is recommended to remove or cover the uniform before approaching Mr Graham.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1024</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Bedtime tantrums</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Ivy, a recent dementia sufferer and recent resident has been disturbing other residents in the early evening in the lounge by shouting that she wants to go to bed first. Otherwise cooperative, Mrs Ivy insists on being the first to go to bed. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Early bedtime; tantrums; habits of a lifetime; plan for individual habits [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Ivy has always lived by a strict policy of going to bed early and waking up early, and insists that she has many important things for tomorrow.  She does not respond to reason or the needs of others, but when a carer makes sure to take her to bed first, then she stops shouting.  In this case it is easy to readjust bedtime planning in order to take into account the special needs of residents, providing it can be done without other disruptions.  It is important to Mrs Ivy to get to bed early and if possible, this wish should be granted whenever possible, and be noted in her care plans.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1025</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Refuses Medication</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Since the introduction of the `no-uniforms` policy, Mr Jones, will often be uncooperative with staff, and in particular, to refuse to take his medication on the rounds, challenging the carer. `Who are you to tell me to take these tablets?` However, he does need to take this medication, and the arguments are distressing to others around, often setting off others who overhear, and sometimes he is left without the medication been given. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: No-uniforms policy; uncooperative; recognisable authority; engage a medic [SolutionDescription]: In this case, another carer needs to put on a doctor`s uniform on, and dispensed the medication. Faced with this recognisable `authority` the resident has been taking his prescribed tablets without objection. This strategy of subterfuge can work in other varieties.  In case the doctor`s coat is not available, what will also work is for the carer to appear to be on the phone to the doctor/consultant on the phone, overheard by and involving Mr Jones in the conversation about the importance of taking his medicine.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1026</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Occupational throwbacks ? the Miner</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Kerris, a recent resident will often exhibit strange behaviour, and if interrupted can become very agitated. His behaviour begins when he crouches down to the floor and crawls along the floor, under his table.  This is deliberate, and should not be seen as falling down. He does not want help to get up.  After some time he stands up and takes all his clothes off, discarding them to one side. Despite encouragement, he will not be persuaded to  put them back on again, though he will wear another set of clothes. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Throwback to former life; unusual behaviours; split-reality dementia; repetitive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: In discussions with Mr Kerris`s  daughter on a visit, she mentioned that he was working as a miner all his life, and that it was likely that the crouching was him re-enacting being in a narrow seam. His other behaviour could similarly be explained - at the end of the shift he would stand, and take off all his clothes before his shower. He wouldn`t put back on his `dirty` clothes. This resident was in the `split reality` stage of dementia, and should be left to enact his routine undisturbed.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1027</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Wanting to go `home`</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Lloyd, a new resident keeps saying `I want to go home`, `I want to go home`.  It`s distressing and confusing for other residents, and gets him agitated.  The staff know he can`t go home. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Going home; feeling safe and secure; symbols of home [SolutionDescription]: It`s important to understand what Mr Lloyd is really saying? Though going home is no longer an option, we can understand what the word `home` means ? and that he is missing the safety and security of home. Carers can help to calm him down by being gentle and reassuring, in particular that he was safe and secure here. Often, if the literal request is not possible, then the symbolic needs can be addressed. It`s also worth noting that Mr Lloyd likes painting when he was younger and likes to look at paintings. He is very knowledgeable. It sometimes helps to distract him by looking at pictures of paintings with him and asking questions about them.  He has a book of them.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1028</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Resident v Resident conflict</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: The trouble started when one resident, Mrs Mirron called out that she was waiting for her mum to visit. Mrs Norris replied that that she wasn`t as her mother was dead, arguing that if Mrs Mirron was nearly 90, her mother would certainly be dead.  Mrs Mirron got very upset and started arguing, requiring care staff to separate them. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Inter-resident conflicts; residents in mixed groups; similar stages of dementia [SolutionDescription]: The trouble lay in having residents in mixed groups.  In this case, a resident with an advanced stage of dementia is living in her reality, but is flatly contradicted by a resident with most of her critical faculties working. To reduce these sorts of conflicts, it can help to keep groups of similar stage dementia sufferers together. Also ask what the resident is really saying ? `I miss being hugged, cuddled, or the touch of another loving person.` In this situation a hug may be very helpful.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1029</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Occupational throwbacks ? the Prison Officer</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Order has been indulging in very strange behaviour. Although normally very orderly and tidy in his habits, he has started to make a complete tip of his room, emptying drawers over the floor, pulling the mattress off his bed, emptying the wardrobe. He will not be stopped or touched while doing this, and has even been violent when staff have tried to stop him. He won`t pick up the contents afterwards. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Throwback to former life; unusual behaviours; split-reality dementia; repetitive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: Discussing Mr Order`s life history with his wife, it transpires he used to be a prison guard for most of his working life. Room searches, looking for contraband, were the order of the day and the inmates` rooms were certainly never tidied up afterwards. It was important to try not to stop the resident`s  behaviour of searching rooms as the resident then became very aggressive and would punch hard. He would calm down when carers allowed him to leave the resident to complete his `search` he would calm down and be fine.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1030</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Collecting his Pension</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Potter, a resident of some 5 months has kept demanding to go to the Post Office to collect his pension. He asks what day it is most days, a number of times, and when he discovers it is Tuesday, he insists on going to the Post Office to collect his pension. When he can`t go, he becomes very agitated and worried. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Compulsive behaviour; unable to act; enabling a compulsive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: This issue distressed Mr Potter so much, it was agreed to create a `Post Office` in the Home, by decorating the outside of an administrative office and a counter inside to that Mr Potter could visit it on a Tuesday, and collect his `pension`.  He was content to go to this `Post Office`, where he would be given some money and return to his room happy. Carers can help to fulfil the fantasy wishes with little effort, but some imagination.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1031</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Collecting the Wanderers</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Queen is a recent resident. She is still fully mobile, and most of the time understands her situation, but is increasingly forgetful. She loves to be outside and is allowed to walk in the garden, but on occasion, walks around the grounds and finds an open entrance.  As she is new to the home, she doesn`t know the area, and will be confused. This does happen from time to time with other residents too. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Wandering residents; lost; creative false amenities; collect lost residents [SolutionDescription]: It is very difficult to stop the situation, while still allowing those who can and want to walk the grounds unaccompanied. It the situation of confused and wandering residents, their behaviour has shown some consistencies, and it was found that by siting a false `bus stop` and sign just outside the home, almost all residents who are prone to wander are found waiting patiently outside, at the bus stop.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1032</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Occupational Throwbacks ? the Teacher</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Reddy, a resident of nearly a year now regularly regresses to her past when she was a teacher. She barks ?sit down and shut up? to all and sundry.  Some residents don`t like this and start challenging her. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Throwback to former life; unusual behaviours; split-reality dementia; repetitive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: The carer can shut up and sit down, not challenging Mrs Reddy`s `authority`, and allowing her to play out her reality. However, if other residents resent being told what to do and do not follow the carer`s example, this could make matters worse.  Prevention is often better than cure in this situation, and it can help to keep apart residents suffering different stages of dementia.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1033</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Continuing Routines</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Smith wanted ?to walk to the sweetshop? every morning. Although he didn`t want to buy any sweets, it had been part of his morning routine to have a walk. It distressed him that he wasn`t allowed to do this when he came to live in the residential home.  This request of his did not go away, and he continued to ask to for a walk each morning after breakfast. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Continuing old habits; creating false amenities; enable old habits [SolutionDescription]: After some weeks, when it became clear that this was a continuing cause for distress for Mr Smith, the outside of an administrative office was decorated to look like sweetshop from the outside.  Mr Smith was now quite happy to go for a walk after breakfast to the sweetshop, and return much happier.  It helps to satisfy residents` wishes symbolically, although seemingly impossible.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1034</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Painful solutions</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Tait, an uncooperative and uncommunicative resident, is often agitated and pinches staff, but does not respond when asked why.  All sorts of reasons have been tried - is she thirsty, hungry, has she got toothache, do her dentures fit, does she want the toilet, is she in pain, etc? She does not answer but continues to pinch the carer, and groan. For some time staff did not know why. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Pinching staff; undiagnosed reasons; allow pinching thinker clothes [SolutionDescription]: It was noticed that Mrs Tait, when asked if in pain, pinches much harder and groans more deeply.  Staff pursued this thread, and put on thick long sleeved clothes, and let her pinch as much as she liked. The thickness of the material allowed the carer to accept the pinching, and the resident eventually tires and also becomes much less agitated. Adapting to apparently unreasonable demand and needs can sometimes be done with minimum efforts, but may need to imagine alternative solutions.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>1035</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Not taking it personally</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Unwin, a new resident, has not settled in and remains uncooperative. He is particularly abusive to the carers ? calling them fat, ugly, picking on race, or whatever. Staff hate to work with him, and a number have refused. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbally abusing staff; ignore abuse; team approachs [SolutionDescription]: Most care staff do not take the abuse personally and just get on with the job instead. They rationalise that Mr Unwin does not really know what his is saying. His wife says that he was a gentle man and would be horrified if he could see himself. But he can`t.  The importance of carers holding up the mirror to themselves is vital. To understand that the resident `can`t help it`, and be strong enough to not take it personally, is something not all carers can accept. Often this acceptance can come from being a carer in a good team, where each member values each other, where it is likely engender the kind of self-confidence so that cruel remarks just bounce off.</Content>
  </MatchedSource>
</MatchedSources>
