<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<MatchedSources xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>2001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Hygiene</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Policing[ProblemDescription]: 17 year old female brought in restrained by two officers. Reported for her safety by a member of the public who thought she was a young child. She kicked custody desk and officers constantly while screaming, shouting and using obscene language. A female officer was called to search her. She urinated on the floor. She is constantly verbally abusive. The female officer asked where she stands on health and safety as the female arrestee was saturated with urine. Four officers were needed to restrain her during the search ? this took nearly ten minutes and she was immediately celled as she was too drunk to process in the normal way ? she continued to kick and scream and had to be restrained to get her into a cell. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: drunken detainees; arrestees; clothing; infectious diseases [Miscellaneous]: Drunken behaviour; urinating; restraint; change of garments [Solution Description]: Hygiene, particularly when dealing with drunken detainees can be a significant problem. Several arrestees defecated or urinated in their clothing during or after arrest. These arrestees were then supplied with a white paper garment to change into, with their clothes being placed in a plastic bag. At best this can be unpleasant for the officers involved when the arrestee is compliant and agrees to change their clothing. At worst it can be a health and safety issue if an arrestee refuses to change clothing. Some officers did express worry about the potential to contract infectious diseases, particularly hepatitis C.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>2002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Drunken Offender</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Policing[ProblemDescription]: Two women (one in her 40s and one in her early 20s) arrested for being drunk and disorderly. The older of the two women had already been processed and was in the side room. She appeared to have been very aggressive and two police women were needed to search her. As she was at risk, she was ?white suited? i.e., her own clothes were removed and she was dressed in a disposable white overall. Through the whole process she shouted and argued and protested her innocence. Two female officers were needed to take her to the cells. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: arrests; street; physical risk; potential for violence [Miscellaneous]: Drunk; aggressive behaviour; change of behaviour; decision-making; judgement [Solution Description]: While the study did not observe officers making arrests, the interviews did explore the process by which they make decisions to arrest an individual who is drunk. The overwhelming thread that ran through interviews was of officers rationalising the need to arrest. Officers on the street can exercise discretion in any decision to arrest. In the case of someone considered to be drunk it would seem that rarely is an arrest automatic but that officers routinely try to calm a situation down before deciding to arrest or not. Generally, officers appear to have a lenient attitude towards inebriates, although the attitude of the individual was paramount in most encounters.  The offender?s physical condition is also a factor considered. If they are so drunk that they run a risk of injuring themselves or making themselves vulnerable to becoming a victim of crime then an arrest is made for their own protection. The potential for violence or other crime is paramount in any decision. If an officer feels that an individual will commit a further offence or that members of the public are at risk then an arrest is the likely outcome</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>2003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Processing Time and care in Custody</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Policing[ProblemDescription]: The police have a duty of care to every person arrested and taken into custody, both in terms of their legal rights and their physical well-being. When individuals are under the influence of alcohol this can put even more demands on a busy custody suite. The main worry for custody staff is the physical well-being of the prisoner because the officer on duty may be held liable if they come to any harm. Officers described drunken arrestees as time-consuming. They were seen as taking longer to process and also to care for once in custody. The custody process often could be incomplete simply because the intoxicated individual was unable or unwilling to give the necessary information. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: arrestee; sleep; check; doctor; hospital; detoxification unit [Miscellaneous]: Responsibility; prisoners; self-harming; time to sober up; involving doctors [Solution Description]: In both sites drunken arrestees were held for a minimum of four hours to sober up. Often these arrestees took up extra time because of the need to be aware of the potential for them to injure themselves by falling or suffocating on their own vomit. Consequently, arrestees were checked regularly and often roused from their sleep to ensure they were conscious. These checks may be as frequent as every 15 minutes and each check must be recorded on the custody record, so putting some degree of pressure on custody officers. A doctor was called if the arrestee was judged as needing to see one because of his/her intoxication or was injured or unwell. However, calling a doctor sometimes required the presence of another officer if the arrestee was violent or aggressive. Some officers believed that a hospital or a detoxification unit was the best place for arrestees who were particularly drunk.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>3001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>The Apathetic Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Teaching[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Bird is very concerned about Dale, a student in her second-grade class. Dale doesn't seem to care about anything. If Mrs Bird praises Dale for completing his work on time, Dale just looks at her. If Mrs Bird punishes Dale for failing to complete his work, Dale just looks at her. Dale doesn't seem to care whether other students pay attention to him. Ms Bird would like to help Dale, but she's uncertain about what she can do. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: strategy; activity; classroom; bulletin board; apathy; discussion [Miscellaneous]: Apathy; uncertainty; improve self-worth; demonstrate value; ignore apathetic behaviour; know the student [Solution Description]: Step 1: Develop strategies that encourage the student to feel good about himself or herself. With an extremely discouraged student, it is essential to provide activities and interactions that demonstrate his or her value in the classroom. One of the best ways to encourage a child is to provide activities and jobs that demonstrate that he or she can be a valuable asset to the classroom. Some activities might include being responsible for delivering the attendance slip to the office, getting to design a bulletin board, or getting to tutor another student. When you present the student with a responsibility or special privilege, present your request as a statement rather than as a question. If the request is put in the form of a question, the student can say he or she is not interested. Step 2: Ignore all apathetic behaviors. Whenever the student expresses disinterest or apathy in something, ignore him or her. Don't try to talk the student into developing an interest in things. Any attempt to convince the student that an activity is worthwhile will only serve to reinforce the student's 'I don't care' behaviour. Step 3:
Spend five minutes every day talking with the student about his or her interests. Tell the student that you appreciate hearing about his or her interests. The focus of the discussions should be on getting the student to practice making positive statements.
</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>3002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Using Bad Language</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Teaching[ProblemDescription]: Oliver is a third-grade student who swears as many as fifteen to twenty times day. If someone bumps into him while the class is lining up, he'll turn and swear at that person. If Oliver drops something, he's likely to shout any number of profanities. For the smallest of reasons and sometimes for no reason at all, Oliver uses profane language. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: reinforcer; feedback; student; motivator; language; classroom; chart; swearwords [Miscellaneous]: Swearing; reinforce good behaviour; praise; solution sheet; student understanding [Solution Description]: Step 1: Decide on a reinforcer for the student who makes it through an entire day without swearing. When the student is successful for an entire day, provide him or her with feedback. For younger students, also provide a privilege like getting to be line leader or getting to erase the board. With older students your praise should be coupled with free time or another powerful motivator. Step 2: A solution sheet does not attempt to define acceptable and unacceptable language; rather it offers the teacher some guidelines carrying out this exercise. Each teacher will have to decide what kind of language is acceptable in his or her classroom. Discuss the problem and the plan with the student. Explain the borderline between acceptable and unacceptable language. Be very specific. Show the student the chart. Make sure the student understands that even swearwords that may not have been put on the list are considered unacceptable. Tell the student about the consequence for using unacceptable words or phrases and the reinforcer for making it through a day without using unacceptable expressions</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>3003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>The Bully</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Teaching[ProblemDescription]: Ned is a sixth-grader who constantly bullies other children and ends up in fights. It's a rare day when Ned doesn't get into one scrape or another. In class, Ned is an average student and is generally cooperative unless he gets into a fight with another student. The other students are beginning to avoid Ned. They don't like talking to him for fear that it will lead to a fight. Some children are actually terrified of Ned. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: positive interaction; insecurity; sense of security; self-concept; tutor; situation [Miscellaneous]: Fighting and bullying; fear; insecurity; reinforce good behaviour; role models; monitoring; trust [Solution Description]: Step 1 - Increase the number of positive interactions between you and the student. Because the primary cause of this problem is related to the student's feelings of insecurity, focus on building the individual's self-concept and sense of security. This may seem like a circuitous way to attack the problem, but it is essential. Attempts to implement the subsequent steps of the plan will be ineffective if you are not first successful in elevating the student's self-concept. Step 2 - Design a reinforcer for the student when he or she can go an entire day without fighting. Since the student's problem emanates from a poor self-image, establish a reinforcer that will five him or her a certain level of responsibility. Getting to tutor a younger student is a powerful reinforcer for this type of student. Check with one of your colleagues who teaches a lower grade than you do. See if the teacher would allow your student to help one of his or her students. The 'helping' can be as simple as listening to the younger student read, or as involved as helping the younger student work arithmetic problems. Make sure that your student's skills are adequate for the type of tasks he or she will be asked to perform. The tutorial session should take place at the end of the day, but only if the student has not been in a fight. If the student has been in a fight, he or she should not be allowed to tutor that day. Each day is a fresh start. If the student does not make it without fighting on Monday, Tuesday morning start with a clean slate. The student must see that one failure only affects the day of the fight and no more. Step 3 - Determine how to monitor situations when you will not be there, such as in the cafeteria, halls, restroom, and so on. What will you do if a student tells you that the bully was in a fight? Ignore it. The best procedure to follow is to base your actions on the student's own evaluation of whether or not he or she was in a fight. After each recess period, lunch period, and so on, ask the student how he or she did. If you have been working diligently on improving the student's self-image, it's unlikely that this procedure will backfire. If the student is honest and tells you that he or she was in a fight, don't allow the student to tutor that day, but praise the student for his or her honesty and maturity. Encourage the student to do better the next day. If you think that the student might have been in a fight, but denies it, do not call him or her a liar. Take the student's word for it; allow him or her to tutor that day. You don't want to confront the student with a charge that you cannot prove. If the student lies to you, he or she is telling you that you haven't done enough to elevate the student's self-image.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>3004</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Arranging private tutorials</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Teaching[ProblemDescription]: A group of college students was struggling to understand linear algebra. Although the members of the group were attending a college class in which they were being taught linear algebra, their backgrounds and the behaviour of others in the class was impeding their learning. The students were beginning to become more concerned about falling behind, especially with a summer exam pending. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: student group; personal tutor; funds; learning goals [Miscellaneous]: Failure to learn; stress; group learning; tutor; shared solution [Solution Description]: The student group took its learning into its own hands. It sought out a private personal tutor to provide additional linear algebra teaching after the college class. Each of the students had limited funds. However the group as a whole pooled sufficient funds to pay for the tutor. The tutor was able to provide effective class teaching to all of the students in the group. Furthermore, the tutor was able to provide individual tutoring to single members of the group, so that each of the students achieved their own learning goals.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>6001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Violence and intimidation as defence mechanism</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Social Services[ProblemDescription]: Craig was 15 years old; a boy with little or no experience beyond his physically and emotionally deprived inner-city home - and this was not his first experience of residential care. However, he was initially disoriented by this new rural placement near the sea. He tried to cover this up with an urban swagger and unspoken aggression to go with his hoody appearance. Still, the initial shock was there for all to see as he stared out of the window, looking across a green horizon, uninterrupted by streets and tall buildings. The care system had not been good for Craig or he for it. He'd been through foster homes and children's homes, each with similar outcomes - exclusion following threats, damage, violence and a sneering intimidation that was his standard defence mechanism. He would threaten and anxious staff would respond with counter-threats. He would then throw a chair or a fist and staff would restrain him - a feat often requiring three or four of them to do it safely and successfully - his considerable size and strength being a useful support to his already alienated personality. This cycle - Craig's life for more than three years - had the advantage of predictability and of keeping the world at a safe emotional distance. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: boy; mother; frustration; environment; anger; cause; self-determination; personal benefit [Miscellaneous]: Residential care; new environment; physical violence; intimidation; side with resident; self-restraint [Solution Description]: The boy is confused, bewildered and hurting. The boy also hates his Mother. Most of all there is frustration and a sense of complete powerlessness over his own life. And because of her the boy is in a strange place with strange people with no chance of influencing anything. It is important to recognise the boy powerlessness as the cause of his anger and hitting out as the beginning. It was essential to ensure staff are lined-up alongside the boy, rather than locking horns in a power struggle that no one would win. The quietness of the environment and the staff's deliberate, gentle way of speaking to him seems to have opened a space up for the boy. Tentatively at first he steps into it and begins to share not just his anger, but some of its causes. Staff need to explain to the boy the importance of avoiding physical restraint. As long as staff intervenes physically he does not have to take responsibility for his own behaviour. Over time he begins to comprehend what choice and self-determination means for him and others around him. He is able to appreciate the personal benefits of accepting the respect and trust of others and reciprocating it. Ultimately to talk through his feelings rather than act on them makes the difference.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>6002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Re-creating memories from childhood</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Social Services[ProblemDescription]: Sam was one of those children whose social and emotional disadvantage was well established almost from the moment of his conception. Sam was a regular witness to, and a victim of his parent's volatile relationship, as well as the inability of his well-meaning grandmother to protect him. By the time he started school Sam was already displaying disturbing behaviour consistent with an attachment disorder. On occasion he acted out the same scenes at his new home, with staff and with other children at the home as the target of his aggression. His mistrust of all adults, especially younger women (at whom much of his anger was directed) was deep and real and dominated his existence. He was also still confused by the mixed messages still being given to him regularly by his mother and grandmother. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: staff; boy; understanding; facilities; environment [Miscellaneous]:  [Solution Description]: Staff need to help the boy to gradually relate to the other boys around him who are all around his own age and have similar experiences. While none of the boys readily shares their pasts with each other, there is an unspoken understanding between them. It is essential to help the boy feel less self-conscious as he learns, along with the other boys, to play as the boy?s chaotic and deprived early life has offered few opportunities to play. There is sparse facilities at home and at school his behaviour frightened most of his peers. At Marlowe Child and Family Services however, he begins to express himself in an environment that offers him safety.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing an Applicant`s Difficult Parent</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A parent of an applicant to a university undergraduate degree course was convinced that the applicant?s current school was withholding their child?s results. The parent believed that the results were being withheld for personal reasons. Therefore the parent rang the university continuously to complain. She told staff at the university that school?s failure to disclose results was the fault of the university. The applicant was embarrassed by their parent?s involvement in the process. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: staff member; situation; strategy; communication; trust; conversation [Miscellaneous]: Withholding information; privacy; mediation; trust; student-relative conversations [Solution Description]: The university staff member decided to play a long game to resolve the situation. She adopted a strategy to befriend all of the participants involved in it. During communications with the parent she pretended to be on the parent`s side in order to gain the parent`s trust and to manage the interactions with her. At the same time the staff member tried to communicate with the school, highlighting the problems that the parent was causing for the university. As a consequence of mediating different conversations, the situation was resolved to the satisfaction of all participants.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Handling a Parent`s Complaint</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A parent of a school pupil complained to the Department of Education. The substance of the complaint was that the requirement to learn the Welsh language was violating the pupil?s human rights. The parent behaviour was aggressive towards the Department?s staff, which in turn alienated the staff towards her complaint. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: staff; situation; member of parliament; school staff; advantages; process [Miscellaneous]: Aggression towards staff; alienation; communication; permission; explaining procedures [Solution Description]: Staff at the Department recommended that she communicate directly with the staff at the pupil`s school to resolve the situation. She was also recommended to communicate directly with her member of parliament. The staff explained to the parent both the current legislative situation and the processes to follow to communicate to school staff and the member of parliament. The staff also made the effort to explain to the parent the advantages to the child of learning another language. In order to resolve the situation the parent was allowed to complain, a process supported by the Department staff.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Supporting a Depressed Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An undergraduate student becomes depressed during the second year and attempted suicide. The university staff were initially uncertain how to handle this situation. The course director was not able to deal with the situation emotionally or strategically. There were concerns about how the student in question would interact with other students on the course. The course director also refused to speak to the parent due to the need to protect the privacy of the student. The student herself was not prepared to initiate the involvement of the parent. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: situation; student; parent; conversation; university; absence of love; support; meetings; accessible information [Miscellaneous]: Emotions; depression; managed conversation; individual support; counselling [Solution Description]: The situation was resolved by inviting the student to attend the university with one of her parents. The university managed to facilitate a conversation between the student and the parent. This conversation revealed that the underlying problem was an absence of love towards the student during time at university. As a result of the facilitated conversation, the problem was resolved quickly. Support for the student was put in place. The university decided to support regular meetings with the course director to monitor the student, and access to counselling services. Staff tried to give a staff friend to the student to be able to talk to. In addition, staff tried to make important information accessible to the student at all times.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4004</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Supporting a Homeless Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: Security staff reported that an undergraduate student had attacked one of their staff. The student had been living in the 24-hour computing labs. A security staff member on a night-time patrol had encountered the student and challenged him. The university staff were very surprised that the named student would have attacked someone. Whilst attempting to flee, the student had accidently stood on the toes of the security staff, which had triggered the report. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: university staff; informal meeting; home; exam results; mediated conversation; pressure; mechanisms; outcome [Miscellaneous]: Homelessness; family feuds; mediation; understanding; student support [Solution Description]: University staff first located the student on campus. Staff tried to invite the student for an informal meeting with his personal tutor. Care was taken to not inflame the situation. The meeting revealed that the student was homeless. He had left home because he was doing badly in his studies. He left home without reporting his exam results to his strict parents. The problem was resolved by inviting the parents into the university to have a mediated conversation with the personal tutor. The personal tutor asked the parents to not put pressure on the student. He explained that the university would try to put in place mechanisms to help the student. The outcome was improved results that a return to home for the student.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4005</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Mediating between Academic Staff and Students</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student on a field trip to a foreign city missed the return flight home, and was forced to travel back on their own. The student had missed the flight back because was engaged in nocturnal activities in a local brothel, and did not notice the time. The academic in charge of the trip held strong conservative views, and objected to the student?s behaviour. The outcome was a major conflict between the academic and the student that led to physical threats only resolved by keeping the two people in different rooms. As a consequence the university considered abandoning future field trips. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: situation; chaperone; student; staff member; mediator [Miscellaneous]: Personal conflicts; power relationships; chaperone; monitored meetings; mediation [Solution Description]: The university managed to resolve the situation by providing a chaperone for all meetings between the student and staff member over the subsequent months. The chaperone ensured that the academic and the student were not allowed in the same room together alone. The chaperone also acted as a mediator for communication between the student and staff member.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4006</SourceId>
    <SourceName>The Student Giving Back the Masters Degree </SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A postgraduate student who had been awarded their postgraduate degree contacted the university and asked to return their degree. The university replied that this was not possible. Next the student informed the university that he had cheated by committing academic misconduct in his dissertation work. The university double-checked the dissertation for plagiarism, and was unable to detect any misconduct. The student then reported that he had someone else undertake the dissertation work on his behalf.The student explained that he achieving the Masters had given him a superiority complex that was then inhibiting him from obtaining a job.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: university staff; conversation; accusation; matter; guilt; student; situation [Miscellaneous]: Guilt; lack of confidence; explanation; self-confidence [Solution Description]: The university staff managed to resolve the situation through a lengthy conversation with the student. The staff member tried to respond to each accusation by the student in turn. Eventually the staff member told the student that there was no evidence of this, and that the matter was closed. The student responded that the conversation had allowed the student to offload any guilt that he had about the post-graduate reward. The student was now happy and received the degree. This demonstrates that attempting to talk to the student is sufficient to resolve the situation before it becomes more serious.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4007</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Pairing Students to Manage their Personalities</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was regularly angry in her interactions with the university. She would treat each interaction in simple, black-and-white terms, which would leave her dissatisfied much of the time. The student was diagnosed with borderline personality disorder. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: university staff; situation; buddy; student; friendship; degree course [Miscellaneous]: Personality problems; people buddies; individual characteristics [Solution Description]: The university staff managed to resolve this situation by providing another student as a buddy for the student. The other student was very shy. The result of the friendship was a change in the behaviour of both students. The student with borderline personality disorder became more calm, and the student who was shy became more confident and outward going. One reason for the success of this friendship was that the shy student was very effective at saying `no` to requests without saying `no` directly, and the other student accepted this way of working. At the end of the course both students were able to graduate from their degree courses.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4008</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing Future Student Expectations</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An applicant to the university had failed to achieved the required A-level grades to enter university, and was very disappointed. The staff managing the entrance process was managing the situation. The applicant, his father and his mother had all rang the university to seek a change of decision. The mother had shouted at the staff, blaming the university for wider social problems associated with youth unemployment.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: staff member; continued dialogue; parents; frustration; applicant; career options [Miscellaneous]: Angry relatives; understanding; communication; explanation; exploring options [Solution Description]: The staff member managed to resolve the situation through continued dialogue with parents. First of all, she tried to allow the parents to vent their frustration so that she would not be interrupted later on. She then explained that the applicant still had many future career options open to him. The options included re-sitting the A-levels, and applying to other universities.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4009</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Helping the Self-Harming Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was self-harming in front of the staff because the university was unable to provide assessment marks to her on demand. She was kicking furniture and banging her head against the office wall. The student said that she needed to have the assessment outcomes to obtain a visa for travel purposes. At first the university staff were uncertain how to manage this situation. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: staff member; immediate situation; student; private office; university staff; request; exceptional circumstances; authority; assessment marks; shortcut [Miscellaneous]: Personal stress; physical violence; exceptional circumstances; additional support; demonstrating care [Solution Description]: The staff member managed to contain the immediate situation by first leading the student into a private office out of sight and sound of other students. The university staff then tried to seek a means of meeting the student`s request due to the exceptional circumstances. The university staff did this by locating a member of academic staff with the necessary authority to compute and release the assessment marks. The student was provided with what she needed so desperately within one hour of the situation developing. This shortcut served to calm the student considerably.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4010</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Support for a Sexually-Abused Student</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student new to the university had attended a social event to the university on a Friday night. On Monday morning the student came to the Department to allege that a sexual assault had taken place on her. She was desperately seeking advice from the university. She had not informed the police beforehand, although some of her friends were concerned that she should. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: member of department; student; private space; complaint; counselling; incident; student union; CCTV system; information; university; prosecution; outcomes [Miscellaneous]: Sexual assault; police involvement; making a complaint; building trust; prosecution [Solution Description]: A member of the Department`s staff provided the student with a private space to discuss what had happened. He recorded the complaint on her behalf. He used the complaint to speak to the Student`s Union and to counselling. The Student`s Union located the incident and the accused student using its CCTV system. As a result of this information, the student was expelled from the university. Furthermore the information was provided to the police who undertook a prosecution. All of these outcomes were possible because the Department staff led the student through the difficult and challenging process in a trusting way.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>7001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Connecting seafarers to their families</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Quality of Life[ProblemDescription]: Connecting seafarers to their families was expensive and difficult. Seafarers were only able to talk to their families using expensive technologies with limited bandwidths. Seafarers used prepaid cards to call their families back home using a ship?s Iridium phone. This was expensive. Seafarers used to spend up to $150 per month calling their families. Families were only able to send e-mail messages to their relatives on the ships. As a result, seafarers were lonely. Their quality of life was affected. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: installation; broadband; ship; seafarer; families; accommodation space; social networking sites; social network media; living at sea [Miscellaneous]: loneliness; expensive; poor quality of life; free connections; social media [Solution Description]: The installation of Inmarsat 500 broadband on board ships has transformed communications between seafarers and families. The system is installed in all accommodation spaces in a ship. Seafarers can now access social networking sites such as Facebook, Twitter and Friendster. The access to these social networking media is free for everyone. As a result it has been sailing and living at sea pleasant and fun.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>7002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Improving living conditions in prisons</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Quality of Life[ProblemDescription]: The increasing number of people in prison leads to prison overcrowding. Prison overcrowding contributes to a range of problems that arise. One reason for this is the poor accommodation for prisoners available in prisons. Problems include reduced staff morale and difficulties controlling the prison inmates. The prisoners suffer from poor health. Staff suffer from stress because of caring for the prisoners. Many of these problems arise because of the old buildings that are used to house prisoners. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: prison; example; wing of their own; communal space; architecture; fresh air; communal section; loggia; bars; courtyards; seating wall; single file [Miscellaneous]: poor quality of life; lack of freedom; poor accommodation; outdoor spaces; free movement [Solution Description]: Some countries are building new types of prison. One example is Austria?s show-piece prison in Leoben. Prisoners in groups of up to thirteen are accommodated in a wing of their own and can move freely among the cells and the communal spaces. The architecture identified the importance of fresh air to the prisoners.  Each communal section has a type of loggia, which is surrounded by bars, but the prisoners are outdoors. The prisoners also have three courtyards to move in. Each courtyard has concrete seating walls meandering through the space, so it is no longer possible to circle around in a single file.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>7003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Improving prisoner activities in prisons</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Quality of Life[ProblemDescription]: The increasing number of people in prison leads to prison overcrowding. Authorities cannot increase the size of prisons to house the larger number of prisoners. In turn prison overcrowding contributes to a range of problems. One problem is reduced staff morale. A second problem is difficulties controlling the prisoners. Prisoners suffer from poor health. Staff suffer stress from caring for the prisoners. In overcrowded prisons, the prison controls prisoners by restricting their movement. Unfortunately this adds to the stress and hostility felt by prisoners. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: solution; prisoner security; idleness; opportunities; exercise; sports; cultural and religious activities; level of risk; risk groups [Miscellaneous]: poor quality of life; lack of freedom; increased activities; classifying risk; dividing prisoners [Solution Description]: One solution to prisoner security is to reduce the idleness of the prisoners. The prison should provide more opportunities for exercise, sports, cultural and religious activities. Active prisoners are less likely to feel stressed and hostile. The prison should also classify and house prisons according to their level of risk. Lower risk groups require less security. These prisoners can be managed on a lower security basis.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>7004</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Improving the health of prisoners</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Quality of Life[ProblemDescription]: The increasing number of people in prison leads to prison overcrowding. The facilities available to prisoners become inadequate. The inadequate facilities are toilets, kitchens and sanitation. As toilet, sanitation and cooking facilities become inadequate to serve a growing prison population, the health of prison staff and prisoners is at risk. This risk increases the difficulties to control contagious diseases. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: sanitation; inmate; preventative health care; food preparation; personal hygiene; prisoner labour; vegetable garden; livestock; pigs; chickens; varied food; prison; nutrition; meaningful activity [Miscellaneous]: facilities, health, sanitation, cooking [Solution Description]: One solution is to improve the sanitation. Seek to organize and train inmates in preventative health care including basic sanitation, food preparation and personal hygiene. Another solution is to involve low risk prisoner labour to cultivate vegetable gardens, raise livestock such as pigs and chickens, and to provide more and varied food for the prison. This will improve nutrition. It will also provide the prisoners with meaningful activity.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8001</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Depressed and abusive teenage boy</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: Alice is a single parent of Peter, a teenage boy who is increasingly losing all motivation and has depression. The counselling support he receives at school will end soon. He refuses to get out of bed in the morning and is losing interest in his schooling and personal hygiene. He prefers to remain alone in his room on his computer.  When spoken to he is abusive and reacts violently. There is a hostile atmosphere in the home. His behaviour is steadily getting worse, and he is at risk of failing his GCSEs.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: parents; computer; bedroom; action; strained relationship; son; trusted family member; GP; counselling; local organisations; Local Authority; national Gingerbread Assocation [Miscellaneous]: Depression; violence; hostility; counselling; independent support [Solution Description]: The parents do not want to take the computer from the bedroom. This action will make their strained relationship with their son worse. The son is encouraged to talk to an independent and trusted family member, or family friend. The son will also visit his GP and ask for further counselling. The parent will seek support from local organisations either through the Local Authority or from the national Gingerbread association. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8002</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing a disrespectful child</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: An intelligent 13-year-old boy voices opinions that are hurtful and embarrassing. He refuses to consider the views of others and often makes discriminatory statements. The parents have removed his privileges and threatened to take him out of the school he loves. This approach has not worked. He now makes hurtful comments to his mother about her appearance. He insults neighbours and guests to their home. He is rude and mimics their behaviour. He shows no remorse for his actions. His mother is at the end of her tether. She is concerned she may react badly to her son or have to leave the home.   [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: son; boundaries; clear rules; acceptable behaviour; rude comments; firm tone; explanation; comments; parents; punishment; rule breaking; team; privileges; rewards; consistent good behaviour [Miscellaneous]: Hurtful comments; rude behaviour; setting boundaries; punishment and reward system  [Solution Description]: The son needs very clear boundaries set. The parents are going to set clear rules on acceptable behaviour. They will state what they are not prepared to tolerate. They will highlight rude comments in a firm tone with the boy.  He will receive an explanation as to why the comments are hurtful. Both parents will agree punishments for rule breaking that are realistic. They will work as a team and follow through on punishments. The son can then regain his privileges as rewards for consistent good behaviours. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8003</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Teenage behavioural problems</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: Josh has behavioural problems. His parents receive conflicting advice on his behaviours. He is stealing money and damaging property. He does not attend school regularly. When he does attend, he is asked to leave classes because of his behaviour. He has threatened young boys and abused older women. Josh is now adult size (six foot, fourteen stone) and physically uncontrollable. His parents have five children but Josh takes up the majority of their time and energy. Their relationship and business are suffering. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Behavioural problems; theft; conflict resolutions; alternative activities [Solution Description]: Punishment and reward systems do not work in this extreme case. In discussion, the parents agree to stop verbally fighting with their son and leave him alone to consider his actions. He is encouraged to see these issues as his problem not theirs. The parents will walk away from conflict with him. He is given a punch bag and gloves to take out his frustrations. He is likely to leave school soon so he needs activities to do. He will look into training courses, sport and employment as alternatives to school.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8004</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Inappropriate sexual activities</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: The parent of a 14-year-old girl has found her `sexting? (sending sex related texts). The daughter has previously received sex related texts from her boyfriend. They confront the boyfriend asking him to stop. The daughter has now received a graphic sexual image from this 14-year-old boyfriend. She is also telling lies about her activity and location. The Mother is deeply concerned that the daughter is too young for sexual activity. She is also concerned that the images and texts will be shared with others.    [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: parent; mother; images; indecent materials; daughter; personal images; camera phone; basic model; teenagers; texts; images [Miscellaneous]: Inappropriate sexual activity; parental conversations; explaining consequences [Solution Description]: The parent speaks to the boyfriend`s mother and reveals the images her daughter has been sent. Both sets of parents agree to delete any images and indecent materials. The parent educates the daughter on the dangers of making personal images publically available. The Mother replaces the daughter`s camera phone with a basic model (without a camera). Both parents agree to point out to the teenagers the law relating to indecent images. In discussion with the children, they both agree to stop sending texts and images.  </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8005</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Dealing with bullying</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: Another 13-year-old boy from his school is bullying Todd (13). The bully is part of a gang. The gang are targeting the family home and causing a nuisance. The ringleader claims that Todd abused his younger sister. This is untrue. Todd?s mother is concerned that he rarely leaves the home now. The bully chases him and hits him. She is also concerned that there will be consequences for the younger children if they take the matter to the police.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: mother; bully; school; behaviour standards; local PCSO; bullying [Miscellaneous]: Bullying; isolation; parental consultation; school support; contacting local police  [Solution Description]: The mother knows the parents of the bully. She contacts them and talks the matter through. Both parents agree to separate the boys from hanging out in the same places. To stop further violence the parents will contact the school. The school has a good record for dealing with bullying and setting behaviour standards. The parents will also contact their local PCSO for advice. However, they will not officially report the issue to avoid making the situation worse. They will reconsider this if the bullying gets worse.  </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8006</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Coping with difficult siblings </SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: 12-year-old Alice behaves badly towards her older sister Claire (15). Both keen ice-skaters, the sisters require expensive equipment for their hobby. The family collectively save a lot of money to buy Claire a specialist pair of skates. The younger sister damages these skates in anger. She kicks her sister in the process. The skates need temporary repairs. However, the long-term damage to the skates is unclear. They may need to be replaced.   [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: sister; repairs; compensational feelings of jealousy; feelings of anger; daughter; regular amount of money [Miscellaneous]: Jealousy; sibling rivalry; financial penalty; setting behaviour rules [Solution Description]: The younger sister is remorseful. She agrees to pay for the repairs. She must also pay compensation to her sister. The parents discuss feelings of jealousy with both daughters. All parties agree that they will discuss together feelings of anger. The parents make their daughter aware that violent behaviour is not acceptable. The younger daughter also agrees to save a regular amount of money to pay for future repairs.    </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8007</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Helping a child with eating disorder and self-harming </SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: An academically advanced teen is self-harming. Diagnosed with aspergers at 6-years-old he has recently come out as gay. He tells his parents that he is confident. His mother notices red marks on his arms. The boy explains he is biting himself. His mother also discovers he is not eating regularly. She finds messages that he wishes to be skinny and he enjoys compliments for his weight loss. She suspects he has an eating disorder.    [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: boy; weight loss; health issues; fragile mental state; parents calm manner; love; support; hugs; praise; outside help; family GP; counselling [Miscellaneous]: Self-harming; eating disorder; parental support; counselling; use of outside specialist agencies [Solution Description]: The boy is in denial about his weight loss and health issues. He is in a fragile mental state and evades questions. The parents talk to him in a calm manner to explain they are worried. Both parents seek to reassure the son of their love and support. Discussions always involve hugs and praise. The parents seek outside help. The family GP offers counselling and a referral to CAHMS. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8008</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Coping with ritual behaviours </SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: Alex, a 15-year-old boy, is behaving in ritual ways. His parents think his habits are odd. He regularly stands with his head in his hands and knees bent. He also empties all the bins from the house late a night. Alex stays this is a habit and that he can stop it. His parents continue to find him acting in these ways. He stops the behaviour when he sees people watching him.    [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: mother; family GP; OCD; control issues; behaviour; ritual behaviour; grandfather death; counselling; stress; support [Miscellaneous]: Unusual behaviour; OCD; GP support; stress; bereavement counselling [Solution Description]: The mother speaks to the family GP. Alex may have a mild form of OCD. The GP explains that OCD is about control issues and he may grow out of it. And that this is not uncommon behaviour in teenagers. Alex explains he thinks that the cause of the ritual behaviour is his grandfather?s death. The parents arrange counselling. They also talk to Alex about stress in his life that triggers his behaviours. Alex is happier with this support. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8009</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Dealing with theft</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: Mum of three, Sally, has money going missing from her purse. She has asked her three children if they are taking it. Then, a large sum of money goes missing. In Sally?s opinion, only the youngest daughter was at home and could have taken it. Sally searches her daughter?s bedroom. The daughter denies taking it. She later claims to find the money in the kitchen. Consequently, Sally removes her daughter?s pocket money and access to cash. Her daughter shows no remorse and continues to lie.    [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: access to cash; interim solution; secrets; parents; daughter; money; quiet space; issues; sums of cash [Miscellaneous]: Theft; lying; withdrawal of privileges; monitoring behaviour  [Solution Description]: Removing the daughter`s access to cash is an interim solution. The daughter is keeping secrets. She is gently encouraged by her parents to reveal the reasons she needs money. Her mother believes there is an underlying reason for this behaviour. Both parents create quiet space for the daughter to talk to them about her issues. The parents agree to monitor their daughter`s behaviour and will eventually allow her access to small sums of cash (pocket money). </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8010</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Removing teenage daughter from the home</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: A teenage girl with violent mood swings destroys her parent?s property. She throws nail varnish over walls and defaces the carpet with a swear word. She is physically violent to her parents. This time the parents contact the police. The daughter struggles with her anger. She runs away from home when confronted. The parents are exhausted and unable to cope.   [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: daughter; social services; temporary care; home; organisation; foster care; weekends; psychiatric evaluation; praise; love; long-term assistance [Miscellaneous]: Violence; mood swings; anger; temporary care; removal from home; outside support [Solution Description]: Previously, the daughter has been referred to CAMHS services. She refuses to fully engage with them. The parents contact social services about temporary care away from the home. They contact Support Breaks, an organisation supporting young people and families. The teenager will stay in foster care for weekends and undergo psychiatric evaluation. The parents write down their praise and love for their daughter in a letter for her to read. They realise their daughter needs long-term assistance.    </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8011</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Runaway child </SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: The parents of Susan ban her from using online chat rooms and facebook. Susan chats to older boys and posts sexual content. This is causing arguments between her and her parents. She refuses to stop. Her parents block the accounts. Susan refuses to accept this punishment and creates new accounts. Her parents discover the new activity and confront her. Susan argues with her parents and runs away to meet a boy she chatted to online. She stays away over night and returns the next day.      [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: parents; behaviour; safe environment; death of get grandfather; close relative; mentor; extra support [Miscellaneous]: Online sexual activity, running away from home, safe trusting environment, counselling [Solution Description]: The parents realise this behaviour is out of the ordinary for their daughter. They assure her she is in a safe environment and can talk to them. The daughter eventually explains that she has not been coping since the death of her grandfather. The parents arrange counselling. A close relative agrees to act as a mentor for the daughter. She can contact the mentor whenever she needs to. Susan is happy for this extra support. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>8012</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Anti-social teen</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Childcare[ProblemDescription]: Hayley is often anti-social. She is refusing to socialise with her family at meal times. Hayley would rather eat alone. She also appears conscious of her weight. If told she must eat with the family she refuses to eat altogether. Her parents feel that removing privileges like her laptop will only make the situation worse. However, they do not want Hayley to remain isolated or to eat alone while the family eat together. Hayley is 14-years-old.    [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]: body image; eating; serious issue; mealtime eating; battle; family; healthy meals; arrangement; situation [Miscellaneous]: Anti-social behaviour; eating disorder; isolation; agreeing new eating arrangements; supported monitoring  [Solution Description]: Hayley is asking many questions related to her body image. As a result, the parents feel that they should not focus on eating as a serious issue. The parents agree that mealtime eating should not be a battle between them and their daughter. In discussions, Hayley admits she is conscious of the family watching her eating. Her parents believe she will not eat if forced to sit with the family.  As an interim measure, the family agree that Hayley may eat her meals alone. Hayley agrees to eat regular healthy meals as part of this arrangement. They will all revisit the situation in a few months time.  </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4011</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing a student who failed their project</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student had submitted his Masters project, and required his degree to be awarded by March to obtain a post-study work visa. Recent changes in UK Border Agency regulations limited the student?s ability to obtain a post-study work visa. However, the student?s project was suspected of academic misconduct and his award could not be made by March. He was found guilty of misconduct by a University panel, and subsequently failed the project. Very upset he attended the course office in tears to ask the Course Officer about what he should do. The Course Officer advised the student to speak to his supervisor and obtain support from the Student Centre. The Course Officer went through the appeals process and the grounds an appeal can be made on, while suggesting the student spoke to the International Office about their visa.  The student came back to the office on several occasions upset and needing support. The Course Officer reiterated where they could go and seek advice to ensure the student sought all the help they could.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: academic misconduct; appeal; visa; [Solution Description]: On appeal the student was given a three month referral period to complete their project. The Course Officer, now experienced in this student?s situation, decided to spend time with the student to ensure they knew exactly what they needed to do next. The Course Officer explained in great detail the new deadlines, fees, where advice should be sought on the work the student was required to do, and the likely outcome of the project re-submission. The student was pleased to note that the fail mark would not appear on their official transcript and went on to successfully complete the degree. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4012</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Managing a student who failed their project</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student had submitted his Masters project, and required his degree to be awarded by March to obtain a post-study work visa. Recent changes in UK Border Agency regulations limited the student?s ability to obtain a post-study work visa. However, the student?s project was suspected of academic misconduct and his award could not be made by March. He was found guilty of misconduct by a University panel, and subsequently failed the project. Very upset he attended the course office in tears to ask the Course Officer about what he should do. The Course Officer advised the student to speak to his supervisor and obtain support from the Student Centre. The Course Officer went through the appeals process and the grounds an appeal can be made on, while suggesting the student spoke to the International Office about their visa.  The student came back to the office on several occasions upset and needing support. The Course Officer reiterated where they could go and seek advice to ensure the student sought all the help they could.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: academic misconduct; appeal; visa; [Solution Description]: On appeal the student was given a three month referral period to complete their project. The Course Officer, now experienced in this student?s situation, decided to spend time with the student to ensure they knew exactly what they needed to do next. The Course Officer explained in great detail the new deadlines, fees, where advice should be sought on the work the student was required to do, and the likely outcome of the project re-submission. The student was pleased to note that the fail mark would not appear on their official transcript and went on to successfully complete the degree. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4013</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Student panicking before the deadline</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A hard working student, with first class marks to date, emailed the Course Officer to say he had decided to withdraw from the course without submitting his final project. He explained in his email that he felt that the work he had done was not good enough to pass and that he would not be able to gain his degree. The student did not want to discuss this with their supervisor as they felt intimidated by them.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: course withdrawal; intimidated; struggling with writing;  [Solution Description]: The Course Officer calmly reassured the student that supervisors had a lot of experience in supporting students in project work and that they would have had many students who?d faced similar problems. The Course Officer was able to persuade the student to attend the University to discuss their situation in person and bring in the work they?d done to date. The student explained that they were in fact embarrassed to let the supervisor know that they were struggling with writing up their project, and that with only one month left they felt that they wouldn?t be able to complete on time. To resolve the issue the Course Officer was able to speak privately to the project tutor about the students concerns and show them what the student had done to date. The situation was resolved by passing the tutor?s positive comments to the student, who was then felt able to discuss this in person with the tutor.  </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4014</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Out of character behaviour in missing deadlines</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: The Course Officer has a lot of contact with her students and was normally made aware of students with extenuating circumstances either by tutors or by the students themselves. A student doing well on her undergraduate degree did not submit a piece of coursework for a module.  The Course Officer realised that this non-submission was unusual behaviour for this student and contacted the tutor to see if they were aware of this. The tutor was surprised and the Course Officer suggested that they would contact the student directly to ask what had happened.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: extenuating circumstances; non-submission of coursework; unique student circumstances;  [Solution Description]: The student explained they were having significant family problems and the Course Officer identified that this was a case for extenuating circumstances. However, the student hadn?t submitted their claim as they believed that they had missed the deadline, and had accepted that the mark for the coursework would be zero. The Course Officer persuaded them to submit their claim by explaining what the panel could consider, that depending on the circumstances of the submission a number of options were available to them. In this case, the claim was accepted and the panel believed that it was sufficiently serious for the student to be given a module mark that equated to the exam mark in lieu of the coursework, and they therefore passed the module. The Course Officer resolved the issue through taking the extra time to consider the unique circumstances of this student. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4015</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Transition from school to university</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An experienced Course Officer is aware that the transition from school to university can be challenging for some students, and in difficult scenarios they look for out of character behaviour. One student started with high coursework grades in semester one, but then it was noted that they were not submitting work or attending exams for every module. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: out of character behaviour; struggling with workload; learning success;  [Solution Description]: The Course Officer contacted the student who explained that they found it challenging to take notes and work under University conditions that were different to school. They had struggled with the workload and were unsure how to organise their time or write certain types of assignment/reports. The Course Officer noted that student was overwhelmed with information at induction and first week of term and so that they miss the support on offer to them. The student was advised to go to student centre and access the learning success team who offer study skills, essay writing, and exam preparation. The Course Officer noted this concern and made sure that they reminded all students of where this support can be accessed, posting a message on Moodle, highlighting the new study support link in Moodle, and noting it in staff/student liaison meetings. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4016</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Technology malfunction causing non-submission</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A part-time student, while ill, tried to submit a coursework assignment from hospital. They contacted the module leader to inform them that they were unable to submit because Moodle was not working, they asked to submit their assignment via email. The module leader advised the student of the policy on submission and that it could not be accepted by email. A distressed student contacted the school office and was advised to submit an extenuating circumstances claim.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: illness; technology difficulties; assignment non-submission;   [Solution Description]: However, the student continued to call to explain it was a Moodle fault, speaking to numerous staff members. The student then came to the office in person, distressed, he appeared intimidating to the staff with his level of frustration. His Course Officer sat him down and calmly explained the extenuating circumstances procedure and that they would need evidence that Moodle was not working. The Course Officer listened to the student and asked questions which led them to believe a further investigation would be necessary. The student was very experienced in the subject area of the assignment and did not appear to be making false claims. The Course Officer sought advice to investigate the IT/Moodle issue from the technical team, and was able to identify there had been a problem at the time the student was trying to submit their assignment. This issue was not obvious without the investigation by the technical team, but now identified the Course Officer was able to obtain permission to allow the student to submit the assignment again, and pass. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4017</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Student with an unknown disability</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student came to the office upset that they were having greater difficulty study and completing the written coursework compared to their peers. The coursework rubric and reading was causing them a lot of difficulty in comprehension. The Course Officer explained that the University offered a number of classes on study support, and that the learning success team in student services could help them diagnose the difficult they were having.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: disability services; student study support; diagnosis of difficulty;  [Solution Description]: The Course Officer recognised the need to be empathetic and supportive to ensure the student was not made to feel uncomfortable. Also, the Course Officer was aware that the assessment by the student services takes time, so when the report came through it needed to be acted upon urgently. The student was diagnosed as dyslexic. Aware that the student had completed some module assessments already, the Course Officer urgently contacted the students tutor to ensure that student would have the support needed going forward, and that completed marking was now considered retrospectively. The student was informed and reassured that they did not lose out on marks. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4018</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Student queries their mark</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: Marks for a MCQ assessment were released, and a student awarded zero contacted the lecturer to complain. This was forwarded to the Course Officer to investigate what was going on. The Course Officer was able to identify through Moodle that the student had never attempted this test. The student still insisted that they had done the MCQs. The Course Officer asked for an investigation of students? usage of Moodle from the technical team. It was identified that the student had gone in and looked at the test, however the student had taken too long and was timed out (standard practice for this type of test), and they were then unable to access it again. The student was contacted and the situation explained, the Course Officer explained that the process of time limited MCQs was there to ensure the rigour of marking and the credibility of the assessment as part of the degree.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: technical difficulties; extension request denied;  [Solution Description]: The student accepted this and admitted that they were well versed in doing MCQs in the past, but thought they may be able to get an extension if they said they thought they?d done it. It was upheld that the student was given a mark of zero.   </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4019</SourceId>
    <SourceName>A student bought code for their coursework</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was suspected of buying code for their coursework from a website rent-a-code. They were invited to the academic misconduct panel to explain their case. The student came to the office distressed and unsure what would happen to them. The Course Officer explained the plagiarism and academic misconduct policy to the student.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: buying coursework; admitting misconduct;  [Solution Description]: The experienced Course Officer advised the student that it is better to always to be honest and explain what they`ve done, and this will go in their favour. The Course Officer explained that students will be caught out if they try to hide their behaviour, that it is in their interested to accept what they have done, and there are a range of options available to the misconduct panel including exclusion from the University. They were also advised to seek the support from student services. The student admitted that they had purchased the code from the website; they were allowed to repeat the year.</Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4020</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Student complaint over late coursework marks</SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: The marks for a piece of coursework had not been released by the published date and a student attended the office to complain on behalf of their class. The Course Officer explained the policy on returning marked work as set out in the University policy. The unhappy student contacted the office every day following the missed deadline for returning the marks. The Course Officer ensured that they were consistent in the advice they gave to the student and identified when they would contact them and how.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: late publication of results; escalating complaints; formal feedback processes; [Solution Description]: The Course Officer explained how the complaint would be taken further, and the complaint was escalated to the Director of Undergraduate Studies. Ensuring the student was kept informed the Course Officer also spoke to the student representative(s) for the course in order for the information to be disseminated throughout the student body. The module leader was approached by the Director and the marked work was then returned to the students two weeks late, an apology was posted into Moodle. The Course Officer also made sure that they contacted the student who initiated the complaint directly to ensure that they had received their coursework mark. The issue was resolved and the student was further advised where formal feedback could be given about any issues with the module, advising them of the process of staff/student liaison, and the importance of this feedback.    </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
  <MatchedSource>
    <SourceId>4021</SourceId>
    <SourceName>Accusation of plagiarism </SourceName>
    <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was accused of plagiarism after they had received their coursework mark on Moodle. The student was livid at the accusation and adamant that they had followed all the practices including referencing. They contacted the Course Officer and queried why they had been given a mark on Moodle and then retrospectively been accused of plagiarism. The Course Officer referred them to the disclaimer on submission and explained that the work had not been moderated when it was released, and that subsequent moderation had highlighted the accusation. The Course Officer calmly explained that the student would have to wait for the investigation to be conducted, informing them of the process that will be followed and how this links to the formal assessment board process. The student was reassured that all steps would be followed to allow them a fair hearing.  [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: 01/01/0001 00:00:00 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: investigation of plagiarism; poor practice; complaint upheld;  [Solution Description]: The student was found guilty of poor practice and the grade for the assignment was revised to a fail mark. The student had left the country at the time and was very unhappy with the results phoning many of the Course Officer`s colleagues to complain. The Course Officers took the responsibility of contacting the student to inform them that they would be kept up to date on the progress of their complaint. The Course Officer, realising the student was distressed, decided it would be reassuring for them to have one key contact for their issue, and explained that that they would personally contact them. The Course Officer was able to speak personally with the student to inform them that further investigation by the module leader had now resulted in pass mark; the student was able to progress with their degree without further incident. </Content>
    <OverallMatchValue>0</OverallMatchValue>
  </MatchedSource>
</MatchedSources>