<?xml version="1.0"?>
<MatchedSources responseId="1" similarityType="Eddie" dataSourceType="Document">
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1038</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident refusing to take medication</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident was refusing to take his medication. He was refusing to take a range of different tablet. The medication was important to his physical health. The refusal was causing serious concerns amongst the care staff. The resident does not understand or has forgotten what the medication is for. As a consequence, the resident?s physical health was affected by his refusal to take the medication. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: refusal; medication; clear explanations; trusted relationships [SolutionDescription]: The carers realised that it was important to give a clear explanation - using words and symbols that the resident could understand - each time that their medication was offered. The carers also made sure to remind the resident what the tablet is for since the resident was only prepared to swallow each tablet after he knew what it is for. Through trial and error, the carers learned that if the resident did not fully trust the staff member who was offering the medication, he was much less likely to accept it. The carers made sure to provide the medication at a speed that the resident felt comfortable with. Therefore, only carers who had built trusting relationships with the resident gave the medication.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1039</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Residents requiring more flexible routines</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident resists the requests made to him by carers to undertake activities at different times of the day. He prefers to undertake these activities at the times of his choice. These activities include eating, sleeping, and exercise. Some of the carers find this resistance distressing. The carers are unable to encourage the resident to eat. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: resistance; flexible routines; needs of residents; timetables [SolutionDescription]: The senior managers at the care home needed to consider ways of making sure that routines were flexible enough to meet the resident?s needs. Carers were reminded that a care organisation must be run for the benefit of the people with dementia who are receiving care, rather than for the convenience of staff. Carers were reminded that it is very important to enable good teamwork. It was important to avoid overriding the needs and preferences of individuals in order to complete certain tasks by a certain time. Staff made sure to make the day's timetable as flexible as possible, including mealtimes, with the resident being able to eat in their his room and have snacks available at other times.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1001</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Late stage dementia and violent outbursts</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Miss Green, a resident experiencing late stage dementia, frequently lashes out at staff (and even relatives) who are supporting her to get washed/eat/drink. There is a risk both to the staff and to the resident herself. Every attempt has been made to find creative ways to stop this behaviour: staff have tried different approaches, tones of voice and routines, but the behaviour continues. External support and advice has also been sought. The behaviour appears not to be an expression of anger directed at any specific aspect of the environment or task being undertaken. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Violent behaviour; undiagnosed; gentle support; selected support; reduce aggression [SolutionDescription]: Ultimately, in discussion with relatives and outside agencies, it has been agreed that the resident lacked capacity to make decisions, and that, subject to ongoing assessment and exploration of alternative strategies for supporting the resident, a gentle holding down of the arm while the resident is assisted with daily activities was acceptable. Good pratice: study found evidence of staff demonstrating high levels of competence in their ability to reduce aggression, anxiety and distress among residents which, in themselves, had the effect of minimising the need for restraint. Their negotiating, listening and general communication skills were notable. Managers demonstrated how they actively identified members of staff who had personal qualities that the resident responded to positively.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1002</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Verbal abuse of other residents</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Charlesworth, a resident with dementia, shouts expletives at other residents on a daily basis. She expresses herself through screaming, and what appear to be aggressive outbursts. The care home is trying to access help from outside agencies to explore the reasons behind this behaviour and is looking at how the environment might be altered to reduce this distressing behaviour. In the meantime, other residents, particularly those with dementia, are becoming distressed and, in some cases, threatening to be violent towards her. There is an identified risk of harm to the resident and to others. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: violent;disruptive;anti-social [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbal abuse; distressed other resident; risk of harm; private area; selected staff; good communication skills [SolutionDescription]: With agreement of the relatives and external agencies (including the safeguarding adults team and DOLS assessor), the resident is encouraged to reside in one area of the care home where other residents cannot hear her; this might require some level of gentle physical encouragement. This is an interim measure while an alternative action is identified with outside support. Good pratice: study found evidence of staff demonstrating high levels of competence in their ability to reduce aggression, anxiety and distress among residents which, in themselves, had the effect of minimising the need for restraint. Their negotiating, listening and general communication skills were notable. Managers demonstrated how they actively identified members of staff who had personal qualities that the resident responded to positively.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1003</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Violent behaviour needing restraint</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Townsend had to be physically restrained because he attacked a member of staff and one of the residents. He had to be physically removed from the scene and taken to his room because of the high risk of continued violence. The MCA Code of Practice, section 6.43 would support staff with these actions. Under common law staff are able to take appropriate and necessary action to restrain or remove the person, in order to prevent harm, both to that person and to anyone else. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: violent [TreatmentType]: one-off [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Physical violence; restraint; selected staff; good communication skills [SolutionDescription]: Immediate outside help was requested but the incident was a one-off and did not occur again. Good pratice: study found evidence of staff demonstrating high levels of competence in their ability to reduce aggression, anxiety and distress among residents which, in themselves, had the effect of minimising the need for restraint. Their negotiating, listening and general communication skills were notable. Managers demonstrated how they actively identified members of staff who had personal qualities that the resident responded to positively.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1004</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Accessing resident rooms without permission</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident has dementia and is used to walking around the care home. Despite the best efforts of the home to create purposeful walking where residents gain stimulation from being in certain areas of the home, this resident has the habit of walking into other residents? rooms and urinating on the beds. This is particularly distressing for those residents who are bed bound. Clearly advice needs to be sought to reduce the effects of such behaviour on other residents. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Accessing resident rooms; private spaces; gentle physical persuasion; seeking something [SolutionDescription]: Manual restraint, in the form of ?gentle physical persuasion?, was sometimes perceived as necessary to protect the rights of other residents or the safety of an individual resident. Typically, staff would try to encourage residents to remain in the lounge rather than going to other areas of the home to make it easier for them to monitor their well-being. There was clearly a need to explore why the resident was walking around the home, and whether he was searching for the toilet. There are resources available to help care homes to support purposeful walking. The use of Dementia Care Mapping could be adopted in these cases to really understand why the resident is walking into other people?s rooms.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1005</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Physical intimidation</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A tall male resident with dementia had walked across the lounge and was standing over a slight female resident sitting in a chair. The male resident was scaring the female resident, who, because of arthritis, had no means of escaping him. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Physical intimidation of residents; explanation; distraction; one-to-one resident support [SolutionDescription]: When we talk about good care practice we try to improve the interpersonal skills of the care staff. Instead of manually restraining the resident in the form of physical encouragement, staff might be able to verbally encourage the resident to move away, or to engage with something that might be more interesting to them. In these situations carers need to request specialist advice and support from the local safeguarding adults team. Where residents are putting themselves or others at risk through getting up, or walking into other people?s bedrooms, this may signify the need to request further funding for greater one-to-one support for the resident.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1036</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident refusing to behave as requested</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is refusing the respond to the requests made to her by care staff. He tells the care staff that he does not understand what she is being asked to do. The problem often occurs at bedtime. The resident refuses to go to bed at the same time as the other residents. Instead he prefers to watch television in the lounge, or to walk around the corridors talking to the other residents. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: refusal; awake at night; work patterns; adapting services [SolutionDescription]: The resident had a history of working during nights. His refusal to fit in with a routine that does not match his own is a positive sign. It showed to the care staff that the he still has a sense of his own identity and autonomy. The care staff adapted the services need to be flexible enough to fit in with his routines. The staff sought to engage him during the night. They discovered ways to provide him with company when there were not many other people around. The care staff realized that he had not given up his right to live according to his own standards and routines.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1037</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident refusing help with their personal care</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident refuses help to wash from carers each morning. She refuses help to bath and to shower. She also refuses help for stand-up washes. The carers are unable to force her to wash. As a consequence, Mrs Jones is sometimes unwashed during the day.  The carers are sometimes concerned about her appearance. Her relatives have raised concerns with the manager about her personal hygiene. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]: lethargic [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: refusal, hygiene, adapting patterns [SolutionDescription]: The carers successfully found an alternative way to provide the personal care that the resident needed. The carers tried to experiment with different washing patterns for different ways of the week. On some days, they made sure to offer a bath rather than a shower. It was important to find out as much as possible about the resident?s previous lifestyle and preferences concerning her hygiene. The carers discovered that she had always had a bath on Sunday mornings and had stand-up washes for the rest of the week. The carers were able to adapt to this routine.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1008</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Risk assessment for mobile residents</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A large female resident used a wheelchair to get around the home and who was adamant that she wished to leave the home unescorted. Outside the home was a large hill, and the manager feared that the resident would lose control of the wheelchair and cause a serious accident to herself or others. The resident was aware of the risk that she was taking, but the manager struggled with the idea of simply allowing the resident to leave on her own, even though she recognised that ultimately the resident was able to make an informed choice. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive [TreatmentType]: member of staff as escort [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Mobile residents; wheelchair; accident risk; informed choice; staff escort; relative expectations [SolutionDescription]: Ultimately the manager felt that she would have to release a member of staff to escort the resident even if that meant leaving the floor short of staff. For her, restraining people if it is in their own interests of safety was something she felt might have been necessary. In this case, a properly negotiated care plan that spelt out the risks and recorded the outcomes of discussions with the resident may be useful both in reducing the perceived need for restraint and indentifying any underlying reasons why the resident wished to take such high risks. Good practice: Relatives tended to be particularly keen on the need to keep doors locked for the residents? own protection. Relatives told us that one of the reasons for coming into the home was the fact that the resident that they visited had been at major risk of ?wandering? when they were in their own home. Creating a positive dialogue with relatives and residents to help understand these fears and worries and how they might infringe on the rights and freedoms of the resident were seen as critical in resolving this issue.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1009</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Non-compliance with home schedule</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident with physical disabilities wishes to remain in bed until 12.30pm at which time she will require support from two staff to get her up (which takes about 40 minutes). Despite staff efforts to negotiate with her, she is adamant that she will not be happy to be got up any later or any earlier than this time. However, this is lunchtime in the home, and staff are all needed to support other residents. If these two staff are taken away from the dining room, other staff will feel pressurised and lunch will be less of a pleasant and relaxed occasion for other residents. How do we resolve this? Why is this resident so fixed in her desire to get up at a set time? Is there support that she needs? In the short term do we stop the resident from getting up or do we stop other residents from getting to the table at lunchtime? [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: lethargic [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Resident non-compliance; taking away resources; impact on residents; resource trade-offs; needs of other residents [SolutionDescription]: One care home manager felt that her staff needed to act as ?detectives?, always assessing both how the environment was affecting the behaviour of residents and how their own practice might be affecting behaviour. In this case practitioners need to understand the reasons behind why a resident is so adamant that she must get up at a fixed time and how the environment of the care home might be exacerbating the need for this resident to want tight control over her routine. If we are flexible to one resident who is able to articulate powerfully her views, are we more likely to ignore those who are quiet, lacking confidence or the ability to express themselves? At the same time we should acknowledge how challenging these negotiations and decisions are for care staff, given limited staff/resident ratios and the sheer workload placed on care home practitioners.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1010</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Risk assessment about falling over</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is assessed to be at high risk of falling and lacking capacity to make decisions. The resident is therefore encouraged to get up only with support from a member of staff. This means that the individual may spend more time sitting than they would wish, which in turn will lead to more muscle wastage and the longerterm consequences of greater unsteadiness and risk in walking. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: unwell;lethargic [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Risk of falling; seated residents; discourage walking; risks trade-off [SolutionDescription]: With this in mind, where the decision has been taken with residents to discourage unaided walking, the longer-term risks and the much greater risk of falling need to be weighed up. It is clear that risk needs to be explored in the wider context of the quality of life of a resident in a care home.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1014</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Large numbers of safeguarding issues</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs. B was being cared for in a home where they were reporting 6-7 safeguarding issues in a month. On assessment it was noted that Mrs. B was angry, racist, non-compliant to care, verbally and physically abusive to residents and staff with no apparent trigger. While reading through all the documents on file it was noted that Mrs. B was a very independent lady. It was stated that she was sharing a shared room with a lady who was snoring constantly at night. Mrs. B had tried to smother her with a pillow to try and stop the noise. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: disruptive;violent [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbal physical abuse; physical assault; settling-in period; resident control; setting a routine; life history [SolutionDescription]: She came to us, we allowed 28 days of settling in which is to observe and put together a management plan. The transition from alternative care or from their own home is such a huge change to take on, so the 28 days settling in period is very, very important. It was decided through observation that we would provide Mrs. B with a routine, allow her choice and control over what was happening with her. Mrs. B when she went to bed at night always felt unsafe and so asked to be able to lock her door. We provided her with a key for her room, but the staff also had a spare. This allowed her some control over how she was feeling. Now here we are 14 months on and Mrs. B does participate in activities really well. It?s been noted that she enjoys helping the other residents with whatever task they are doing. She interacts well with meaningful activities, she likes to fold a little bit of washing. She enjoys doing the dishes and at times she does supervise the kitchen staff with the meals. We have noted a huge reduction in anti-psychotic medications. And in the 14 months that she has been with us we have reduced the safe guarding issues to 3. In the last 6 months, we haven?t had any good practice: an interim care plan is always put in place when a resident comes into a home. Interim care plan being that you take the initial assessment, from talking with family members, from staff that has previously cared for them. It?s important to allow 28 days for settling in, because it gives the resident a chance to orientate to their surroundings, get to know the staff,  and the staff to get to know them. It is then, and only then that you can put in place a person centred care plan. I have to say that the staff being trained in a person centred way allows them to see the bigger picture. The individual and not the condition. The staff are working with the residents and the family members on putting together life stories. We?ve found this measure so helpful in understanding the person. The residents enjoy their life stories and quite often will sit quietly looking through their life story and their photos. The life story doesn?t end when they come to the home, we do another part towards the end of the life story about my life now, incl. Any new activities I?ve taken up any new interests that they are looking forward to.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>5001</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Travel disruption in Tokyo due to an earthquake</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Travel[ProblemDescription]: Mr Takahashi had returned to Tokyo from South Korea. However a minor earthquake in Tokyo has disrupted the transport system, and is unable to use the normal train system to return to his home in the city from Narita airport. The airport trains to Tokyo are not running. The limited metro system is overloaded, and people are forming long, orderly queues even to get into the stations. There are very few taxis available. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Transport problems; unable to access transport; group travel; shared solutions [SolutionDescription]: Mr Takahashi used his organizational skills to locate a group of other travelers who need to reach the same part of the city. He used the combined buying power of this traveler group to locate and arrange travel. Mr Takahashi led the group to group-book a large taxi to a car hire company in a town near to Narita. From there he arranged for the group to rent a mini-bus sufficiently large to drive all of the travelers to their destination. An off-duty bus driver, found at the airport by Mr Takahashi, drove the mini-bus until the last traveler had been dropped off.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1040</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Homosexual relationships between residents</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A new male resident joined the residential home. After a time, the resident began a homosexual relationship with another male resident in the home. Both residents are sexually active. Although both residents are discrete about their relationship, some of the carers are uncomfortable. Reasons for this discomfort include religious beliefs and personal preferences. Some of the carers tried to keep the residents apart, which distressed the two residents, and led one of them to exhibit disruptive behaviour. This disruptive behaviour affects the comfort of other residents. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: homosexual relationships; sexually active; religious views; tolerance; openness [SolutionDescription]: The carers needed to be open and sympathetic to the relationship. They were requested not judge the appropriateness of each resident?s behaviour according to their own personal preferences or standards. For example, a carer?s own religious view may be that homosexuality is wrong, but we cannot let this personal viewpoint lead us into condemning a person's natural sexual preferences as inappropriate. The carers recognized that many older lesbian and gay people have had experiences of their closest relationships being ignored or even denied, so it is particularly important to be as open-minded and inclusive as possible. After the carers became more open and inclusive to the relationship, the behaviour of the residents became less disruptive.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1041</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Handling openly sexual behaviour in public</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A male resident who is sexually active has begun to exhibit sexual behaviour in public. Sometimes he exposes himself. Other times, he masturbates in front of other residents. On one occasion, he mistook a female resident for his wife. Although the behaviour is occasional, it is embarrassing and awkward for other residents, carers and visitors. Carers do not know when the resident will choose to masturbate, and this has caused them to keep him out of public areas during visiting hours. On one occasion the resident misunderstood the situation when a carer was helping him with intimate personal care, and believed that they are having a sexual encounter. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: masturbate; exposing oneself; sexual confusion; managing strategies; providing privacy [SolutionDescription]: The carers responded with sensitivity and empathy to the sexual behaviour of the resident, and respect his feelings and his dignity. It was important to give him privacy to masturbate. The carers had a key role to play in assisting someone with dementia to express their sexuality. They needed to compensate for difficulties that arose due to symptoms of the dementia. When he exposed himself or began to masturbate in the lounge of their care home, a carer discreetly advised him to go to his bedroom, and guide him there if necessary. When he mistook another member of their day centre for his spouse, carers gently reminded him who the person was and let them know when they will be seeing his wife. To avoid confusion over sexual encounters, the carer calmly explained the situation to the resident. Carers were reminded to be aware that this person may need frequent reminders during personal care of exactly what's happening.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1011</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Managing family requests</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: The decision to allow someone to walk around unsupported may have longer-term consequences if they suffer a fall. One relative talked about how she didn?t want her mother to get up and walk around unaided, not because she could fall, but because the fall might lead to the resident requiring a spell in hospital. This relative knew that her mother feared hospitals. A hospital stay would be highly distressing and disorientating and could ultimately lead to her further mental deterioration. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: n/A [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Family request; relative knowledge of resident; risk trade-off [SolutionDescription]: It is clear that risk needs to be explored in the wider context of the quality of life of a resident in a care home.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1013</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Poor resident health</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr. S had been living at home with his only son. 2010 he came to the home with a diagnosis of lung cancer. The symptoms included a huge decrease in weight due to not eating and drinking. He has been with us for 12 months and has put on over 1 stone in weight. He eats and drinks well at the dining room table with the other gentlemen. He`s still a smoker and smokes regularly. He is supported by this by the carers when he requests a cigarette he is given one and the staff will light it for him, and he sits quite happily outside in the smoking area in the home and enjoys all the visitors coming and going. He sits at the front door in his wheel chair. He says that this allows him to greet people as they come into the home. He is on oxygen supply that helps us to monitor his health, as it gives him some control over his care. His son visits regularly and sits outside with him to have morning tea or a cigarette. He interacts very well with the other residents. The lady residents love him. In the afternoon he likes to go to bed to rest and to watch his football with peace and quiet. And then he`ll get up again in the afternoon and attend the evening meal. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: unwell [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Resident health; smoking outside; adapted daily routine [SolutionDescription]: n/A</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1015</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident personal interests</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: We have a gentleman who is only just 65 who have come to the home with vascular dementia, he walks with crutches, he?s had a very messy personal background, quite in-depth. He is on anti-depression medication at the moment. On speaking with him and his family, he enjoyed breeding birds and fishing and enjoyed gardening and considered himself to be a bit of a designer or an architect. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: unwell [TreatmentType]: isolation [DateOfIncident]: Fri January 30 23:52:37 BST 2011 [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Complex personal background; settling-in period; support personal interests; life history added to [SolutionDescription]: After speaking with him we have provided him with a sketchpad and the utensils he needs to help devise a garden. The building team for the organisation are going to build an aviary with which Mr. X will assist. And he?s going to design the summer garden. It just so happens that this aviary is outside his room in the courtyard. He?s so excited about the plans for this. And he?s drawn up many plans and has many ideas about the garden. He?s turned to his daughter, who works with plants, and she is assisting in deciding which plants we should put into the garden once the aviary is completed. Mr. X is now coming to me saying that perhaps he could start a little business where he could on-sell his birds and raise a little money for resident activities. An interim care plan is always put in place when a resident comes into a home. Interim care plan being that you take the initial assessment, from talking with family members, from staff that has previously cared for them. It?s important to allow 28 days for settling in, because it gives the resident a chance to orientate to their surroundings, get to know the staff,  and the staff to get to know them. It is then, and only then that you can put in place a person centred care plan. I have to say that the staff being trained in a person centred way allows them to see the bigger picture. The individual and not the condition. The staff are working with the residents and the family members on putting together life stories. We?ve found this measure so helpful in understanding the person. The residents enjoy their life stories and quite often will sit quietly looking through their life story and their photos. The life story doesn?t end when they come to the home, we do another part towards the end of the life story about my life now, incl. Any new activities I?ve taken up any new interests that they are looking forward to.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4001</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Managing an Applicant`s Difficult Parent</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A parent of an applicant to a university undergraduate degree course was convinced that the applicant`s current school was withholding their child`s results. The parent believed that the results were being withheld for personal reasons. Therefore the parent rang the university continuously to complain. She told staff at the university that school`s failure to disclose results was the fault of the university. The applicant was embarrassed by their parent`s involvement in the process. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Withholding information; privacy; mediation; trust; student-relative conversations [SolutionDescription]: The university staff member decided to play a long game to resolve the situation. She adopted a strategy to befriend all of the participants involved in it. During communications with the parent she pretended to be on the parent`s side in order to gain the parent`s trust and to manage the interactions with her. At the same time the staff member tried to communicate with the school, highlighting the problems that the parent was causing for the university. As a consequence of mediating different conversations, the situation was resolved to the satisfaction of all participants.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4002</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Handling a Parent`s Complaint</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A parent of a school pupil complained to the Department of Education. The substance of the complaint was that the requirement to learn the Welsh language was violating the pupil`s human rights. The parent behaviour was aggressive towards the Department`s staff, which in turn alienated the staff towards her complaint. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Aggression towards staff; alienation; communication; permission; explaining procedures [SolutionDescription]: Staff at the Department recommended that she communicate directly with the staff at the pupil`s school to resolve the situation. She was also recommended to communicate directly with her member of parliament. The staff explained to the parent both the current legislative situation and the processes to follow to communicate to school staff and the member of parliament. The staff also made the effort to explain to the parent the advantages to the child of learning another language. In order to resolve the situation the parent was allowed to complain, a process supported by the Department staff.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4003</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Supporting a Depressed Student</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An undergraduate student becomes depressed during the second year and attempted suicide. The university staff were initially uncertain how to handle this situation. The course director was not able to deal with the situation emotionally or strategically. There were concerns about how the student in question would interact with other students on the course. The course director also refused to speak to the parent due to the need to protect the privacy of the student. The student herself was not prepared to initiate the involvement of the parent. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Emotions; depression; managed conversation; individual support; counselling [SolutionDescription]: The situation was resolved by inviting the student to attend the university with one of her parents. The university managed to facilitate a conversation between the student and the parent. This conversation revealed that the underlying problem was an absence of love towards the student during time at university. As a result of the facilitated conversation, the problem was resolved quickly. Support for the student was put in place. The university decided to support regular meetings with the course director to monitor the student, and access to counselling services. Staff tried to give a staff friend to the student to be able to talk to. In addition, staff tried to make important information accessible to the student at all times.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4004</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Supporting a Homeless Student</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: Security staff reported that an undergraduate student had attacked one of their staff. The student had been living in the 24-hour computing labs. A security staff member on a night-time patrol had encountered the student and challenged him. The university staff were very surprised that the named student would have attacked someone. Whilst attempting to flee, the student had accidently stood on the toes of the security staff, which had triggered the report. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Homelessness; family feuds; mediation; understanding; student support [SolutionDescription]: University staff first located the student on campus. Staff tried to invite the student for an informal meeting with his personal tutor. Care was taken to not inflame the situation. The meeting revealed that the student was homeless. He had left home because he was doing badly in his studies. He left home without reporting his exam results to his strict parents. The problem was resolved by inviting the parents into the university to have a mediated conversation with the personal tutor. The personal tutor asked the parents to not put pressure on the student. He explained that the university would try to put in place mechanisms to help the student. The outcome was improved results that a return to home for the student.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4005</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Mediating between Academic Staff and Students</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student on a field trip to a foreign city missed the return flight home, and was forced to travel back on their own. The student had missed the flight back because was engaged in nocturnal activities in a local brothel, and did not notice the time. The academic in charge of the trip held strong conservative views, and objected to the student`s behaviour. The outcome was a major conflict between the academic and the student that led to physical threats only resolved by keeping the two people in different rooms. As a consequence the university considered abandoning future field trips. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Personal conflicts; power relationships; chaperone; monitored meetings; mediation [SolutionDescription]: The university managed to resolve the situation by providing a chaperone for all meetings between the student and staff member over the subsequent months. The chaperone ensured that the academic and the student were not allowed in the same room together alone. The chaperone also acted as a mediator for communication between the student and staff member.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4006</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The Student Giving Back the Masters Degree</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A postgraduate student who had been awarded their postgraduate degree contacted the university and asked to return their degree. The university replied that this was not possible. Next the student informed the university that he had cheated by committing academic misconduct in his dissertation work. The university double-checked the dissertation for plagiarism, and was unable to detect any misconduct. The student then reported that he had someone else undertake the dissertation work on his behalf.The student explained that he achieving the Masters had given him a superiority complex that was then inhibiting him from obtaining a job. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Guilt; lack of confidence; explanation; self-confidence [SolutionDescription]: The university staff managed to resolve the situation through a lengthy conversation with the student. The staff member tried to respond to each accusation by the student in turn. Eventually the staff member told the student that there was no evidence of this, and that the matter was closed. The student responded that the conversation had allowed the student to offload any guilt that he had about the post-graduate reward. The student was now happy and received the degree. This demonstrates that attempting to talk to the student is sufficient to resolve the situation before it becomes more serious.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4007</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Pairing Students to Manage their Personalities</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was regularly angry in her interactions with the university. She would treat each interaction in simple, black-and-white terms, which would leave her dissatisfied much of the time. The student was diagnosed with borderline personality disorder. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Personality problems; people buddies; individual characteristics [SolutionDescription]: The university staff managed to resolve this situation by providing another student as a buddy for the student. The other student was very shy. The result of the friendship was a change in the behaviour of both students. The student with borderline personality disorder became more calm, and the student who was shy became more confident and outward going. One reason for the success of this friendship was that the shy student was very effective at saying `no` to requests without saying `no` directly, and the other student accepted this way of working. At the end of the course both students were able to graduate from their degree courses.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4008</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Managing Future Student Expectations</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An applicant to the university had failed to achieved the required A-level grades to enter university, and was very disappointed. The staff managing the entrance process was managing the situation. The applicant, his father and his mother had all rang the university to seek a change of decision. The mother had shouted at the staff, blaming the university for wider social problems associated with youth unemployment. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Angry relatives; understanding; communication; explanation; exploring options [SolutionDescription]: The staff member managed to resolve the situation through continued dialogue with parents. First of all, she tried to allow the parents to vent their frustration so that she would not be interrupted later on. She then explained that the applicant still had many future career options open to him. The options included re-sitting the A-levels, and applying to other universities.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4009</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Helping the Self-Harming Student</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was self-harming in front of the staff because the university was unable to provide assessment marks to her on demand. She was kicking furniture and banging her head against the office wall. The student said that she needed to have the assessment outcomes to obtain a visa for travel purposes. At first the university staff were uncertain how to manage this situation. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Personal stress; physical violence; exceptional circumstances; additional support; demonstrating care [SolutionDescription]: The staff member managed to contain the immediate situation by first leading the student into a private office out of sight and sound of other students. The university staff then tried to seek a means of meeting the student`s request due to the exceptional circumstances. The university staff did this by locating a member of academic staff with the necessary authority to compute and release the assessment marks. The student was provided with what she needed so desperately within one hour of the situation developing. This shortcut served to calm the student considerably.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4010</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Support for a Sexually-Abused Student</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student new to the university had attended a social event to the university on a Friday night. On Monday morning the student came to the Department to allege that a sexual assault had taken place on her. She was desperately seeking advice from the university. She had not informed the police beforehand, although some of her friends were concerned that she should. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Sexual assault; police involvement; making a complaint; building trust; prosecution [SolutionDescription]: A member of the Department`s staff managed to provide the student with a private space to discuss what had happened. He recorded the complaint on her behalf. He managed to use the complaint to speak to the Student`s Union and to counselling. The Student`s Union tried to locate the incident and the accused student using its CCTV system. As a result of this information, the student was expelled from the university. Furthermore the information was provided to the police who undertook a prosecution. All of these outcomes were possible because the Department staff led the student through the difficult and challenging process in a trusting way.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1016</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Uncooperative</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Annie Able, a new resident has been refusing to be washed, dressed or assisted any way.  She is verbally abusive to staff when approached.   Carers feel reluctant to approach her for fear of being abused.  Staff members become upset and feel like they want to reply to her comments, and leave her without assisting her. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbal abuse; avoiding; change of environment; reassurance [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Able has been at the home less than a month. She is also suffering from dementia.  It is difficult for her to adjust to a new environment and new people.  Annie has been independent, and has lived alone, since her husband died nearly 30 years ago. Her only child, Angela, lives abroad with her family and rarely visits. She is not used to people being in her home.  She feels anxious and expresses herself in this way.  Also she is in an unfamiliar environment and at times cannot understand why.  She can`t help it, and carers need to give her reassurance and understanding. When residents abuse you, do not take it personally. The incident has been documented, and has been discussed with all staff at handover.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1017</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Lashes out</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs. Bea Bridge, a resident who has been with us for some time, resisted when going to lunch with Nina.  Nina, a new carer, tried to help her up, but when she did, Bea slapped her across the face, and said `No, No.`.  Another carer called for a nurse who promptly arrived.  Other similar incidents have been documented in Mrs Bridge`s notes. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Physical abuse; resistance; greater explanation; patience; doubling-up care [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Bridge suffers from dementia and at times she is can be very confused. They tried to take her back to her room and ask her what was wrong.  It seems that the carer forgot to explain in more detail what she was doing so that Mrs Bridge understands that the carer had come to escort her to lunch, and not feel frightened and unsure of what is happening around her.  Carers acted well when they tried to find someone senior to assist them. They left her for some time and approached her again later on when she was less agitated.  A good suggestion for now might be to have two carers always present when caring for Mrs Jones as she appears to be volatile at times.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1018</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Racism</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Crawford has been resident at the home for just over one year. He is verbally abusive to staff on a regular basis, particularly to black members of staff.  He makes comments at all times of the day and comments are not restricted to certain aspects of his care.  Mr Crawford does apologise to staff after each incident if confronted. He has not been diagnosed with dementia and has been deemed to have mental capacity.  On direct questioning Mr Crawford is unable to explain his behaviour.  Many staff particularly those with darker skin do not want to go into his room as his comments are very offensive. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Racist verbal abuse; mental capacity; avoidance; cognitive impairment; ignore verbal comments [SolutionDescription]: Where possible, ask carers to care for him who are less likely to be subject to such comments However, this is not always possible.  When Mr Crawford makes offensive comments staff leave the room, senior nurses are consulted and then after some time someone will return to his room to speak to him.  Nursing staff are concerned he may have some degree of cognitive impairment which may be responsible for the behaviour. Care staff make sure to always document the patient`s behaviour in his care plan. His family and the doctor have been consulted regarding this matter.  His wife has done her best to talk to her husband.   She tries to understand why he makes such comments to the staff.  Staff are doing their best not to respond to the comments made to him, not to `take it personally`, but if they feel upset, to leave the room.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1019</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Grabbing</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Dean is a lady who is fully mobile.  She is a pleasant lady and has been at the nursing home for some time.  She walks around the ground floor of the home all day and makes a low pitched moaning noise, when a person walks past her she physically grabs their arm and won`t let go.  This is difficult for staff as they are often busy with daily duties and cannot stop so frequently. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Grabbing continuously; fear; anxiety; anti-psychotic drugs; companions; friendship [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Dean is a lady who has been at the home for a few years now.  She suffers from dementia and paranoia.  Her dementia has gradually become worse.  The doctor and family have been consulted regarding her behaviour.   Her constant need for attention is because of  her paranoia. Mrs Dean is afraid that she will die, and that she will be alone.  She is afraid and feels alone.  The doctor is reluctant to prescribe anti-psychotic drugs for her as she is already in a fragile state of health. Staff members do their best to take Mrs Dean to an area of the home where there are other residents / people.  She often sits near the reception desk where she can be near administrative staff and carers.  It is however at times difficult to give her the attention she needs.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1020</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Screaming</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Eccles was admitted to the nursing home 4 months ago.  She is unable to mobilize and requires full nursing care.  She screams all day from when she wakes until she sleeps.  Other residents in neighbouring rooms find the noise disturbing and have made complaints about the situation.  It also makes work more challenging for carers as they try whatever they can to calm Mrs Eccles. She is made as comfortable as possible, has started to eat her meals where she did not when she first arrived here and is toileted regularly.  She also receives regular medication including pain killers. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Screaming; noise disturbance; new environment; anxiety; communication; explanation [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Eccles is a lady who has moved to a strange environment with new people. She will feel distressed, afraid and anxious.  Staff try to note the days where she seems to be especially distressed or days where she is quiet.  In thinking about the reasons behind her behaviour the importance of communication is emphasised.  Carers sit and explain things calmly to Mrs Eccles and try to get to know her a little better so she feels more at home here.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1021</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Swears and Kicks</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Forrest is a new resident, and often has fits of swearing and shouting in her room, and when staff approach she can kick and pull the hair of the staff members. Staff are afraid to approach her as she is unpredictable. She has not made any relationships with other residents or carers, and is disruptive with others. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Shouting; physical abuse; alone; calming massage; toy doll; mirroring technique [SolutionDescription]: Ask her what is troubling her. Reassure her.  She may respond to gentle massage to calm her down. What has also worked for a while is to divert her attention. Mrs Forest particularly liked to hold a small doll, `Billy`, and may respond to choosing clothes for dressing up. If distraction doesn`t work, then a `mirroring` technique may work, where the carer `mirrors` the behaviour, even more pronounced, until they are in control, then brings down the behaviour and the volume, guiding the resident to become calmer,  and gradually stop. This technique would not work in later stage dementia.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1022</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Likes the Uniforms</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Graham often shouts at staff when they go into his room, telling them to get out. As he`s quite deaf, he doesn`t respond to explanations, and won`t stop shouting until they leave. Staff are upset and intimidated, and don`t want to see him as their knocks are often not heard. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Shouting; deaf resident; intimidation; changed uniforms; military background; staff names [SolutionDescription]: Mr Graham, a resident of nearly a year has been confused by the recent change of uniform policy.  Mr Graham was in the Army for some years and is comfortable with uniforms and it helps him to understand your authority when you go into his room.  It is possible to use a number of old uniforms that have been retained in the staff room for the care of Mr Graham. Mr Graham is not the only one to be confused. Although he won`t remember , try to get him to look for the staff badge and to use names.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1023</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Dislikes the Uniforms</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Halford, a resident of some 2 months will become very agitated at certain times, and try to hide.  The sight of an ambulance crews seemed to set this off for the first time, but it`s happened occasionally at other times.  Following a stroke, mobility and speech has become very difficult for Mr Halford, and he`s finding it difficult to express himself.  Medical assessments and treatments are particularly difficult and he seems to have taken a dislike to Dr Peters` nurse, who is often resisted when trying to treat him. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Fear of uniforms; medical uniforms; speech impediment; prisoner; remove uniforms [SolutionDescription]: Mr Halford will be expressing frustration at his inability to express himself, and staff should take time and show patience with him. However, it seems that Mr Halford spent some time in a foreign prison in his younger days and reacts badly to uniforms of any kind. It is recommended to remove or cover the uniform before approaching Mr Graham.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1024</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Bedtime tantrums</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Ivy, a recent dementia sufferer and recent resident has been disturbing other residents in the early evening in the lounge by shouting that she wants to go to bed first. Otherwise cooperative, Mrs Ivy insists on being the first to go to bed. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Early bedtime; tantrums; habits of a lifetime; plan for individual habits [SolutionDescription]: Mrs Ivy has always lived by a strict policy of going to bed early and waking up early, and insists that she has many important things for tomorrow.  She does not respond to reason or the needs of others, but when a carer makes sure to take her to bed first, then she stops shouting.  In this case it is easy to readjust bedtime planning in order to take into account the special needs of residents, providing it can be done without other disruptions.  It is important to Mrs Ivy to get to bed early and if possible, this wish should be granted whenever possible, and be noted in her care plans.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1025</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Refuses Medication</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Since the introduction of the `no-uniforms` policy, Mr Jones, will often be uncooperative with staff, and in particular, to refuse to take his medication on the rounds, challenging the carer. `Who are you to tell me to take these tablets?` However, he does need to take this medication, and the arguments are distressing to others around, often setting off others who overhear, and sometimes he is left without the medication been given. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: No-uniforms policy; uncooperative; recognisable authority; engage a medic [SolutionDescription]: In this case, another carer needs to put on a doctor`s uniform on, and dispensed the medication. Faced with this recognisable `authority` the resident has been taking his prescribed tablets without objection. This strategy of subterfuge can work in other varieties.  In case the doctor`s coat is not available, what will also work is for the carer to appear to be on the phone to the doctor/consultant on the phone, overheard by and involving Mr Jones in the conversation about the importance of taking his medicine.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1026</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Occupational throwbacks: the Miner</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Kerris, a recent resident will often exhibit strange behaviour, and if interrupted can become very agitated. His behaviour begins when he crouches down to the floor and crawls along the floor, under his table.  This is deliberate, and should not be seen as falling down. He does not want help to get up.  After some time he stands up and takes all his clothes off, discarding them to one side. Despite encouragement, he will not be persuaded to  put them back on again, though he will wear another set of clothes. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Throwback to former life; unusual behaviours; split-reality dementia; repetitive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: In discussions with Mr Kerris`s  daughter on a visit, she mentioned that he was working as a miner all his life, and that it was likely that the crouching was him re-enacting being in a narrow seam. His other behaviour could similarly be explained - at the end of the shift he would stand, and take off all his clothes before his shower. He wouldn`t put back on his `dirty` clothes. This resident was in the `split reality` stage of dementia, and should be left to enact his routine undisturbed.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1027</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Wanting to go `home`</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Lloyd, a new resident keeps saying `I want to go home`, `I want to go home`.  It`s distressing and confusing for other residents, and gets him agitated.  The staff know he can`t go home. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Going home; feeling safe and secure; symbols of home [SolutionDescription]: It`s important to understand what Mr Lloyd is really saying? Though going home is no longer an option, we can understand what the word `home` means ? and that he is missing the safety and security of home. Carers can help to calm him down by being gentle and reassuring, in particular that he was safe and secure here. Often, if the literal request is not possible, then the symbolic needs can be addressed. It`s also worth noting that Mr Lloyd likes painting when he was younger and likes to look at paintings. He is very knowledgeable. It sometimes helps to distract him by looking at pictures of paintings with him and asking questions about them.  He has a book of them.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1028</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident v Resident conflict</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: The trouble started when one resident, Mrs Mirron called out that she was waiting for her mum to visit. Mrs Norris replied that that she wasn`t as her mother was dead, arguing that if Mrs Mirron was nearly 90, her mother would certainly be dead.  Mrs Mirron got very upset and started arguing, requiring care staff to separate them. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Inter-resident conflicts; residents in mixed groups; similar stages of dementia [SolutionDescription]: The trouble lay in having residents in mixed groups.  In this case, a resident with an advanced stage of dementia is living in her reality, but is flatly contradicted by a resident with most of her critical faculties working. To reduce these sorts of conflicts, it can help to keep groups of similar stage dementia sufferers together. Also ask what the resident is really saying ? `I miss being hugged, cuddled, or the touch of another loving person.` In this situation a hug may be very helpful.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1029</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Occupational throwbacks: the Prison Officer</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Order has been indulging in very strange behaviour. Although normally very orderly and tidy in his habits, he has started to make a complete tip of his room, emptying drawers over the floor, pulling the mattress off his bed, emptying the wardrobe. He will not be stopped or touched while doing this, and has even been violent when staff have tried to stop him. He won`t pick up the contents afterwards. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Throwback to former life; unusual behaviours; split-reality dementia; repetitive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: Discussing Mr Order`s life history with his wife, it transpires he used to be a prison guard for most of his working life. Room searches, looking for contraband, were the order of the day and the inmates` rooms were certainly never tidied up afterwards. It was important to try not to stop the resident`s  behaviour of searching rooms as the resident then became very aggressive and would punch hard. He would calm down when carers allowed him to leave the resident to complete his `search` he would calm down and be fine.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1030</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Collecting his Pension</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Potter, a resident of some 5 months has kept demanding to go to the Post Office to collect his pension. He asks what day it is most days, a number of times, and when he discovers it is Tuesday, he insists on going to the Post Office to collect his pension. When he can`t go, he becomes very agitated and worried. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Compulsive behaviour; unable to act; enabling a compulsive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: This issue distressed Mr Potter so much, it was agreed to create a `Post Office` in the Home, by decorating the outside of an administrative office and a counter inside to that Mr Potter could visit it on a Tuesday, and collect his `pension`.  He was content to go to this `Post Office`, where he would be given some money and return to his room happy. Carers can help to fulfil the fantasy wishes with little effort, but some imagination.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1031</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Collecting the Wanderers</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Queen is a recent resident. She is still fully mobile, and most of the time understands her situation, but is increasingly forgetful. She loves to be outside and is allowed to walk in the garden, but on occasion, walks around the grounds and finds an open entrance.  As she is new to the home, she doesn`t know the area, and will be confused. This does happen from time to time with other residents too. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Wandering residents; lost; creative false amenities; collect lost residents [SolutionDescription]: It is very difficult to stop the situation, while still allowing those who can and want to walk the grounds unaccompanied. It the situation of confused and wandering residents, their behaviour has shown some consistencies, and it was found that by siting a false `bus stop` and sign just outside the home, almost all residents who are prone to wander are found waiting patiently outside, at the bus stop.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1032</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Occupational Throwbacks: the Teacher</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Reddy, a resident of nearly a year now regularly regresses to her past when she was a teacher. She barks `sit down and shut up` to all and sundry.  Some residents don`t like this and start challenging her. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Throwback to former life; unusual behaviours; split-reality dementia; repetitive behaviour [SolutionDescription]: The carer can shut up and sit down, not challenging Mrs Reddy`s `authority`, and allowing her to play out her reality. However, if other residents resent being told what to do and do not follow the carer`s example, this could make matters worse.  Prevention is often better than cure in this situation, and it can help to keep apart residents suffering different stages of dementia.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1033</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Continuing Routines</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Smith wanted ?to walk to the sweetshop? every morning. Although he didn`t want to buy any sweets, it had been part of his morning routine to have a walk. It distressed him that he wasn`t allowed to do this when he came to live in the residential home.  This request of his did not go away, and he continued to ask to for a walk each morning after breakfast. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Continuing old habits; creating false amenities; enable old habits [SolutionDescription]: After some weeks, when it became clear that this was a continuing cause for distress for Mr Smith, the outside of an administrative office was decorated to look like sweetshop from the outside.  Mr Smith was now quite happy to go for a walk after breakfast to the sweetshop, and return much happier.  It helps to satisfy residents` wishes symbolically, although seemingly impossible.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1034</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Painful solutions</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mrs Tait, an uncooperative and uncommunicative resident, is often agitated and pinches staff, but does not respond when asked why.  All sorts of reasons have been tried - is she thirsty, hungry, has she got toothache, do her dentures fit, does she want the toilet, is she in pain, etc? She does not answer but continues to pinch the carer, and groan. For some time staff did not know why. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Pinching staff; undiagnosed reasons; allow pinching thinker clothes [SolutionDescription]: It was noticed that Mrs Tait, when asked if in pain, pinches much harder and groans more deeply.  Staff pursued this thread, and put on thick long sleeved clothes, and let her pinch as much as she liked. The thickness of the material allowed the carer to accept the pinching, and the resident eventually tires and also becomes much less agitated. Adapting to apparently unreasonable demand and needs can sometimes be done with minimum efforts, but may need to imagine alternative solutions.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1035</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Not taking it personally</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mr Unwin, a new resident, has not settled in and remains uncooperative. He is particularly abusive to the carers; calling them fat, ugly, picking on race, or whatever. Staff hate to work with him, and a number have refused. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Verbally abusing staff; ignore abuse; team approachs [SolutionDescription]: Most care staff do not take the abuse personally and just get on with the job instead. They rationalise that Mr Unwin does not really know what his is saying. His wife says that he was a gentle man and would be horrified if he could see himself. But he can`t.  The importance of carers holding up the mirror to themselves is vital. To understand that the resident `can`t help it`, and be strong enough to not take it personally, is something not all carers can accept. Often this acceptance can come from being a carer in a good team, where each member values each other, where it is likely engender the kind of self-confidence so that cruel remarks just bounce off.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1042</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Sexual behaviour obscuring other problems</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A female resident had become a widow. She began to exhibit sexual behaviour towards men in the care home. These men included residents, relatives of other residents and workmen on site. Most of this behaviour included holding hands, kissing and intimate cuddling. On one occasion she exposed herself to another resident. Although most men found the behaviour amusing, the behaviour did cause some discomfort for some visitors to the care home. Carers were uncertain how to control or reduce this undesirable behaviour. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: widow; overt sexual behaviour; underlying reasons; changing resident activities [SolutionDescription]: It is very important to identify the needs that the resident was communicating through apparently sexual behaviour. The carers were able to explore different underlying reasons for the behaviour. In particular the carers were able to explore whether the resident was expressing a need for closeness and comfort. They tried to investigate whether the resident was feeling bored or physically restless. They also tried to investigate whether the resident exposing herself indicated a need to go to the toilet or that she was too hot. As a consequence the carers managed to learn that the resident had become bored and restless since the loss of her husband. A tailored program of activities and exercise was implemented, and the resident?s overt sexual behaviour was reduced.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1043</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Consenting to an open sexual relationship</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A male resident and a female resident, both with dementia, began to start a sexual relationship. The relatives of the female resident raised specific concerns with the management of the care home. The relatives wanted to know whether the resident was able to give consent to the relationship. Carers were also concerned about the effect of the relationship on other residents. Sometimes the couple demonstrated some sexual behaviour towards each other in the day lounge. This distressed and confused some of the other residents. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: consent; sexual behaviour; couples; new relationship; understanding needs of residents [SolutionDescription]: The carers played a vital role to play in protecting the vulnerable female resident from abuse and exploitation. ?It was important to explain that a diagnosis of dementia alone did not automatically mean that she lacked the capacity to consent to sex. ?It was important to help a person make the right decisions. To do this, the carers were able to develop an awareness of the resident?s past sexual preferences and habits and reminded her of wishes she had communicated previously. The carers also managed to realize that consent to sex would often be communicated non-verbally rather than verbally. The carers understood that the resident had the capacity to consent to engage in a sexual relationship with another consenting adult. Therefore the carers were able to arrange for the privacy of the couple to be encouraged and respected.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1051</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Using wheelchair biking with residents</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: The managers of a care home were concerned about the lack of engagement of a group of older residents in the home. The use of traditional home-based activities was ineffective for this group of residents. These activities included reading, playing, and listening to music. Therefore the management were seeking new types of therapeutic activities. In particular the managers sought outdoor activities. They were looking for activities that enabled the residents to travel and receive more fresh air. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: lack of engagement; therapeutic activities; biking; duet bikes; group discussions of past experiences [SolutionDescription]: One successful activity was wheelchair biking. The activity offered a thrilling opportunity for the residents. It combined a small group psychosocial component with individual rides of a duet bike. The managers raised the funds to purchase one duet bike. The residents in the group discuss past experiences with biking. The residents report back on their new ride experiences. Although the rides were short, the managers and carers observed important effects. The rides appeared to alleviate depression and engage residents more.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1044</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Using music to engage with unresponsive residents</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: An older male resident with dementia did not respond to external stimuli from his carers or relatives. Each day he would sit in a chair in the day lounge, seemingly asleep. He would not talk to carer or other residents. He did not undertake individual activities. He did not participate in the group activities. This lack of engagement caused problems. The carers struggled to ensure that he would eat and take his medication. The carers were uncertain how to engage with the resident. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: unresponsive resident; listen to music; selecting relevant music; understanding the resident?s past [SolutionDescription]: After a discussion with a relative, one enterprising carer was able to provide the resident with music from his youth. The carer made sure to select music popular in the period and location of the resident when he was in his 20s. The music was intended to trigger memories and emotions. The carer uploaded the music into a MP3. She then placed a set of headphones on the head of the resident, and played the music. The resident?s response was dramatic. His face was expressive and full of joy. He moved to the rhythm of the music. He engaged with other people around him in full conversation. He was no longer an unresponsive resident.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1045</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Creating meaningful activities for residents with Alzheimer`s</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: An older male resident with Alzheimer?s has recently moved to a new residential home. Although formerly an active man, he is not integrating well. He does not undertake many activities during a day. Rather he sits in the day lounge for long periods looking out of the window. He becomes increasingly agitated, and is showing the first signs of depression. According to his relatives, he was keen at woodwork and other outdoor hobbies. A discussion with carers revealed that continuing such hobbies imposes a health risk to both the resident and carers. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: boredom; hobbies; safe spaces; error-free encouragement; woodwork [SolutionDescription]: The carers decided to offer a simplified version of his hobbies in the care home. The management decided to convert an unused shed into a safe place for the resident to practice his hobbies. They managed to create some simple woodwork games based on his interests. The carers created a set of simple woodwork activities. Each of the available activities was error-free, to encourage a sense of success. Carers with the resident gave both visual and verbal instructions, and even guided his arms gently when needed. As a result the resident was able to engage more generally with other residents, and became less agitated over time.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1046</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Finding activities that keep residents engaged</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A female resident had recently arrived in a new care home. She had moved from another residential home, and arrived with a well-documented life history that described many of the pastimes that she had participated in during her life. The carers in the new home used these pastimes to design new activities for her to undertake. However, these activities were unsuccessful. The resident showed little interest in them. She became agitated if the carers persisted in offering these pastimes. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: pastimes; daily routines; repeat activities; varied content [SolutionDescription]: The carers explored a range of new activities to see which activities best engaged the resident. They were not afraid to try something new. They made sure to note the pastimes that the resident enjoyed. Although the resident did not always remember the pastime the next time, she appeared to repeat them instinctively. During familiar pastimes, such as sorting objects, the carers tried to keep the procedures the same, but varied the content from day to day to keep it fresh for the resident. They managed to establish a routine that repeated favourite pastimes.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1047</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Take a resident gardening with you</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A female resident with dementia is disrupting the routines of the care home. Although the effect of the dementia is increasing, she remains physically fit and active. The carers have sought to engage in a range of activities, such as games and cooking, but the lady refuses to participate in them. She sometimes acts aggressively towards carers who encourage her to undertake some activities. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: aggression; non-engagement; repetitive tasks; gardening; multiple senses [SolutionDescription]: From talking to the lady`s relatives, the carers learned that she was a keen gardener. Therefore the manager of care home decided to pair the resident with a carer who was also a keen gardener. The carer tries to take the resident gardening together regularly in a small plot of the home`s estate. The carer tries to encourage a range of repetitive tasks such as weeding, planting and smelling. The garden contains herbs and other non-toxic plants that arose multiple senses, in particular smell and colour. The regular gardening activity has reduced the level of aggression shown by the resident.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1048</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Use external stimuli to engage a resident</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident with dementia was failing to interact with his carers or relatives. He did not undertake individual activities or participate in the group activities. He would resist efforts to get out of the bed in the morning, and prefer to remain in his room asleep. This lack of interaction made it difficult to care for him alongside the other residents. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: lack of engagement; effective stimuli; one-to-one social interaction; visitor with baby; visitor with dog [SolutionDescription]: The carers tried to experiment with different stimuli to engage with the resident. The most successful activities were activities involving live social interaction. One successful form of live social interaction appeared to involve a one-to-one conversation with a carer or visitor. Another successful form of social interaction was with a visitor with a dog. The carers felt the importance to arrange social interaction with a visitor with a real baby because the resident also responded well to such interactions. In contrast, simulated social interactions such as with videos or a life-like baby doll well less effective.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1049</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Involving a resident in work in the residential home</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A female resident does not respond to traditional forms of interaction with carers. During scheduled activities in the day lounge and the dining room during the day, she sits quietly and resists encouragement to participate. However, the resident is physically active, and able to move on her own. Carers have noticed that she tends to follow them around the home during the morning shift, observing their work such as cleaning, sorting and folding bed sheets. The carers are uncertain whether to engage with her during these work activities. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: lack of engagement; work-like activities; folding towels; sorting socks; occupation [SolutionDescription]: The carers, after discussion with a relative, agreed to let her participate with a carer in some work-like activities such as folding towels and sorting socks. During these activities the resident became more engaged in conversation with the carer. Moreover, these engagements would last longer than most types of engagement. The carers were able to participate in these activities easily. The carers reflected that the work-like activities combatted feelings that the resident was unoccupied, isolated or bored. The carers and relative agreed to continue work-like activities. However, they also agreed to review the ethics of participation in such work-like activities.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1050</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Using animals to counter the effect of apathy</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is demonstrated an increased level of apathy. She appears less motivated than before to participate in activities that she participated in previously. One consequence is that the resident requires more management and support from carers. The carers need to schedule their activities around this resident. The carers, during some therapy sessions, experimented with different types of recreational activities to re-motivate the resident. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: apathy; animal-assisted therapy; pet dog; feeding; brushing [SolutionDescription]: One successful activity with this resident was to introduce an animal to engage the resident to reduce the apathy. The carers tried to encourage the resident to undertake different activities with the dog. The carers also tried to encourage the resident to play with the dog and to feed and brush the dog. She talked to the dog and its handler, and reminisced about her past pets. As a result of these regular activities, the resident became more engaged in other kinds of activities.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1052</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident asks for someone who has died or is not present</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is distressed and tells care staff that she wants to see her mother, who is no longer alive. The resident appears anxious and repeatedly asks care staff and other residents when her mother is going to come home. The resident refuses to participate in any activity that the care staff propose, until she is allowed to see her mother. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: different reality, relative, family, not present, illusion, away, belief, affection, comfort, feelings, mother [SolutionDescription]: A person with dementia sometimes experiences a different reality. Insisting on the truth that resident`s mother is dead can cause unnecessary distress. Lying that she will come would not help either, because she will feel even more distressed when she does not come. Instead, carer responded sensitively to the resident`s feelings and tried to discover why the resident needs to see her mother. The carer tried to investigate further as this behaviour often indicates a need for closeness, acceptance, comfort, affection or something specific that the relative used to do. Carer focused on trying to reassure, rather then trying to distract the resident. It was important to refer to the Care Plan for additional information on the individual resident in order to make sure understanding is complete and make a note of the event.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1053</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident believes he is still working or having young children</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Resident repeatedly wakes up at the same time in the morning and wants to leave the care home premises. Care staff have trouble persuading him to go back to his room. Afterwards, the resident continues to be distressed and repeats that he has been late for work. He refuses to participate in any leisure activities and says he has no time to lose on entertainment because important tasks await him. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: different reality, illusion, belief, work, purpose, value, feelings, job [SolutionDescription]: Insisting on the truth that resident is no longer employed can cause unnecessary distress. Lying that he will be going to the office next morning would not help either, because he will feel even more distressed when he cannot go. Instead, carers responded sensitively to the resident`s feelings and tried to discover why is he in need to go to work. A person`s belief that they still work or have young children often indicates a need for being involved in an activity that has value or purpose, or the need to feel needed. Carers tried to reassure the resident by suggesting activities that would address those needs, rather than providing distractions and entertainment. Carers also tried to refer to the Care Plan for additional information on the individual resident in order to make sure understanding is complete, and make a note of the event.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1054</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident is hallucinating</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is very distressed and is scared without an obvious reason. She says that she can see insects on her bed although none are there. Therefore, she refuses to go to sleep. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: illusion, different reality, not present, belief, fear, feelings, hallucination [SolutionDescription]: A person with dementia sometimes experiences a different reality. Her feelings are important and must be taken seriously. The carer managed to respond sensitively to the resident`s feelings. The carer tried to discover why the resident is seeing imaginary insects. The carer eventually managed to identify the underlying problem. Because the resident`s bedcover had a flowery pattern it seems that the resident was mistaken the flowers for insects. Therefore, the carer arranged to replace the bedcover. This was enough to calm the resident. The carer tried to refer to the Care Plan for additional information on the individual resident in order to make sure understanding is complete and make a note of the event.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1055</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident hears something that is not there</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A resident is very distressed and refuses to stay in her room. She says that she is very afraid of dogs, and asks care staff to get rid of the dog that she thinks is in the room. There are no dogs in the care home facilities. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: illusion, different reality, not present, belief, fear, feelings, hallucination [SolutionDescription]: A person with dementia sometimes experiences a different reality. Her feelings are important and must be taken seriously. The carer managed to respond sensitively to the resident`s feelings.  The carer tried to discover why the resident is hearing imaginary dogs. The carer eventually managed to identify the underlying problem. The person in the adjacent room was coughing and the resident thought it was a dog barking. The carer tried to refer to the Care Plan for additional information on the individual resident in order to make sure understanding is complete and make a note of the event.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1056</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Resident is aggressive due to misunderstanding</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A new resident is refusing to eat his lunch and throws food at carers and other resident at his table, while shouting and cursing. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: misunderstanding, aggression, feeling unheard, shouting, screaming, difficult, making choices [SolutionDescription]: Because of the way dementia affects the brain, the person may have lost some of the inhibitions that would have prevented them from showing their feelings in this way previously.  After kindly reassuring the resident, carers tried to investigate why the resident behaves in such a way. Care staff managed to discover that the resident is allergic to shrimps and was irritated and offended by the offer of shrimps at lunch. It was important to apologize to the resident, and provide him another meal.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1057</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Allowing personal space and independence</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: A new resident is being aggressive towards the carer when she is feeding her. She attacks carer with her hands when she is approached, accompanied by screaming and shouting. She says she wants to do it herself, but is physically unable to eat on her own due to her hands shaking. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: fear, threat, aggression, personal space, independence, difficult, attack, preserving independence [SolutionDescription]: Aggressive behaviour is by no means a common response from people with dementia. If aggression does occur, the most likely reason is that the person is reacting to a distressing situation. Care staff were able to realise that the resident was in need of more personal space. Due to her poor eye sight, the resident felt threatened by the nearness of her carer and attempts to being fed without previous explanation. The carer was able to respond sensitively to the resident`s feelings and explained to the resident who the carers are and why they are there. It was important to allow more personal space to the resident. Carer encouraged the resident to eat on her own, in order to preserve resident`s independence. When a resident is aggressive due to not being able to do things on their own, it is important to find things that the person can still do, and encourage exercising them.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1058</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Muriel`s Pacing up and down</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Muriel was always a nervous person.  And since she developed dementia and become a nursing home resident she has become withdrawn and is often seen pacing up and down. There didn`t seem to be anything which set off the behaviour. She will do this in the garden, or in her room or in the corridors. It might be day or night. She will ignore others who try to communicate with her. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: nervous person, withdrawn; pacing up and down; walking around [SolutionDescription]: Walking up and down isn`t necessarily harmful, to the person doing it, or to others. Many people without dementia will walk up and down when thinking.  Pacing is often done to relieve tension and frustrations. It may be possible to distract Muriel, but why try? Walking around can make it feel as if they are doing something, and can release pent up energy.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1059</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Spitting out food</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Jill was almost always polite and dignified in her quiet way, but developed an apparent habit of spitting out food at breakfast and the other meals in the dining room. Was it something about the dining room, or the other residents at the table? [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: habit of spitting out food; fixed times for meals; trouble with swallowing; eat quickly [SolutionDescription]: With fixed times for meals, even experienced staff were under time pressures to feed all the residents. Jill simply could not eat quickly and had trouble with swallowing, which can be common in sufferers of dementia.  Jill`s spitting the food out was her way of communicating that she couldn`t eat that quickly. This rarely happened in her room.  Jill wasn`t alone in behaving negatively at mealtimes, and now the fixed times have been relaxed, and Jill will often have meals in her room, where she can eat at her own pace. Staff have also been trained to respect the individual`s needs ? some will need more time than others to eat. Eating should be at the resident`s pace, not the carers.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1060</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Grabbing passing staff</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Jack has been in residential care for nearly two years, over which time his problems with speech and being able to verbalising his wishes correctly have been growing steadily worse. He is now causing problems in the Home because he has started grabbing members of staff when they are passing, causing surprise at best, and a danger to others when carrying things. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: speech problems; grabbing staff; frustration; inability to communicate; actively listening [SolutionDescription]: Jack often cannot say what he really means, and what he says is often interpreted wrongly in a casual interaction by a passing staff member - causing immense frustration in Jack. Jack`s frustration with his inability to communicate is showing itself by his grabbing behaviour ? literally grabbing their attention.  Jack needs the time to try to express himself, and someone prepared to spend their time watching and waiting, helping by reassuring him, and making an effort to understand ? actively listening to him.  When Jack feels himself understood he will perceptibly relax, and the grabbing activity stops.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1061</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Screamingly anti-social</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Edna lived for many years on her own, a widow, childless but with a circle of friends in her neighbourhood. Over the years most of her friends had died, and despite Edna`s known views about ``old people`s homes`` ? she didn`t want to end up in one -  that`s exactly where she ended up when dementia, coupled with mobility problems, made living on her own impractical. Despite an attractive dining room and lounge and a range of activities available, Edna screamed whenever she was taken into a room where there were other residents.  This was seen an initial teething problems at the outset, but didn`t improve. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Widow; screaming; anti-social; personalise room [SolutionDescription]: To Edna, and other sufferers of dementia who may be unaware of their own situation, seeing a group of people with dementia can be disturbing anyway, and Edna`s own fears of residential care were realised when she saw other residents in the lounge. It was important to increase the period of settling in.  Knowing this, staff made sure to make her room as personal and homely as possible, and encouraged Edna`s friends to visit whenever they could.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1062</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Taking off his clothes</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Tom liked the outdoors and would often be seen walking the garden on nice days.  Tom was never an exhibitionist, but often staff would come across Tom in the dining room or an activity room without most of his clothes, and sometimes without all of them. Mobile but unable to speak or communicate easily, he resisted his clothes being put back on, even pushing staff when they tried. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Enjoy walking outdoors; aggressive towards staff; become too hot; change of temperature [SolutionDescription]: The fact that Tom only took his clothes off in certain places ? not the garden or his room - indicated that the problem was around location. It simply was too warm in the dining room and activity room for Tom, where the poorly designed windows were always locked shut ? as a ``health and safety precaution``. If Tom stayed too long in those rooms he became too hot, and ?naturally` did something about it.  Staff were able to recognise that all residents don`t have the same reactions to the same environmental conditions. What is warm to one person is cold to another, and what is comfortable to one person is uncomfortable to the next. It is important to be able to respond to each individual`s needs ? in this case by being able to modify the temperature by opening a window.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1063</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Rejects intimate care</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Rebecca was single all her life, living with her cats and teaching music at the local girls grammar school. After her beloved tabby cat died, she became very forgetful, and started to neglect herself. Her relatives had stated on her entry to the home that her strong preference for intimate care was to be only performed by female staff, and was described by them  to be ``shy and timid`` - yet her resistance to intimate care was anything but timid, regularly putting up a fight. Staff tried to reassure her, the best they could.  They explained who they were and what they were doing, which helped at the start, but invariably she would start to fight at some point in the process. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Single; intimate care only by female staff; sexually abused; avoid casual contact [SolutionDescription]: Rebecca always had problems with intimate care, even when the most sensitive of help was offered after a family secret was discovered by accident. When talking to a visiting relative about the problem, it was disclosed that Rebecca had been sexually abused by her stepfather as a teenager. Since that time she had avoided casual contact with males and kept away from intimacy. Now, in her eyes, she couldn`t understand why ?strangers` removed her clothes, and the incident probably brought back the feelings of fear and disgust of her teenage years.  Knowing Rebecca`s background, carers were able to understand her reactions and be more sensitive to their own behaviour when with Rebecca.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1064</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Too Many Rules</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Following a diagnosis of dementia after a stroke and without relatives to care for him, Kevin was forced to move into a nursing home.  Kevin always had liked the outdoors, since being a child on a farm. He had found work with the Forestry Commission and spent most of his working life outdoors. In retirement he spent much of his time on his allotment. So it wasn`t surprising that he liked to start each day with a walk outside ? ``to understand the weather`` he would say. It mattered not to Kevin that it was raining, or cold, or foggy ? out he would go, sometimes dressed appropriately, sometimes not. He would head for the nearest exit each morning before his breakfast. Distraction did not always work, and when he was prevented from going out, he became agitated, then angry, and could lash out. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Outdoor life; walk outside; agitated and angry; avoid confrontation; keep routine [SolutionDescription]: No one went out before breakfast. But why not? If that`s what Kevin wanted to do, it did not cause harm to others, and even when he was inappropriately dressed, he seemed to be aware of that on his return.  There was no point in staff provoking a confrontation with Kevin ? such rules about going out before breakfast seemed not worth upholding. Indeed, when staff looked at the issue, Kevin`s routine didn`t seem so bizarre, and now they look out for him early in the morning and help him choose appropriate clothing and ask for a report on the weather on his return.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1065</SourceId>
        <SourceName>A need to read the Life History</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Harry was always getting upset, cross and angry with people ? usually new staff who hadn`t read Harry`s Life History in the Care Plan.  Suffering from dementia for some two years now, he was often found repeating the same question to anyone who went near him ? ``have you seen my wife?`` It seemed that ``No`` was the only safe answer, and that didn`t cheer him up as he went looking for someone else to ask.  An answer of ``yes`` was worse, provoking a range of angry words and gestures.  His wife, when she came in, couldn`t understand it. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Upset and angry; repeating same question; previous marriage; help by distraction [SolutionDescription]: Harry was actually referring to his first wife ? the one who had run away with another man! Harry`s reality was often to be found some 40 years before, when he was married to a war-bride. Unfortunately, according to his brother who was visiting, the marriage turned sour after the war finished, and she left him soon afterward. Harry never heard from her again, and it had played on his mind ever after, even after getting remarried.  Understanding the reference now, staff are more aware of the issues, and will try to help Harry move on, by distraction, and asking about his role in the War, which will usually get him talking about his days in the army.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1066</SourceId>
        <SourceName>A Lack of Love</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Nancy usually liked to sit alone, and seemed to ignore most approaches by other residents and by staff.  She didn`t object to being wheeled to the lounge to join in the various organised activities, but she didn`t seem to get any enjoyment from them.  Depression was considered, but proved negative. She seemed to be a loner, and so staff tended to leave Nancy alone, in a world of her own.  Is this challenging behaviour? In a sense, yes, as Nancy challenged the staff to help her live a dignified life, and yet she lived in effective isolation, with little human warmth. This was highlighted after she was discovered wet and uncomfortable, probably for a number of hours. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: alone, isolated; neglectful treatment; raise awareness of others [SolutionDescription]: For various reasons - lack of time, more demanding residents, a lack of response from Nancy, or a lack of staff understanding ? Nancy was unable to receive the warmth and affection that all humans need. Her neglectful treatment raised alarm bells and a case review tried a number of different approaches, with much more one to one contact. The one approach that made the most difference was to give her a doll to hold. That was accepted immediately, and was then shown to others proudly thereafter. This interaction enabled Nancy to get back into social situations and raised her awareness of others around.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>1067</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Armed and Dangerous</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Healthcare[ProblemDescription]: Mick was a recent resident in the care home, after his daughter could no longer cope with his realities and ``unpredictable behaviour``. He was ``a character`` and had spent much of his life working on ships and seeing the world ? which was a very different experience from the usual resident in his care home. One morning, Mick went into the kitchen and picked up a vegetable knife and walked towards a kitchen assistant ? who screamed. Mick became very agitated as other staff ran in to find out what was happening. He was clearly confused and bewildered. He dropped the knife, and was immediately grabbed and held, while the knife was taken away. Unable to communicate, Mick was likely to be moved into a psychiatric ward and treated as dangerous. Was this necessary? [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: working on ships; armed with knife; cook; knowledge of past life [SolutionDescription]: Mick spent much of his time on ships - as a cook. He was very much at home in a kitchen, and knives were part of his trade ? not as a dangerous weapon. He was ?going to work`.  Yet, the initial reaction, based on a misunderstanding, quickly exacerbated the situation, and led to a chain of events that was likely to hasten Mick`s decline, with powerful sedatives and/or physical restraint. So much of a person`s behaviour can be understood from a knowledge of their past life. And much will be misunderstood without that personal knowledge.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4011</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Managing a student who failed their project</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student had submitted his Masters project, and required his degree to be awarded by March to obtain a post-study work visa. Recent changes in UK Border Agency regulations limited the student`s ability to obtain a post-study work visa. However, the student`s project was suspected of academic misconduct and his award could not be made by March. He was found guilty of misconduct by a University panel, and subsequently failed the project. Very upset he attended the course office in tears to ask the Course Officer about what he should do. The Course Officer advised the student to speak to his supervisor and obtain support from the Student Centre. The Course Officer went through the appeals process and the grounds an appeal can be made on, while suggesting the student spoke to the International Office about their visa.  The student came back to the office on several occasions upset and needing support. The Course Officer reiterated where they could go and seek advice to ensure the student sought all the help they could. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: academic misconduct; appeal; visa; [SolutionDescription]: On appeal the student was given a three month referral period to complete their project. The Course Officer, now experienced in this student`s situation, decided to spend time with the student to ensure they knew exactly what they needed to do next. The Course Officer explained in great detail the new deadlines, fees, where advice should be sought on the work the student was required to do, and the likely outcome of the project re-submission. The student was pleased to note that the fail mark would not appear on their official transcript and went on to successfully complete the degree.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4012</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Managing a student who failed their project</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An overseas student had submitted his Masters project, and required his degree to be awarded by March to obtain a post-study work visa. Recent changes in UK Border Agency regulations limited the student`s ability to obtain a post-study work visa. However, the student`s project was suspected of academic misconduct and his award could not be made by March. He was found guilty of misconduct by a University panel, and subsequently failed the project. Very upset he attended the course office in tears to ask the Course Officer about what he should do. The Course Officer advised the student to speak to his supervisor and obtain support from the Student Centre. The Course Officer went through the appeals process and the grounds an appeal can be made on, while suggesting the student spoke to the International Office about their visa.  The student came back to the office on several occasions upset and needing support. The Course Officer reiterated where they could go and seek advice to ensure the student sought all the help they could. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: academic misconduct; appeal; visa; [SolutionDescription]: On appeal the student was given a three month referral period to complete their project. The Course Officer, now experienced in this student`s situation, decided to spend time with the student to ensure they knew exactly what they needed to do next. The Course Officer explained in great detail the new deadlines, fees, where advice should be sought on the work the student was required to do, and the likely outcome of the project re-submission. The student was pleased to note that the fail mark would not appear on their official transcript and went on to successfully complete the degree.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4013</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Student panicking before the deadline</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A hard working student, with first class marks to date, emailed the Course Officer to say he had decided to withdraw from the course without submitting his final project. He explained in his email that he felt that the work he had done was not good enough to pass and that he would not be able to gain his degree. The student did not want to discuss this with their supervisor as they felt intimidated by them. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: course withdrawal; intimidated; struggling with writing; [SolutionDescription]: The Course Officer calmly reassured the student that supervisors had a lot of experience in supporting students in project work and that they would have had many students who`d faced similar problems. The Course Officer was able to persuade the student to attend the University to discuss their situation in person and bring in the work they`d done to date. The student explained that they were in fact embarrassed to let the supervisor know that they were struggling with writing up their project, and that with only one month left they felt that they wouldn`t be able to complete on time. To resolve the issue the Course Officer was able to speak privately to the project tutor about the students concerns and show them what the student had done to date. The situation was resolved by passing the tutor`s positive comments to the student, who was then felt able to discuss this in person with the tutor.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4014</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Out of character behaviour in missing deadlines</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: The Course Officer has a lot of contact with her students and was normally made aware of students with extenuating circumstances either by tutors or by the students themselves. A student doing well on her undergraduate degree did not submit a piece of coursework for a module.  The Course Officer realised that this non-submission was unusual behaviour for this student and contacted the tutor to see if they were aware of this. The tutor was surprised and the Course Officer suggested that they would contact the student directly to ask what had happened. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: extenuating circumstances; non-submission of coursework; unique student circumstances; [SolutionDescription]: The student explained they were having significant family problems and the Course Officer identified that this was a case for extenuating circumstances. However, the student hadn`t submitted their claim as they believed that they had missed the deadline, and had accepted that the mark for the coursework would be zero. The Course Officer persuaded them to submit their claim by explaining what the panel could consider, that depending on the circumstances of the submission a number of options were available to them. In this case, the claim was accepted and the panel believed that it was sufficiently serious for the student to be given a module mark that equated to the exam mark in lieu of the coursework, and they therefore passed the module. The Course Officer resolved the issue through taking the extra time to consider the unique circumstances of this student.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4015</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Transition from school to university</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: An experienced Course Officer is aware that the transition from school to university can be challenging for some students, and in difficult scenarios they look for out of character behaviour. One student started with high coursework grades in semester one, but then it was noted that they were not submitting work or attending exams for every module. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: out of character behaviour; struggling with workload; learning success; [SolutionDescription]: The Course Officer contacted the student who explained that they found it challenging to take notes and work under University conditions that were different to school. They had struggled with the workload and were unsure how to organise their time or write certain types of assignment/reports. The Course Officer noted that student was overwhelmed with information at induction and first week of term and so that they miss the support on offer to them. The student was advised to go to student centre and access the learning success team who offer study skills, essay writing, and exam preparation. The Course Officer noted this concern and made sure that they reminded all students of where this support can be accessed, posting a message on Moodle, highlighting the new study support link in Moodle, and noting it in staff/student liaison meetings.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4016</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Technology malfunction causing non-submission</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A part-time student, while ill, tried to submit a coursework assignment from hospital. They contacted the module leader to inform them that they were unable to submit because Moodle was not working, they asked to submit their assignment via email. The module leader advised the student of the policy on submission and that it could not be accepted by email. A distressed student contacted the school office and was advised to submit an extenuating circumstances claim. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: illness; technology difficulties; assignment non-submission; [SolutionDescription]: However, the student continued to call to explain it was a Moodle fault, speaking to numerous staff members. The student then came to the office in person, distressed, he appeared intimidating to the staff with his level of frustration. His Course Officer sat him down and calmly explained the extenuating circumstances procedure and that they would need evidence that Moodle was not working. The Course Officer listened to the student and asked questions which led them to believe a further investigation would be necessary. The student was very experienced in the subject area of the assignment and did not appear to be making false claims. The Course Officer sought advice to investigate the IT/Moodle issue from the technical team, and was able to identify there had been a problem at the time the student was trying to submit their assignment. This issue was not obvious without the investigation by the technical team, but now identified the Course Officer was able to obtain permission to allow the student to submit the assignment again, and pass.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4017</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Student with an unknown disability</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student came to the office upset that they were having greater difficulty study and completing the written coursework compared to their peers. The coursework rubric and reading was causing them a lot of difficulty in comprehension. The Course Officer explained that the University offered a number of classes on study support, and that the learning success team in student services could help them diagnose the difficult they were having. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: disability services; student study support; diagnosis of difficulty; [SolutionDescription]: The Course Officer recognised the need to be empathetic and supportive to ensure the student was not made to feel uncomfortable. Also, the Course Officer was aware that the assessment by the student services takes time, so when the report came through it needed to be acted upon urgently. The student was diagnosed as dyslexic. Aware that the student had completed some module assessments already, the Course Officer urgently contacted the students tutor to ensure that student would have the support needed going forward, and that completed marking was now considered retrospectively. The student was informed and reassured that they did not lose out on marks.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4018</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Student queries their mark</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: Marks for a MCQ assessment were released, and a student awarded zero contacted the lecturer to complain. This was forwarded to the Course Officer to investigate what was going on. The Course Officer was able to identify through Moodle that the student had never attempted this test. The student still insisted that they had done the MCQs. The Course Officer asked for an investigation of students` usage of Moodle from the technical team. It was identified that the student had gone in and looked at the test, however the student had taken too long and was timed out (standard practice for this type of test), and they were then unable to access it again. The student was contacted and the situation explained, the Course Officer explained that the process of time limited MCQs was there to ensure the rigour of marking and the credibility of the assessment as part of the degree. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: technical difficulties; extension request denied; [SolutionDescription]: The student accepted this and admitted that they were well versed in doing MCQs in the past, but thought they may be able to get an extension if they said they thought they`d done it. It was upheld that the student was given a mark of zero.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4019</SourceId>
        <SourceName>A student bought code for their coursework</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was suspected of buying code for their coursework from a website rent-a-code. They were invited to the academic misconduct panel to explain their case. The student came to the office distressed and unsure what would happen to them. The Course Officer explained the plagiarism and academic misconduct policy to the student. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: buying coursework; admitting misconduct; [SolutionDescription]: The experienced Course Officer advised the student that it is better to always to be honest and explain what they`ve done, and this will go in their favour. The Course Officer explained that students will be caught out if they try to hide their behaviour, that it is in their interested to accept what they have done, and there are a range of options available to the misconduct panel including exclusion from the University. They were also advised to seek the support from student services. The student admitted that they had purchased the code from the website; they were allowed to repeat the year.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4020</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Student complaint over late coursework marks</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: The marks for a piece of coursework had not been released by the published date and a student attended the office to complain on behalf of their class. The Course Officer explained the policy on returning marked work as set out in the University policy. The unhappy student contacted the office every day following the missed deadline for returning the marks. The Course Officer ensured that they were consistent in the advice they gave to the student and identified when they would contact them and how. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: late publication of results; escalating complaints; formal feedback processes; [SolutionDescription]: The Course Officer explained how the complaint would be taken further, and the complaint was escalated to the Director of Undergraduate Studies. Ensuring the student was kept informed the Course Officer also spoke to the student representative(s) for the course in order for the information to be disseminated throughout the student body. The module leader was approached by the Director and the marked work was then returned to the students two weeks late, an apology was posted into Moodle. The Course Officer also made sure that they contacted the student who initiated the complaint directly to ensure that they had received their coursework mark. The issue was resolved and the student was further advised where formal feedback could be given about any issues with the module, advising them of the process of staff/student liaison, and the importance of this feedback.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>4021</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Accusation of plagiarism</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Education[ProblemDescription]: A student was accused of plagiarism after they had received their coursework mark on Moodle. The student was livid at the accusation and adamant that they had followed all the practices including referencing. They contacted the Course Officer and queried why they had been given a mark on Moodle and then retrospectively been accused of plagiarism. The Course Officer referred them to the disclaimer on submission and explained that the work had not been moderated when it was released, and that subsequent moderation had highlighted the accusation. The Course Officer calmly explained that the student would have to wait for the investigation to be conducted, informing them of the process that will be followed and how this links to the formal assessment board process. The student was reassured that all steps would be followed to allow them a fair hearing. [Observations]: n/A [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: investigation of plagiarism; poor practice; complaint upheld; [SolutionDescription]: The student was found guilty of poor practice and the grade for the assignment was revised to a fail mark. The student had left the country at the time and was very unhappy with the results phoning many of the Course Officer`s colleagues to complain. The Course Officers took the responsibility of contacting the student to inform them that they would be kept up to date on the progress of their complaint. The Course Officer, realising the student was distressed, decided it would be reassuring for them to have one key contact for their issue, and explained that that they would personally contact them. The Course Officer was able to speak personally with the student to inform them that further investigation by the module leader had now resulted in pass mark; the student was able to progress with their degree without further incident.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9001</SourceId>
        <SourceName>A Airway: Aperture delle vie aeree</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Vieni inviato dalla c.o. su un cod. R 02 K, al tuo arrivo chiami e scuoti il paziente, non ti risponde,  metti la persona in posizione supina e fai comunicare via radio dal tuo collega lo stato di  incoscienza. Tu devi procedere alla pervieta' delle vie aeree. [Observations]: Perdita di coscienza~Lingua scende verso il basso e ostruisce le vie respiratorie [ObservedBehaviour]: non applicabile [TreatmentType]: Svuotamento del cavo orale&gt;Aprire la bocca procedendo ad iperestendere il capo;Verificare che non vi siano corpi estranei;Rimuovere corpi estranei presenti con pinze;Aspirare eventuali secrezioni tramite l'aspiratore di secreti [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non asportare protesi dentarie, se stabili~Non spingere in basso il corpo estraneo presente [TriggeringEvent]: Aspiratore di secrezioni [Miscellaneous]: Iperestensione capo [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di ruotare delicatamente il capo di lato per favorire la fuoriuscita di secrezioni, rigurgito o vomito; Hai pensato di usare una garza per aiutarti a rimuovere secrezioni, rigurgito o vomito</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9007</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Crisi convulsiva</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Siete in sede e ad un tratto entra un ragazzo correndo. Vi dice di essere della scuola media di fianco alla vostra sede e vi riferisce che due minuti prima un suo compagno e' caduto a terra e ha cominciato a tremare. Avvisate la CO118 che vi assegna un codice G 04 P. Data la vicinanza, giungete a destinazione dopo un paio di minuti e vi trovate di fronte al ragazzo, a terra, in stato confusionale. Appaiono segni di incontinenza. Chiedete ai compagni cosa e' accaduto: ``Stavamo giocando in cortile e Luigi ha cominciato a tremare`` dice un compagno. ``Si, pero' prima e' diventato tutto rigido e poi e' caduto`` dice un altro. E un terzo: ``Abbiamo provato a chiamarlo ma non ci risponde``. A questo punto chiedete da quanto tempo e' successo e vi rispondono che saranno passati circa cinque minuti in tutto. [Observations]: Stress~Ipossia~Ipertermia~Ipoglicemia~Danni strutturali (tumori cerebrali, trauma cranici, disordini vascolari) [ObservedBehaviour]: Irrigidimento di tutto il corpo~Rilascio degli sfinteri che provoca incontinenza~Movimenti incontrollati e intensi~Cianosi delle labra e del volto~Stato confusionale [TreatmentType]: Evitare che contrazioni e movimenti incontrollati causino trauma~Adagiare la persona al suolo~Al termine delle convulsioni, posizionare la persona in una posizione da poterla monitorare~Facilitare il flusso di eventuali secrezioni~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi con una mascherina d'ossigeno [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non tentare di immobilizzare la persona~Non mettere nulla in bocca della persona [TriggeringEvent]: Mascherina d'ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di liberare lo spazio attorno alla persona in modo che non urti contro oggetti e non si ferisca; Hai pensato di controllare costantemente le funzioni vitali; Hai pensato di raccogliere quante piu' informazioni possibili da parte delle persone presenti; Hai pensato di fare in modo che i presenti non si fermino a guardare</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9013</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Emorragia esterna</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O.118 vi invia presso un ufficio con un codice G 01 P. Si tratta di un ragazzo che si e' ferito mentre staccava un quadro che gli e' scivolato di mano. 
Arrivati sul posto trovate il ragazzo ferito ad una mano e assistito al meglio da un collega. Dopo averne valutato le funzioni vitali ed aver constatato che non corre pericoli di vita procedete al primo soccorso con l'obbiettivo di arrestare l'emorragia. [Observations]: Lacerazione di arterie~Lacerazione di vene~Lacerazione di capillari [ObservedBehaviour]: Arterie - sanguinamento a zampilli ritmici~Venose - sanguinamento con flusso continuo~Capillari - scarsa fuoriuscita di sangue [TreatmentType]: Applicazione di un bendaggio compressivo sul moncone residuo~Applicazione di un laccio emostatico, SOLO in caso il solo tampone e' inefficace~Prestare pronto soccorso~Reperire la parte amputata~Pulire in modo minuzioso con soluzione salina sterile~Porre la parte imputata in una busta e sigillatela~Avvolgere la busta in un telino~Porre la busta in un contenitore termico con buste di ghiaccio secco [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non toccare la ferita con le dita~Non far alzare in piedi o a sedere il paziente~Non somministrare caffe' o te' [TriggeringEvent]: Bendaggio compressivo~Laccio emostatico, SOLO in caso necessario [Miscellaneous]: Emorragia esterna [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di usare bretelle, cinture, fazzoletti, spago, etc se non hai il laccio emostatico; Hai pensato di scrivere l'ora in cui hai applicato il laccio emostatico</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9002</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Amputazioni</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Venite inviati in un parco con un codice G 01 P. Un giardiniere, potando le piante del parco, si e' amputato un braccio con la motosega. La situazione e' drammatica ma vi avvicinate con calma e valutate la situazione. [Observations]: Amputazione di un arto superiore~Amputazione di un arto inferiore [ObservedBehaviour]: Dolore fortissimo [TreatmentType]: Applicazione di un bendaggio compressivo sul moncone residuo~Applicazione di un laccio emostatico, SOLO in caso il solo tampone e' inefficace ~Prestare pronto soccorso~Reperire la parte amputate~Pulire in modo minuzioso con soluzione salina sterile~Porre la parte imputata in una busta e sigillatela~Avvolgere la busta in un telino~Porre la busta in un contenitore termico con buste di ghiaccio secco [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non usare solo ghiaccio per la conservazione della parte imputata, per evitare il congelamento. Usare acqua con ghiaccio [TriggeringEvent]: Bendaggio compressivo~Laccio emostatico, SOLO in caso necessario [Miscellaneous]: Amputazione, braccio, arto [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9008</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Distorsioni e lussazioni</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Venite inviati con il mezzo di base presso la palestra comunale con un cod. V 01 Y.Al vostro arrivo notate un ragazzo a terra che riferisce di essere caduto durante un' azione di gioco e nel buttare a terra le mani per attutire la caduta, riferisce un forte dolore alla spalla destra con perdita di funzionalita' dovuta alla lussazione della spalla. Il ragazzo vi riferisce che gia' parecchie altre volte ha subito la lussazione della spalla ed e' in lista per un intervento. [Observations]: Distorsione: quando in un'articolazione il capo articolare  esce e rientra spontaneamente nella propria sede naturale~Lussazione: quando in un'articolazione il capo articolare  esce e non rientra spontaneamente [ObservedBehaviour]: Distorsione&gt;
la persona riferira' del dolore molto intenso patito durante l'evento. In seguito presentera':
gonfiore localizzato;
movimenti limitati ma possibili;
dolore al movimento~
Lussazione&gt;
Il capo articolare non ritorna nella propria sede naturale pertanto potrete rilevare deformita' dell'articolazione. Inoltre saranno presenti:
Dolore molto intense anche a riposo;
Impotenza funzionale;
tumefazione;
alterazione del normale profile anatomico [TreatmentType]: Distorsione&gt;
Rimuovere gli indumenti sovrastanti la sede della lesione;
Immobilizzare l'articolazione;
Applicare ghiaccio istantaneo~
Lussazione - Spalla&gt;
Immobilizzare la spalla nella posizione in cui si trova, sostenendo l'arto mediante un bendaggio a triangolo;
Riempire il cavo ascellare con materiale modellabile;
Non tentare mai la riduzione~
Lussazione - Anca&gt;
Posizionare e trasferire con cautela la persona su barella a cucchiao, bloccando la colonna lombare, il bacino e gli arti inferiori; 
Riempire gli spazi vuoti con material modellabile [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non muovere mai attivamente l'arto per vedere se il dolore si fa piu' intenso~Non tentare mai la riduzione della lussazione dell'anca [TriggeringEvent]: Bendaggio a triangolo~Barilla a cucchiaio [Miscellaneous]: distorsione, lussazione, spalla, anca [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9014</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Fratture</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O.118 vi invia sul luogo di un infortunio sul lavoro con un codice G 01L. Un uomo e' caduto mentre lavava un vetro e al momento e' assistito da colleghi.
Trovate un signore di circa 40 anni sdraiato a terra che lamenta un forte dolore al braccio. Vi dice di non riuscire a muoverlo e che quando i colleghi hanno tentato di aiutarlo il dolore si e' fatto piu' forte. I colleghi hanno seguito le istruzioni della C.O.118. [Observations]: Rotture di un osso [ObservedBehaviour]: Dolore~Sensazione di cedimento o di crack~Perdita del normale profilo anatomico~Impotenza funzionale~Mobilita' diversa dal normale~Tumefazione ed alterazione del colorito della cute~Alterazione della sensibilita': formicolio e intorpidimento [TreatmentType]: Rimuovere gli indumenti o monili sovrastanti la sede di frattura~Se frattura aperta: lavare con acqua fisiologica, proteggere con telino sterile, evitare l'uso di disinfettanti~Immobilizzare l'arto bloccando l'articolazione prossimale e distale, riempiendo gli spazi vuoti creatisi tra l'arto fratturato e lo strumento di contenzione~Valutare la presenza del polso periferico, radiale o pedideo, prima e dopo aver mosso od immobilizzato l'arto~In assenza di polso periferico controllare l'immobilizzazione [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non usare il telo portaferiti~Non muovere il paziente~Non muovere l'arto o la parte fratturata~Non usare disinfettanti~Non spogliare il paziente [TriggeringEvent]: Barella atraumatica (cucchiaio)~Asse spinale~Stecco benda rigida o a depressione [Miscellaneous]: frattura, fratture [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di coprire la persona con una coperta; Hai pensato di sostenere l'arto con una mano</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9003</SourceId>
        <SourceName>B Breathing: ripristino della funzione respiratoria</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: non applicabile n/a [Observations]: Varie [ObservedBehaviour]: Respiro agonico o gasping~Respiro assente [TreatmentType]: Valutazione usando la manovra del GAS (guardo-ascolto-sento)~
Se la persona respira&gt;
Allentare gli indumenti costrittivi (cravatte, cincture, busti, ecc.);
Controllare periodicamente e favourite la funzione respiratoria;
Posizionare la persona in Posizione Laterale di Sicurezza;
Procedete al trasferimento nella maniera piu' opportune;
Attendete l'aiuto di mezzi avanzati~
Se la persona non respira&gt;
Eseguire 2 ventilazioni;
Verificare che il torace si espanda durante le insufflazioni e si abbassi tra un'insufflazione e l'altra;
Riposizionare il capo e ripetere 2 insufflazioni in caso di insuccesso [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Posizione laterale di sicurezza~Ventilazioni~Pallone di Ambu~Respirazione bocca maschera~Respirazione bocca-bocca [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9009</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Dolore cardiaco</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O.118 invia un mezzo di soccorso di base, di cui tu sei un componente dell'equipaggio, per un codice G 02 K. Al tuo arrivo, trovi un signore seduto in poltrona, sudato e pallido, con respiro affannato ed aspetto sofferente. Ascoltate il racconto che vi viene fatto. Il signor Plutarco, 55 anni, lamenta da circa un'ora un dolore molto fastidioso riferito alla ``bocca dello stomaco``, con qualche irradiazione al torace; dando la colpa ad una digestione difficoltosa, non ha riferito nulla alla moglie, sia per non spaventarla, sia perche' lo rimprovera sempre di mangiare troppo: infatti il signor Plutarco, con i suoi 85 Kg, e' effettivamente in sovrappeso.
Dopo qualche tempo, la moglie si e' accorta che il marito non stava bene: lo vedeva pallido e sudato, con un respiro affannoso e la faccia sofferente. Dopo aver rintracciato il medico curante, e su suggerimento di questo, ha allertato il 118.
Nell'attesa dell'arrivo dei soccorsi, la signora ha fatto bere al marito una bella tazza di acqua e limone zuccherata e gli ha messo sul torace la borsa dell'acqua calda. Pur rispondendo alle vostre domande, il signor Plutarco e' restio ad accettare aiuto, anzi mostra la sua volonta' ad alzarsi e camminare da solo per raggiungere l'ambulanza, affermando che non sta poi cosi' male e che non e' ancora moribondo. [Observations]: Infarto cardiaco [ObservedBehaviour]: ``Senso di peso`` riferito dalla persona~
Senso di ansia e/o di angoscia~
Pallore cutaneo~
Sudorazione fredda~
Debolezza~
Irregolarita' del polso~
Senso di nausea ed episodi di vomito~
Respirazione superficiale e irregolare [TreatmentType]: Monitorare i segni vitali~
Evitare qualsiasi tipo di movimento~
Mettere la persona in posizione semi-seduta~
Allentare gli indumenti costrittivi~
Somministrare ossigeno~
In caso di arresto cardiocircolatorio, mettere in pratica le technique del BLS [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non somministrare cibi o bevande di alcun tipo alla persona [TriggeringEvent]: Maschera del gas [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di mantenere la temperatura corporea</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9015</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Gravidanza: dolore e perdita di sangue</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Sei un componente dell'equipaggio di base, che viene inviato in Via Roma al n. civico 18 terzo piano, con un cod. G 14 K, la C.O. ti informa che non c'e' a disposizione un'ambulanza medicalizzata prima di 15 minuti, giunti sul posto il marito ti informa che la signora al quarto mese di gravidanza dopo un periodo di circa 30 minuti di dolore al ventre, ha perso molto sangue, la signora si presenta dolorante, pallida, sudata, rilevi la p.a. che risulta essere 95/60. [Observations]: Aborto~Parto prematuro~Gravidanza~Parto fisiologico~Complicanze in gravidanza~Gestosi [ObservedBehaviour]: Perdita di sangue~Stillicidio o emorragia vaginale~Espulsione dell'embrione e della placenta~Dolore vivo pelvico e lombare~Dolore alla palpazione~Stato di shock (emorragia interna)~Ipotensione~Polso filiforme~Pallore, sudorazione ed agitazione~Contrattura della parete addominale~Possibili convulsioni [TreatmentType]: Trasportare immediatamente in ospedale in posizione supina/antishock~Conservare il materiale espulso~Monitorare constantemente i sintomi~Segnalare le condizioni alla centrale operative 118 [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non far camminare la persona [TriggeringEvent]: ABCD~Somministrazione di ossigeno ad alti flussi [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9004</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Circulation: ripristino della funzione cardiaca</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: non applicabile n/a [Observations]: Varie [ObservedBehaviour]: non applicabile [TreatmentType]: Valutare se e' presente l'attivita' cardiocircolatoria&gt;
Mantenere estesa con una mano la testa della persona;
Individuare con l'indice e il medio dell'altra mano la cartilagine laringea della persona;
Fate scivolare le due dita lateralmente verso l'esterno fino ad incontrare un solco della parte laterale del collo;
Valutare, facendo una lieve pressione, per non piu' di 10 secondi, il battito;
Contemporaneamente ricercare i segni di circolo (MO-TO-RE)~
Se il polso carotideo e' presente&gt;
Continuare con la ventilazione artificiale, mantenendo un ritmo di 10-12 atti respiratori al minuto;
Monitorare constantemente la presenza del polso carotideo e degli altri segni di attivita' cardiaca (MO-TO-RE)~
Se il polso carotideo NON e' presente&gt;
Provvedere tempestivamente alla circolazione artificiale per mezzo del massaggio cardiaco esterno [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Evitare di porre le dita di traverso sulle vie aeree, rischiando in tal modo di comprimere le stesse [TriggeringEvent]: Massaggio cardiaco esterno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9005</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Colpo di calore</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: E' il 12 di luglio e la C.O.118 vi invia con un codice G 19 Q presso la scuola elementare del paese. Vi dicono che un'insegnante ha avuto un malore durante una riunione.
Arrivati sul posto entrate e vi dirigete in sala professori dove si stava tenendo la riunione. Trovate il preside che vi spiega l'accaduto.
Durante gli scrutini iniziati ormai da alcune ore la professoressa ha chiesto da bere ma prima che arrivasse il bicchier d'acqua ha avuto ``un mancamento``. Vi avvicinate alla professoressa e cominciate la valutazione. [Observations]: Temperature ambientale elevate~Umidita' relative elevate~Abbigliamento che ostacola la dispersione di calore e l'evaporazione del sudore~Attivita' fisica intensa e prolungata [ObservedBehaviour]: Affaticamento~Cute calda e secca~Sete intensa~Temperature corporea elevate~Mal di testa e vertigini~Polso rapido~Alterazione della stato di coscienza fino alla perdita di coscienza [TreatmentType]: Allontanare la persona dalla fonte del calore caldo e umido~Rimuovere gli abiti~Avvolgere la persona in lenzuola umide~Mettere la persona in posizione anti-shock~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi~Porre sacchetti di ghiaccio secco sotto le ascelle, ditro le ginocchia, sull'inguine, suoi polsi e sulle caviglie e ai lati del collo~Controllare costantemente I parametri vitali [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: colpo, calore, mancamento [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di somministrare liquidi freschi per bocca se la persona e' cosciente; Hai pensato di aprire le finestre e porte in caso il locale e' molto caldo e umido</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9010</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Dolori addominali o dorsali di origine non traumatica</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O. vi invia su un Cod. V 19 K, giunti sul luogo dell'intervento trovate  il Sig. Augusto che riferisce un forte dolore al fianco sinistro subito sotto il costato, il dolore si irradia fino all inguine. Il Sig. Augusto vi dice che da anni soffre di calcolosi renale e gia' parecchie altre volte ha fatto ricorso alle cure mediche presso il reparto di urologia dell'Ospedale Maggiore, tutti i parametri vitali sono nella norma. [Observations]: Coliche addominali e renali~Mal di schiena [ObservedBehaviour]: Dolori fortissimi e insopportabili [TreatmentType]: Suggerire la posizione antalgica addominale per il trasporto della persona~Lasciar decider la persona la pisizione per il trasporto~Trasportare la persona all'ospedale di competenza secondo indicazione della C.O. [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Posizione antalgica addominale [Miscellaneous]: colica, rene, lombalgia [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di distrarre la persona dal dolore parlando di altre cose; Hai pensato di suggerire all'autista di proseguire verso l'ospedale con un tipo di guida il piu' confortevole possibile evitando scossoni e cambi di direzione improvvisi</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10004</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The Virgin Atlantic Upper Class service</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Whilst first-class air passengers often enjoy a good service during a flight, these passengers do not receive a first-class service before or after the flight.  A passenger is still required to carry their baggage to the airport. The passenger is then required to check-in baggage to the flight at the airport. The passenger is still required to undergo security checks at the airport, and the passenger is also required to plan their only journey to and from the airport. All of these activities are time-consuming to plan and to undertake. Moreover, the passenger needs to allow extra time for the journey because the time needed to check in for the flight cannot be predicted. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.virgin-atlantic.com/gb/en/the-virgin-experience/upperclass.html [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: First-class travel; door-to-door service; removing barriers to comfort; exclusive [SolutionDescription]: The Virgin Atlantic Upper Class service provides a complete door-to-door service to a passenger. The service seeks to remove all barriers and inconvenience to the passenger. A limousine service collects the passenger at the start of their journey to take the passenger to the airport, and transports the passengers from the airport to their destination after the flight. During the drive to the airport, the driver checks the passenger and the baggage into the flight. On arrival at the airport, the airline immediately takes the baggage from the passenger. The passenger enters the airport through a bespoke entrance. The entrance provides a private security check service. A passenger using this service is able to transfer from the limousine to the lounge within 10 minutes of arriving at the airport with minimum effort.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9016</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Ictus</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Sono le 20.15 e la CO118 allerta la tua squadra per un codice G 04 K. La CO118 riferisce che si tratta di un signore di 68 anni riverso a terra e inanimato. La tua squadra si avvia verso l'abitazione e una volta giunti entrate in casa.
Vi accoglie la moglie. Appare agitata e in lacrime. Vi dice in modo trafelato: ``Abbiamo finito di cenare e mio marito e' svenuto. Ho provato a chiamarlo ma non risponde. Ho fatto il 118 e mi hanno detto di stargli vicino e di aspettarvi``.
Il signore e' a terra, in cucina, e non sembra cosciente. [Observations]: Lesione o morte di una parte del cervello, causata da un apporto insufficiente di ossigeno~Aterosclerosi~Ipertensione~Aterosclerosi e ipertensione insieme [ObservedBehaviour]: Improvvisa alterazione di coscienza con paralisi~Alterazione della sensibilita' e della parola~Difficolta' respiratoria~Anisocoria, generalmente la pupilla piu' grande e' quella del lato opposto della paralisi [TreatmentType]: Monitoraggio e supporto  delle funzioni vitali~Posizionare la persona in posizione supina per il trasporto~Sollevare la testa con due cuscini [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Somministrazione di ossigeno~Barella [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di somministrare ossigeno alla persona</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9017</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazioni da oppiacei</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Sono le 2.25 del mattino. La C.O.118 vi allerta per un codice G 07 P. Si tratta di un giovane apperentemente inanimato e sdraiato su una panchina nel parco giochi del paese. Giungete sul posto dopo 4 minuti e trovate il ragazzo  sdraiato, una siringa e' ancora inserita nel braccio, attorno lui non vedete alter persone. [Observations]: Overdose da eroina [ObservedBehaviour]: Pupille puntiformi~Perdita progressiva della coscienza~Diminuzione della frequenza respiratoria fino all'arresto respiratorio~Cianosi [TreatmentType]: Controllore lo stato di coscienza della persona~Sfilare con cautela la siringa, tamponando eventuali emorragie~Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Somministrare ossigeno in caso di frequenza respiratoria [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Somministrazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di avvisare immediatamente il C.O.118 per facilitare la somministrazione di farmici utili a contrastare gli effetti degli oppiacei</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9006</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Contusioni</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Un ragazzo cade dal motorino, lamenta dolore al ginocchio sinistro e piange perche' i genitori non gli permetteranno piu' di usarlo. Ad un primo controllo notate un gonfiore al ginocchio sinistro senza segni di escoriazione. [Observations]: Urto contro un oggetto~Urto contro il suolo [ObservedBehaviour]: Dolore nella parte contusa~Dolore che si acutizza alla pressione della parte contusa~Gonfiore~Colore della cute alterato (livido) [TreatmentType]: Rimuovere gli indumenti per valutare correttamente la lesione~Raffreddare la contusione con ghiaccio istantaneo~Immobilizzare la parte contusa [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: Contusione [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10001</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Aeropuertos de Portugal</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: ANA (Aeropuertos de Portugal) is the state-owned company which operates Portugal`s eight major airports. ANA had become specialists in operations and infrastructure to meet the needs of the airlines, their primary customers.
With rapidly changing economic conditions, increased competition, rising fuel prices and the millions of passengers using their airports, ANA realised they needed to alter their perspective. To be truly world class they had to increase their offer for passengers and visitors and provide distinct and memorable customer services and initiate a shift in focus from infrastructure to service provider.
ANA asked Engine to help build a service brand and a strategy for implementation across their airports. Engine created a new role for the airport to play in passengers` experiences and outlined a sustainable customer service strategy. The new vision was realised in a series of workstreams that developed services and propositions to meet a range of customer needs, from business travellers to families, groups and connecting passengers. The project has been taken forward to have significant impact across the business, its environments, operations and culture. [Observations]: http://enginegroup.co.uk/work/ana-service-brand-strategy [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.ana.pt/en-US/Pages/Homepage.aspx [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: airport; monitor flight status; family services; [SolutionDescription]: A set of deliverables was created for each of nine workstreams. Including:
Final service specifications, propositions and blueprints to create the ideal passenger experience for value-add services
Structured approaches, tools and methods for the sustainable management strategy, such as a staff forum for training and sharing insights
Where appropriate, the deliverables also contained practical support for implementation, integration with other services and the key enablers and resources.
In 2011 prototypes and pilots of a range of services were taken forward, including ANA `PODs` and Family Services. ANA Basics concepts were trialled, embedded within key staff roles and responsibilities, and integrated within training programmes for front-line staff.
As of 2012, ANA have rolled out a number of the concepts and services that were developed with Engine.
Family services:
Baby changing facilities
Family `living room` spaces
Strollers provided after luggage check
ANA mascot; children`s entertainer
A children`s play area with seating and food preparation areas
Airport facilities and technology:
ANA `PODs and lounge spaces to meet a range of customer needs
ANA mobile and iPad app - to monitor flight status and more</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9018</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da sostanze caustiche</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O.118 vi invia in un ristorante poco distante da voi per un codice G 07 P. Pochi minuti dopo entrate nel ristorante e venite accompagnati dal gestore che appare preoccupato e vi dice: ``Gli ho solo dato degli spaghetti al sugo... non so cosa dire... cucino solo cose sane...`` Chiedete al gestore quanto tempo sia passato e vi dice che la signora ha mangiato e poi e' stata subito male. Raggiungete la signora che e' stata fatta sedere in una saletta del ristorante. Appare molto sofferente e si lamenta di avere dei forti dolori: ``Mi fa male alla gola, e piu' giu'``. Chiedete di che tipo di dolore si tratti e la signora vi dice che e' un forte bruciore che parte dalla bocca e arriva allo stomaco. Dice che il bruciore e' fortissimo. Vi dice che le e' venuto subito dopo aver bevuto un bicchier d'acqua.
Valutando le condizioni della signora notate che ha le labbra arrossate cosi' come la cavita' orale. Riuscite a recuperare la brocca d'acqua dal tavolo dove era seduta la signora e sentite che odora di detersivo. [Observations]: non applicabile [ObservedBehaviour]: Sensazione di bruciore in seguito ad indigestione di una bevanda~Ustioni alle labra e nella cavita' orale~Dolori violenti nella regione retrosternale~Bruciore alla bocca e alla gola [TreatmentType]: Evitare il contatto diretto della sostanza~Somministrazione di ossigeno~Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Recuperare e trasportare il contenitore della sostanza assicurandone l'integrita' [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non somministrare bevande o antidote di nessun genere~Non provocare il vomito~Non toccare o inalare le sostanze contenute nel contenitore [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di tappare il contenitore; Hai pensato di tappare il contenitore con qualche strumento di fortuna, in caso di mancanza del tappo; Hai pensato di portare in pronto soccorso il contenitore contenente il liquido</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9019</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da alimenti avariati e da funghi</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Venite inviati dalla C.O. presso l'Hotel Holiday Inn, per un codice V 07 P, giunti nella hall l'addetto alla reception vi dice che la guardia medica e' presso la stanza 223 per  una visita medica, vi accompagna, entrando il medico di guardia vi riferisce che il Sig. Rossi, ha vomito, diarrea, forti dolori addominali, riferisce che la sera prima ha preso parte ad una cena con altri compagni di viaggio e che altri tre amici hanno avuto gli stessi sintomi dopo aver cenato all' Osteria del Buon Viaggio. [Observations]: Indigestione di cibi mal conservati (latte, uova, ecc.) [ObservedBehaviour]: Nausea e vomito~Diarrea profuse~Dolori addominali~In alcuni casi comparsa di febbre~Tremori~Alterazioni dello stato di coscienza~Eccessiva salivazione~Tachicardia [TreatmentType]: Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Controllare gli episodi di vomito~Posizionare e trasferire la persona in posizione antalgica~Recuperare e trasportare eventuali residui di cibo [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Posizione antalgica [Miscellaneous]: Alimenti avariati [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9020</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da Ecstasy o altre anfetamine</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O. vi invia su di un codice V 07 S, all'arrivo trovate un signore di circa 25 anni, all'uscita di una discoteca con tachicardia, pupille dilatate e in difficolta' respiratoria, vi riferisce: ``vedo  una persona che sta dormendo nel mio letto e non vuole alzarsi``. [Observations]: Uso di ecstasy e altre anfetamine [ObservedBehaviour]: Nausea~Pupille dilatate~Sudorazione~Difficolta' respiratoria~Secchezza della bocca~Tachicardia~Ipertermia~Alterazioni dello stato di coscienza: ansia, depressione, delirio, attacchi di panico, allucinazioni [TreatmentType]: Trasferire la persona in un ambiente fresco ed aerato~Porre confezioni di ghiaccio sintetico sotto le ascelle, le ginocchia, l'inguine, i polsi, le caviglie e ai lati del collo~Applicare il BLS se necessario~Monitorare constantemente le funzioni vitali~Controllare gli episodi di vomito~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Somministrazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9021</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da farmaci</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Andate in Via Mazzini al civico 27 terzo piano per un trasporto ordinario, trovate la signora Maria che anziche' aspettarvi come al solito seduta sulla poltrona, e' distesa a letto; valutate la respirazione e la rilevate in 8 atti respiratori al minuto, molto sonnolente, vi parla con difficolta'. Dalle poche parole che riesce a riferire capite che ha ingerito piu' volte la quantita di antidepressivi che di solito prende come terapia medica. Avvisate la C. O. che vi supporta nell'intervento e vi assegna un cod. G 07 K . La C.O. vi comunica che l'ambulanza medicalizzata arriver? dopo 10 minuti. [Observations]: Ingestione accidentale di una dose eccessiva~Ingestione volontaria di una dose potenzialmente dannosa a scopo di suicido [ObservedBehaviour]: Movimenti del corpo scoordinati~Espressioni vocali non coerenti~Diminuzione della frequenza respiratoria, fino all'arresto respiratorio~Perdita progressiva della coscienza, dalla sonnolenza fino al coma [TreatmentType]: Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Somministrare ossigeno~Coprire la persona~Recuperare e trasportare iI flacon e/o blister contenenti il farmaco, anche se sono vuoti [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non somministrare bevande o antidote di nessun genere~Non provocare il vomito [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: Atto respiratorio, antidepressivo [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9022</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da monossido di carbonio</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O.118 vi invia ad un'abitazione privata per un codice G 07 K indicandovi inoltre la presenza sul posto dei Vigili del Fuoco. Arrivati sul posto notate un camion dei Vigili del Fuoco uno dei quali, assieme al portiere dello stabile, vi accompagna al quarto piano, dove abitano le persone per le quali siete stati chiamati. Salendo le scale il portiere vi dice: ``Non li ho visti uscire questa mattina e allora ho provato a chiamarli ma non rispondono. Hanno appena ristrutturato l'appartamento e si sono dimenticati di darmi le chiavi nuove.`` Il vigile del fuoco aggiunge che stanno tentando di sfondare la porta. Appena arrivate al quarto piano trovate la porta gia' aperta dai VVF che sono entrati nella casa. L'impulso di entrare sarebbe forte ma attendete prudentemente che i Vigili del fuoco escano e vi indichino con certezza che l'ambiente e' sicuro. Infatti dopo pochi secondi esce un Vigile del fuoco che vi dice: ``Ci sono due persone in camera da letto. Non rispondono, sembrano svenute. Potete entrare perche' non ci sono fughe di gas``. Entrate e raggiungete la camera da letto. Le due persone sono ancora sotto alle coperte. Il portiere che vi ha seguiti in casa vi dice che sono marito e moglie. Vi avvicinate al letto e valutate le due persone. [Observations]: Ingestione accidentale di una dose eccessiva~Ingestione volontaria di una dose potenzialmente dannosa a scopo di suicidio [ObservedBehaviour]: Nausea e vomito - cefalea~Perdita progressive di coscienza, dalla sonnolenza fino al coma~Difficolta' respiratoria, con assenza di cianosi, e comparsa di colorito rosso vivo (segno tardive) [TreatmentType]: Autoproteggersi~Rendere sicuro l'ambiente~Allontanare la persona dalla sostanza tossica~Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi~Coprire la persona [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non somministrare bevande o antidote di nessun genere~Non provocare il vomito [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di trasferirti in un ambiente sicuro e privo di monossido di cario, se possibile; Hai pensato di essere rapido in quello che fai per evitare di essere intossicato; Hai pensato di aprire finestre e porte per eliminare il monossido di carbonio dalla stanza; Hai pensato di cercare la causa dell'intossicazione (stufa o scaldabagno) e spegnerla; Hai pensato di lasciare ai Vigili del Fuoco il compito di trovare e spegnere la causa dell'intossicazione (stufa o scaldabagno)</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9023</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da gas infiammabili</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Venite inviati  su un Cod.  G 07 K, all'arrivo trovate i VVF che hanno appena aperto una porta di un appartamento e vi chiedono di aspettare a distanza perche' stanno valutando la sicurezza dei locali da cui fuoriesce un forte odore di gas. Una volta aerato il locale vi permettono di entrare. Trovate il paziente steso a terra nel bagno, ha difficolta' respiratoria, accanto a se ha residui di cibo vomitato, la persona e' semicoscente. [Observations]: Fuga di gas infiammabile [ObservedBehaviour]: Nausea e vomito~Predita progressive di coscienza, dalla sonnolenza fino al coma~Difficolta? respiratoria [TreatmentType]: Autoproteggersi~Prevenire i rischi di esplosioni~Interrompere, se possibile, l'erogazione del gas~Allontanare la persona dalla sostanza tossica~Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi~Coprire la persona [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non suonare il campanello~Non attivare o disattivare contatti elettrici~Non accendere fiammiferi, candele o alter fiamme libere~Non fumare [TriggeringEvent]: Somministrazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: Rischio esplosione, gas [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di allertare i Vigili del Fuoco</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10002</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The London Parking Payment app</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Car parking on London streets can be a complex and difficult process. Drivers often lack the resources needed to pay for a parking space. Sometimes, motorists often lack the cash needed to pay for a parking space using a meter. Other times, motorists cannot access a meter that accepts a valid credit card. Different London boroughs manage parking spaces using different processes. Different parking services require different tickets. As a consequence, drivers do not know at services are available in advance at free parking spaces. As a consequence, drivers cannot plan to pay for a parking space in advance. This results in both stress and a lack of confidence in street parking in London. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: https://paybyphone.co.uk/mobile-apps/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Car parking; diverse services; one-stop shop; mobile app [SolutionDescription]: The London parking app provides a single service to allow drivers to pay for a London parking space quickly and efficiently. The app runs on the driver's mobile device. The driver can enter information about their vehicle and their credit card into the app in advance. Each parking zone in London has a unique 4-digit identifier. Each identifier is displayed to the driver at the parking zone. When the driver parks in the parking zone, the driver simply enters the identifier and the length of visit into the app, and presses the button to book the parking space. The parking space is automatically booked for the duration requested, and information about the booking is passed to local parking attendants. As such, the app provides the driver with a simple, one-stop shop for all parking requirements in London.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10003</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The Barnet Fix-My-Street service</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Residents in the London Borough of Barnet experience a diverse range of urgent problems with their environment. These problems range from vandalism and poor parking to broken streets and dead animals. Residents often do not know which Borough department to report the problem to, because each resident requires knowledge of what each department does. However, most residents do not have knowledge about what each department does, and cannot choose the right department. As a consequence, some residents often fail to report important problems. Other residents report a problem to the wrong department, which consumes the time of the department. It also delays the fixing of the problem. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://barnet.fixmystreet.com [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Diverse services; unclear user actions; one-stop shop; single website [SolutionDescription]: The London Borough of Barnet introduces an online, one-stop shop to allow residents to report all problems that arise. Each resident can report a new problem on the website, independent of the department that will need to fix it. The resident can provide a textual description of the problem. The resident can attach a photo of the problem to be resolved. The resident can also locate the position of the problem on a digital map on the website. The Borough will seek to repair the problem as soon as possible. When it cannot fix the problem, it will contact the resident to update them on the timetable to fix the problem. After the problem has been reported, the resident can view the problem to view whether it has been fixed. The resident can use the website to also report on the quality of the fix.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9024</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da Hashish/Marijuana</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Arrivati sulla scena del codice R 07 K, trovate alcune persone che presentano chiari segni di intossicazione per inalazione di droghe, tra i coinvolti uno e' tachicardico f.c. 130, ha tremori, riferisce forte dolore alla testa, e sta vomitando. [Observations]: Abuso di Hashish/Marijuana [ObservedBehaviour]: Nausea e vomito~Cefalea~Tremor~Incoordinazione motoria~Tachicardia~Alterazione dello stato di coscienza con ansia e angoscia, depression e perdita di coscienza in casi estremi [TreatmentType]: Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Controllare gli episodi di vomito~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: BLS~Somministrazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: inalazione droghe [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9025</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da Cocaina</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: All'arrivo sul posto di intervento R 07 Z, vi trovate di fronte ad un capannone in vistoso stato di abbandono, i carabinieri presenti sul posto vi comunicano che nel capannone era in corso un rave party e  che alcune pattuglie sono all'interno del locale. Venite scortati nel locale e vedete una persona in evidente stato di alterazione di coscienza, in stato eccitatorio con sensazione di onnipotenza;  coprite la persona, gli somministrate ossigeno in base a quanto indicatovi dalla C.O. e vi preparate a caricare il paziente sulla barella. [Observations]: Abuso di cocaina [ObservedBehaviour]: Tachicardia, naso che cola~Alterazioni dello stato coscienza da uno stato eccitatorio con aumento dell'immaginazione e impression di onnipotenza ad uno stato sonnolento con deliri e allucinazioni spiacevoli [TreatmentType]: Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Somministrare ossigeno~Coprire la persona [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: BLS~Somministrazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: inalazione [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9026</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da antiparassitari</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Venite inviati presso la 'Cascina Vittoria' di Via Sase Sparse, vi aspettano al bivio con della statale 24 e Via della Rimembranza a bordo di una Ford Fiesta grigia in quanto sicuramente potete avere difficolta' a rintracciare il luogo di intervento. Giunti sul posto, trovate un agricoltore che in maniche corte (in quanto fa molto caldo), riferisce che durante il trattamento di un frutteto con alcuni prodotti antiparassitari, ha iniziato a sentire un fastidioso bruciore al torace, agli arti superiori e al viso. Da una vostra valutazione notate che respira in modo difficoltoso, ha forti tremori. [Observations]: Assorbimento cutaneo di antiparassitari o erbicidi [ObservedBehaviour]: Tremori e convulsioni~Difficolta' respiratoria~Alterazione dello stato di coscienza, fino al coma [TreatmentType]: Rimuovere gli indumenti e lavare abbondantemente con acqua corrente le parti che sono venute a contatto con la sostanza tossica~Coprire con garze sterili e telini le parti di cute che sono venute a contatto con la sostanza tossica~Applicare il BLS~Monitorare le funzioni vitali [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: BLS [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di indossare i guanti di protezione; Hai pensato di indossare gli occhiali di protezione per evitare il contatto di schizzi d'acqua con gli occhi; Hai pensato di indossare la mascherina di auto-protezione</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9027</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Intossicazione da morso di serpente</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Randez-vouz con un fuoristrada che trasporta un escursionista morso da una vipera; quando prendete in consegna la persona morsa, vi fanno vedere il polpaccio e lo trovate in evidente gonfiore, alcuni fori provocati dal morso, valutate la frequenza cardiaca (135 battiti minuto), il respiro e' molto alterato [Observations]: Morso di serpente [ObservedBehaviour]: Morso caratterizzato da due piccolo fori~Dolore e gonfiore nell'area del morso~Nausea e vomito~Tachicardia~Alterazione progressiva dello stato di coscienza, dall'agitazione alla perdita di coscienza~Alterazioni della respirazione~Convulsioni [TreatmentType]: Tranquillizzare la persona~Esporre la parte del corpo morsicata~Liberare da oggetti costrittivi quali stivali, cincture, ecc.~Lavare con soluzione fisiologica la zona del morso~Coprire la zona del morso con garze sterili~Immobilizzare la parte morsicata~Monitorare le funzioni vitali~Applicare il BLS~Coprire la persona [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non incidere la ferita~Non succhiare il veleno~Non applicare lacci emostatici o lacci di fortuna~Non somministrare il siero antiofidico o antivipera [TriggeringEvent]: BLS [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di trasportare la persona mantenendo la parte morsicata piu' in basso rispetto al torace; Hai pensato di valutare costantemente le funzioni vitali in quanto e' possibile che la persona morsicata possa cadere in stato di shock</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9028</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Ipotermia</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: State facendo assistenza ad una gara di slalom speciale, nevica e fa molto freddo; il numeroso pubblico e' ormai da ore che aspetta di veder passare i propri idoli. Uno spettatore vi corre incontro dicendovi che un suo amico ha un malore. Giungete nei pressi della persona e notate che ha la giacca a vento molto bagnata dalla neve, forti tremori, vi riferisce che non ha mangiato quasi nulla ma ha ingerito alcuni bicchieri di vino pensando di riscaldarsi, riferisce intorpidimento agli arti. [Observations]: Calo eccessivo della temperatura [ObservedBehaviour]: Brividi~Intorpidimento~Sonnolenza~Calo della vista [TreatmentType]: Parlare alla persona per rendervi conto della gravita'~Portare la persona in un luogo asciutto~Sostenere le funzioni vitali~Somministrare ossigeno~Spogliare la persona da abiti bagnati~Coprire la persona con teli di metallina o coperte asciutte~Somministrare bevande calde e zuccherate~Monitorare costantemente le funzioni vitali~Trasportare in posizione antishock [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non somministrare bevande bollenti [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9029</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Lesioni aperte della cute</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O. vi invia su un cod. G 01 L. giunti sul posto trovate un vetraio che sostituendo un vetro ad una porta del supermercato si e' procurato un vistoso taglio al braccio destro, vi riferisce che il sangue che fuoriusciva dal taglio zampillava in modo abbondante e che dalla C.O. gli hanno detto di effettuare una pressione sulla ferita dopo avergli applicato sopra garze sterili prelevate dalla cassetta di pronto soccorso del supermercato. [Observations]: Diversi tipi di trauma~Corpo estraneo [ObservedBehaviour]: Sanguinamento~Dolore [TreatmentType]: Rimuovere gli indumenti per valutare correttamente la lesione~Lavare con soluzione fisiologica o con acqua corrente per almeno 5 minuti~Disinfettare con disinfettante iodato~Medicare con garze sterili [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9030</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Lesioni cerebrali in seguito a trauma cranico</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Inviati su di un codice R 01 S, trovate un auto capottata ed una persona espulsa dall'auto. La persona e' cosciente,  presenta un vistoso ematoma al cuoio capelluto, dopo qualche istante il ferito inizia a vomitare con vomito a getto, dice di non ricordare assolutamente nulla, non ricorda come si chiama e che giorno sia, appena lo avete immobilizzato, improvvisamente perde coscienza. [Observations]: Frattura aperta con esposizione della materia cerebrale~Ferita penetrante (es. arma da fuoco)~Trauma chiuso [ObservedBehaviour]: Dolore e/o gonfiore~Lacerazione del cuoi capelluto e/o deformazione~Fuoriuscita di sangue o di liquor cerebrospinale dal naso/orecchio~Comparsa di cefalea intense o malessere (nausea)~Alterazione dello stato mentale, dalla confusion all perdita di coscienza~Disturbi dei sensi~Vomito violento e improvviso~Differenza tra i diametri pupillari~Alterazioni della motilita? o della sensibilita? [TreatmentType]: Garantire le funzioni vitali~Garantire l'immobilizzazione della colonna cervicale~Valutare lo stato di coscienza~Controllare e garantire la pervieta' delle vie respiratorie~Somministrare ossigeno ad alti flussi~Arrestare le eventuali emorragie~Medicare e bendare le ferite [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non tamponare fuoriuscite di sangue o liquor da naso e orecchie ma limitarsi a coprire con garza sterile~Non rimuovere mai e per nessun motivo corpi estranei o frammenti ossei~Non effettuare alcuna compressione sui focolai di frattura cranica~Non sollevare il capo della persona o eseguire altri movimenti bruschi~Non somministrare alcun tipo di bevanda [TriggeringEvent]: Collare cervicale~Asse spinale~Cannula orofaringea~Pallone di Ambu~Garze [Miscellaneous]: Commozione cerebrale, Contusione cerebrale, Ematoma intracranico [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di spegnare il quadro elettrico della macchina?; Hai pensato alla possibilita' di lesioni vertebrali (e percio' midollari) associate; Hai pensato di tenere la persona a riposo evitando movimenti bruschi; Hai pensato di immobilizzare e non rimuovere eventuali oggetti confiscati; Hai pensato di immobilizzare la persona mantenendo la colonna allineata; Hai pensato di monitorare continuamente le funzioni vitali; Hai pensato di annotare ogni variazione delle funzioni vitali; Hai pensato di prepararti in caso di vomito improvviso o di convulsioni</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9031</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Lesioni traumatiche della cute</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Vi inviano presso la scuola elementare di via Leonardo da Vinci su un cod. V 01 Q. Una bambina durante l'intervallo e' scivolata provocandosi un'escoriazione agli arti inferiori ed alle mani, piange, riferisce dolore localizzato. [Observations]: Molti tipi di trauma~Escoriazioni~Ferite senza corpo estraneo~Ferite con corpo estraneo [ObservedBehaviour]: La cute si lacera~Sanguinamento~Dolore [TreatmentType]: Rimuovere gli indumenti per valutare la lesione~Lavare con soluzione fisiologica~Disinfettare con disinfettante iodato~Medicare con garze sterili~Coprire con garze sterili ed effettuare bendaggio compressivo~Tentare di stabilizzare il corpo estraneo con un bendaggio contenitivo [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: NON rimuovere il corpo estraneo conficcato nella ferita~NON rimuovere gli abiti sovrastanti alla ferita [TriggeringEvent]: Bendaggio compressivo~Bendaggio contenitivo [Miscellaneous]: cute, emorragia capillare [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di lavare la ferita con acqua corrente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9032</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Lesioni traumatiche dell'addome</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C.O. ti invia presso il galoppatoio, l'addetto alle stalle e' sdraiato a terra in seguito ad un calcio ricevuto da un cavallo. Riferisce forti dolori alla cavita' addominale, riferisce inoltre nausea e vomito. Scoprite l'addome della persona e notate i sogni di una forte contusione all'altezza del fegato. Dopo pochi istanti la persona si sente sempre piu' debole, e' sudato, vi chiede da bere in quanto ha molta sete, gli valutate il polso e rilevate 140 pulsazioni al minuto. [Observations]: Trauma con impatto violento [ObservedBehaviour]: Segni di contusione e ferite~Dolore nella sede della lesione o generalizzato~Contrattura della muscolatura addominale~Nausea e vomito~Debolezza, pallore, sete intensa e polso accelerato, in caso di emorragia interna [TreatmentType]: Lesione addominale chiusa&gt;Mettere la persona in posizione antalgica addominale;Somministrare ossigeno~Lesione addominale aperta&gt;Proteggere la ferita con garze sterili;Nel caso, proteggere i visceri fuoriusciti con un telino sterile;Inumidire periodicamente le medicazioni con soluzione fisiologica;Applicare una medicazione sigillante;Posizionare la persona in posizione antalgica addominale;Somministrare ossigeno [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: non applicabile [TriggeringEvent]: Posizione antalgica addominale~Somministrazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di prepararti per un eventuale shock</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9033</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Ostruzione delle vie aeree da corpo estraneo</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Cod. R 03 Z, vieni inviato presso la casa di riposo della tua cittadina, all'arrivo ti indirizzano presso la sala mensa, giunto sul posto trovi una signora anziana a terra priva di sensi, controlli la pervieta' delle vie aeree e noti un oggetto inserito in fondo alla gola, inizi immediatamente il BLS. [Observations]: Corpo estraneo penetrato nelle vie respiratorie [ObservedBehaviour]: Lieve&gt;tosse vigorosa e continua;inspirazione rumorosa tra I colpi di tosse~Grave&gt;tossa non vigorosa - debole;stridore durante le inspirazioni;difficolta' respiratoria che diventa sempre piu' grave;cianosi~Completa&gt;impossibilita' di parlare;impossibilita' di tossire;impossibilita' di respirare;portarsi le mani alla gola;cianosi;agitazione fino alla perdita di coscienza [TreatmentType]: Lieve&gt;incoraggiare la persona a tossire;allertare la CO118 se la situazione dovesse peggiorare~Grave&gt;pacche dorsali;pacche toraciche;compressioni addominali (manovra di Heimlich);proseguire alternando 5 pacche dorsali, 5 pacche toraciche e 5 compressioni addominali~Se la situazione non si risolve e la persona perde coscienza&gt;valutare lo stato di coscienza e chiedere aiuto al CO118;posizionare la persona supina;iperestendere il capo e sollevare il mento;ispezionare il cavo orale e rimuovere eventuali corpi estranei;effettuare la valutazione G.A.S.;eseguire due ventilazioni;in caso di insuccesso, effettuare 30 compressioni toraciche [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Lieve&gt;non interferire nei tentativi spontanei di espulsione di corpo estraneo [TriggeringEvent]: Pacche dorsali~Pacche toraciche~Compressioni addominali (manovra di Heimlich)~Valutazione G.A.S.~Ventilazioni compressioni toraciche [Miscellaneous]: BLS, Vie aeree [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di estrarre il corpo estraneo usando delle pinzette; Hai pensato di rimuovere il corpo estraneo con il tuo dito a uncino, in caso le pinze non sono disponibili e il corpo estraneo e' ben visibile</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9034</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Parto</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: L'ambulanza medicalizzata e' impegnata su un altro intervento e la C.O. ti invia su un parto su gestante a termine. Al tuo arrivo la signora ti riferisce che le contrazioni si susseguono ormai con un ritmo quasi continuo e molto doloroso. Ad un controllo noti una notevole dilatazione, dopo alcuni minuti e mentre stai comunicando con la C.O. la donna riferisce che sente la necessita' di assecondarle spingendo. Ti prepari ad assistere al parto... [Observations]: Termine di gestazione~Parto [ObservedBehaviour]: Non applicabile [TreatmentType]: Triage pre-parto&gt;Domandare se e' il primo figlio;Se sente il bisogno di spingere;Eseguire l'esame fisico del perineo~Parto per via vaginale&gt;Assecondare le esigenze della madre;Porre le mani alle ossa temporali della testa del neonate quando e' uscita;Controllare che attorno al collo NON ci sia il cordone ombelicale;Far proseguire il parto [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: Non esercitare pressione sulla testa del neonato [TriggeringEvent]: non applicabile [Miscellaneous]: Termine di gestazione [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di attivare subito una seconda ambulanza in caso di parto gemellare; Hai pensato di chiedere la data prevista per il parto; Hai pensato di notare il colore del liquido amniotico; Hai pensato di scaldare l'ambiente, spegnendo le ventilazioni e condizionamenti d'aria; Hai pensato di creare uno spazio adeguato per la donna e per accogliere il neonato; Hai pensato di preparare teli asciutti e caldi; Hai pensato di preparare la maschera facciale pediatrica, il Pallone di ventilazione, clamps, forbici e garze e posizionare la donna in posizione supine</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9035</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Pneumotorace</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La C. O. ti invia su di un cod. R 01 S, all'arrivo trovi una persona che e' stata ferita al torace da un oggetto contundente. Scopri il torace e noti un foro nel costato da cui fuoriesce un sibilo, la persona respira in modo rapido e difficoltoso. Valuti che la persona non abbia subito lesioni traumatiche alla colonna vertebrale e la posizioni semiseduta per favorire la respirazione. [Observations]: Apertura della parte toracica~Lesioni del polmone [ObservedBehaviour]: Dolore toracico~Respirazione rapida e difficoltosa [TreatmentType]: Pneumotorace chiuso&gt;posizionare la persona in modo da essere comoda;somministrare alte concentrazioni di ossigeno;il trasporto deve essere rapido~Pneumotorace aperto&gt;Sigillare tre lati della ferita;Somministrare alte concentrazioni di ossigeno [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: NON rimuovere il corpo estraneo in caso di pneumotorace aperto [TriggeringEvent]: Ventilazione assistita con Pallone Ambu~Garze sterili~Telino sterili [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9036</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Stato di shock</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: La moglie di un agricoltore chiama la C.O. per riferire che il marito e stato punto da un calabrone. Giunto sul posto trovi la persona, molto dolorante nel punto in cui e' stato punto, molto sudato, respiro difficoltoso, frequenza cardiaca molto elevata. Ti prepari a supportare con le manovre del BLS il coltivatore. [Observations]: Emorragia (shock emorragico)~Reazioni allergiche (shock anafilattico)~Infezioni generalizzate (shock settico)~Lesioni traumatiche coinvolgenti il midollo spinale (shock neurogeno)~Situazioni fortemente emotive (shock psicogeno)~Infarto miocardico, embolia polmonare gravi trauma toracici (shock cardiogeno) [ObservedBehaviour]: Polso piccolo e frequente~Respiro accellerato, superficiale, difficoltoso~Cute e mucose pallide e fredde, sudorazione~Agitazione psicomotoria, confusione [TreatmentType]: Posizionare la persona in posizione  anti shock~Coprire la persona per evitare dispersione di calore~Somministrare ossigeno~Trattare le cause scatenanti (emoraggia ecc.) [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: NON mettere nessun cuscino o altro sotto la testa della persona in posizione anti shock~NON mettere la persona in posizione anti shock se si sospetta un evento traumatico [TriggeringEvent]: Erogazione di ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9037</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Subamputazione</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: Vieni inviato in Viale Regina Elena 25 presso l'abitazione di un'anziana signora, al tuo arrivo trovi la persona coricata a terra con la gamba ed il piede incastrato tra i sanitari, una grande quantita' di sangue e a terra, l'anziana signora e' in stato di semicoscienza. Controlli l'arto inferiore e noti che e' sub amputato all'altezza della caviglia. Provvedi immediatamente ad arrestare l'emorragia ed a supportare le funsioni vitali. [Observations]: Subamputazione (piccolo parte dell'arto ancora attaccato al corpo)&gt;di un arto superiore;di un arto inferiore [ObservedBehaviour]: non applicabile [TreatmentType]: Trattare l'emorragia coon un bendaggio compressivo~Avvolgere l'arto piu' volte con un telino~Raffreddare l'arto con ghiaccio secco~Immobilizzare l'arto [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: NON usare solo ghiaccio per la conservazione della parte imputata, per evitare il congelamento. Usare acqua con ghiaccio [TriggeringEvent]: Bendaggio compressivo~Laccio emostatico, SOLO in caso necessario [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>9038</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Ustioni</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Emergency[ProblemDescription]: All'interno del laboratorio di chimica dell' I.I.T.S., un allievo si versa su una gamba un contenitore pieno di una sostanza non ben definita. Al tuo arrivo si lamenta di forte bruciore all'arto inferiore sinistro e al piede. Gli indumenti sono completamente adesi alla ferita. [Observations]: Ustione chimica~Ustione termica~Inalazione di fumi [ObservedBehaviour]: Ustione superficiale dell'epidermide~Arrossamento~Gonfiore localizzato~Ustione che interessa del derma~Bolle e dolore molto intense non solo locali~Ustione sotto il derma, fino alle ossa~Aspetto chiazzato, aree biancastre~Dolore intensissimo [TreatmentType]: AUTOPROTEGGERVI E VALUATERE LA SICUREZZA~Allontanare la persona dalla fonte di calore~Rimuovere gli abiti superficiali e gli oggetti ancora caldi~Lavare le ferite con soluzione fisiologica~Detergere la sostanza chimica con abbondante acqua corrente~Proteggere la parte ustionata con un telino sterile [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]: NON usare estintori per soffocare le fiamme sulla persona~NON rimuovere gli abiti a contatto stretto con la cute~NON tagliare o bucare le bolle~NON applicare cerotti~NON usare cotone~NON usare prodotti 'anti ustione' o sostanze oleose~NON occuparsi delle lesioni locali trascurando lo stato generale della persona [TriggeringEvent]: Somministrazione dell'ossigeno [Miscellaneous]: non applicabile [SolutionDescription]: Hai pensato alla privacy della persona; Hai pensato di tranquillizzare e sostenere psicologicamente la persona se ancora cosciente; Hai pensato di somministrare ossigeno; Hai pensato di prepararti per un eventuale shock; Hai pensato di alleviare il dolore raffreddando le ferite con telini freddi, sterili e bagnati; Hai pensato alle conseguenze dell'inalazione del fumo; Hai pensato di posizionare la persona semi seduta (se possibile)</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10005</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The Pret-a-Manger coffee service</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The purchase of a morning coffee in a busy coffee shop can be an impersonal and unrewarding experience. A different server serves the customer each day.  The customer is often required to repeat their order each day, even though the coffee order does not change. The most that most customers can expect is to receive the correct coffee each morning, without too much wait. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]:  [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Coffee shop; personalised service; free coffee; unexpected bonuses [SolutionDescription]: The Pret-a-Manger chain seeks to enhance the service experience for the customer each morning. Staff are encouraged to remember the regular orders of each customer. Staff are expected to serve customers quickly without the need to wait. Staff are also encouraged occasionally to offer customers their coffee for free, as a bonus to enhance the customer experience.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10008</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Simple speech control of devices</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Currently, most users interact with mobile apps through the digital touch keyboard on the mobile device. Although this form of interaction is familiar to most users, the use of such interaction remains difficult. A user who wishes to enter information into the app is required to stop their current activity to undertake the interaction. For example, a user cannot walk or drive when interacting with a device. Users are impeded from using apps and mobile devices to their full benefit. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.apple.com/ios/siri/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: voice recognition; speech control; mobile app use [SolutionDescription]: Reliable speech recognition services such as Apple?s Siri can provide a solution to this bottleneck to the use of mobile apps. Most people are able to talk whilst undertaking a physical or simple cognitive task.  Therefore, interacting with a mobile device through speech can enhance mobile app usage. Services such as Siri can make everyday tasks less tasking. It can understand which apps to use for which requests, and it can find answers to queries through sources. It plays the songs that a user wants to hear, and can give the user directions as they walk or drive.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10006</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The digital airline boarding pass</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The use of paper boarding passes to gain access to flights can be challenging for travellers.  Many airlines do not allow a traveller to check-in and generate a boarding pass until several days before a flight departs. One consequence is that travellers often need to locate a means to print their boarding pass before traveling. Travellers at home sometimes do not have access to printers. Travellers away from home are often not able to access the Internet and a printer. These travellers do not have equal access to the airline's services. Travellers who want to gain access need to undertake extra steps, often at a cost to themselves. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.britishairways.com/travel/mobile-boarding-pass/public/en_gb [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Boarding pass; airline; mobile app; digital boarding pass [SolutionDescription]: Many airlines now provide a digital app that gives the traveller access to their boarding pass on their mobile device. The British Airways app is available for iPhone, BlackBerry, Windows Phone and Android. A traveller can either log in to their account via the airline website to retrieve their mobile boarding pass. The traveller's next flight is shown on the home screen. When check-in opens for the next flight, the traveller can select the check-in button. If the traveller has not checked in, the traveller will be prompted to do so. When the traveller has checked in for the flight, the boarding pass will be downloaded to their phone. The traveller can then access your boarding pass at any time by selecting the show boarding pass feature on the home screen. If the traveller has already checked in, and mobile boarding passes are available for the destination, the boarding pass will be downloaded to the phone.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10007</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The IKEA online kitchen planner</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The design and purchase of a new kitchen by homeowners are expensive and time-consuming businesses. Designing modern kitchens can be challenging. There is a vast range of different types of devices and appliances that can be installed. The possible combinations of these appliances are complex. Meeting a homeowner's requirements for a new kitchen within space and cost constraints in a difficult design problem. One current solution is a kitchen design expert who acts as a consultant for a homeowner. However, the use of such expert is time-consuming and expensive, and the process does not allow homeowners to express all of their needs. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.ikea.com/ms/en_GB/rooms_ideas/kitchen_howto/EU/plan_your_kitchen_in_3d.html# [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: kitchen design; self-design; plug-and-play; simulation [SolutionDescription]: IKEA provide an online kitchen planner tool to allow homeowners to design their kitchens without a human design consultant. A homeowner can use the tool to draw the kitchen, build it and get a full 3D view of the new kitchen. Getting a detailed overview of a new kitchen in 3D is a great way to get a feel for what the kitchen will look like when it is in place at home. It is designed for non-experienced kitchen planners. The homeowner can switch easily between 3D and floor plan views. A complete product list is included. As the homeowner builds and designs the new kitchen, the planner tool adds a detailed list of all products that the homeowner chooses to include. The product information includes the name, product description, main material and price; all basic information you need to advance the kitchen design.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10009</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Design for the clinic experience</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The lack of interaction at different points throughout the journey at Dr. Amin Kassam's clinic (world-renown neurosurgeon who has perfected a minimally invasive brain tumor removal procedure) creates a barrier between patients and their families and the positive experience of being with Dr. Kassam and his staff. [Observations]: http://jamin.org/upmc-neurosurgery-clinic/ [ObservedBehaviour]: http://placesofdesign.com/files/upmc_holisticbook.pdf [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: clinic; barriers; world-class practice [SolutionDescription]: The ideal situation would be continual interaction extending the positive experience of being with Dr. Kassam and his staff to the patients and their families, putting them at ease and giving them control of their experience. Develop a holistic solution that includes:

The Wall of Hope will be a collection of patients' hand-written testimonials about their surgery or recovery, Dr. Kassam, clinic staff, etc.
The Welcome Booklet gives new patients an overview of the overall patient journey, one clinic visit, the staff and Dr. Kassam in Kassam's own words.
Messages from patients, staff and Dr. Kassam appear on a large Clinic Chat display in the waiting room.
Even a small gift lets the patient know that you care about their experience. 
An automated system that uses RFID would reduce the need for staff to manually track their location and offer opportunities to connect the data to a visualization that is displayed in multiple locations.
Staff meetings would be held on a regular basis to provide a forum for team-building and professional development.
The ambient waiting time displays help Dr. Kassam and his staff provide the attention and care that patients need.
Dr. Kassam often needs to consult with other physicians. LCD screens in the exam room displaying patient information allows Dr. Kassam to identify physicians to contact and assign a staff member to contact them.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10010</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The Zipcar vehicle rental service</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Zipcar is a car sharing scheme that provides vehicle reservations to its members. A member who uses a vehicle is billed by the hour or by the day. The service was generated use by urban residents who do not own a vehicle. Residents often need to use a vehicle for short periods of time in local communities to undertake specific tasks. Existing car hire companies do not provide local, short-term vehicle rentals at a cost that members are prepared to pay. [Observations]: http://multivu.prnewswire.com/mnr/zipcar/37746/images/37746-hi-Landingpage.png [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.zipcar.co.uk/london_campaign?gclid=CJeotqXF0rcCFRMPtAodAV4AQQ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Car rental; vehicle rental; just-in-time access [SolutionDescription]: A member can reserve a Zipcar online or by phone at anytime. A reservation can be made immediately or up to a year in advance. A member has automated access to a Zipcar vehicle using an access card that works with the car's technology to unlock the door. The keys are already located inside the vehicle. Zipcar also offers an iPhone or Android application that allows members to honk the horn to locate a Zipcar and to unlock the doors automatically with the mobile device. Zipcar charges a one-time application fee, an annual fee, and a reservation charge. Petrol, parking, insurance, and maintenance costs are included in the price of the rental.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10011</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Design for the clinic experience</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: There is a lack of interaction between patients and families at different points in the clinic. This creates a barrier between them and affects the positive experience of being in the clinic. Specific current problems include a lack of continuous interaction that extends the positive experience of attending the clinic to patients and their families, failure to put patients at their ease, and a lack of control over the experience. [Observations]: Jamin.org/archives/2008/upmc-neurosurgery-clinic [ObservedBehaviour]: http://placesofdesign.com/files/upmc_holisticbook.pdf [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Lack of interaction [SolutionDescription]: The proposed service offers a holistic solution composed of multiple elements. One element is the wall of hope, which is a collection of patients? hand-written testimonials about their surgery or recovery, Dr. Kassam, and clinic staff. Another element is the welcome booklet, which gives new patients an overview in Kassam?s own words of the overall patient journey, one clinic visit, the staff and Dr. Kassam. The clinic chat reports messages from patients, staff and Dr. Kassam that appear on a large clinic chat display in the waiting room. The element called the gift from the clinic provides information about the even small gifts that let the patient know that you care about their experience. The clinic staff locator is an automated system that uses RFID to track staff location, and the location data is displayed in multiple locations. Another element of the service is clinic staff meetings held on a regular basis to provide a forum for team-building and professional development. The wait-time indicator provides the ambient waiting time that is displayed to help staff provide the attention and care that patients need. Finally, the PCP Direct Link enables Dr. Kassam to consult with other physicians. The service provides LCD screens in the exam room that display patient information to allow Dr. Kassam to identify physicians to contact. A staff member can use this information to contact the physicians.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10012</SourceId>
        <SourceName>BALTIC</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: BALTIC Centre for Contemporary Arts is a landmark arts space. It is a converted flourmill beside the Tyne on what used to be the dockyards of Gateshead. BALTIC is a bold project bringing challenging contemporary art to the people of the North East. It has welcomed over 2 million visitors since it opened in 2002. However, BALTIC had not been achieving its ambition to bring contemporary art to the whole local community. Many visitors were not getting the welcome, expertise or information that would encourage them to return. [Observations]: https://www.balticmill.com/food-drink/baltic-cafe-bar [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.balticmill.com/
http://www.livework.co.uk/our-work/Baltic [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Visitor experience improvement [SolutionDescription]: The improvements at BALTIC include a gallery signage and a better cafe service. They also introduced new ideas, such as a history tour of the building. Collectively, these small ideas have enriched and transformed the visitor experience. An in-house innovation team have regular sessions. They review progress and set themselves targets for getting more ideas implemented. They also have built an ideas blog on their intranet.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10013</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Make it Work: Supporting hard to reach unemployed people into work</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Worklessness as a result of long-term illness is a headline issue. Six million people in the UK live in households where no one works. In the City of Sunderland 26% of the working age population are economically inactive. Besides almost 4 times as many people claim Incapacity Benefit than Job Seekers Allowance. live|work's Northern Way Worklessness pilot  looked at how the long-term unemployed interact with employment services. They developed some innovative ways to reach and support people back into work. Given the complexity of the journey into work, the council needed to develop a new, more nuanced perspective on the outcomes they sought, to include progression between stages. It required a service that could support people beginning at any stage of the journey. It needed to collaborate with community organisations who were already engaging effectively with people early on in their journey back to work. [Observations]: http://vimeo.com/13850609 [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.livework.co.uk/our-work/sunderland-make-it-work
http://www.nesta.org.uk/library/documents/radical-efficiency180610.pdf (page 48) [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Supporting users [SolutionDescription]: The council settled on an approach called an 'activity coalition' that integrated services offering support at all stages of the user journey. The service begins wherever the user is comfortable. The service pooled the various offers from community groups into a single brochure. The person that made the initial contact with the user followed him/her throughout their whole journey. The service established a platform that links the early and later stages of the journey back into work . This way the community groups and council support services are connected. For employers, this means that their main point of contact is still the job centre.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10014</SourceId>
        <SourceName>The Geek Squad</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Customers need someone to come quickly to their premises when they have a technical (software/hardware) problem, fix it, and very discretely disappear (so that they don't lose face). So if you wanted people to come and wire up your television or your computer, it would be great to see somebody who is agent 391. Agent 391 has got a badge like the FBI, he has got black trousers that are deliberately short so you see his white socks, and their tag line is 'You never saw us, we were never here'. Because they know that guys do not want to admit that they cannot wire these things up, so they say 'Call us when your wife or girlfriend is out, we will come and sort it out and you never saw us, we were never here'. Design strategy is about making people smile, feel safe, is having a purpose beyond price which is an emotional connection and not a rational one.' [Observations]: http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=geek+squad+images&amp;hl=en&amp;rls=com.microsoft:en-US&amp;tbm=isch&amp;tbo=u&amp;source=univ&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=wo5cUfqsI4i0PMv9gNgK&amp;ved=0CDAQsAQ&amp;biw=1280&amp;bih=633 [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.geeksquad.co.uk/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Technical problem [SolutionDescription]: Every bit of the Geek Squad experience has been designed to maximise impact and create word-of-mouth advertising. The name and logo were inspired by TV cop shows, employees are called agents, their uniforms, black clip on ties, white socks and a FBI like badge make clients smile and feel reassured. Their slogan - 'You didn't see me. I wasn't here' - means clients don't have to worry about admitting to having problems with technical things in their life. Even agents' shoes are designed. They have a cut out Geek Squad logo on the soles so that branded footprints are left behind. The service offers mobile and tablet Insurance, providing a 5 star Defaqto service, with 24/7 support and protection. The tech support membership plans include 24/7 Agent help with all kinds of technology issues, plus smart security for your mobile or computer. Agents eliminate tech trauma and help you make the most of your devices. The reliable repairs service is available in Carphone Warehouse stores across the UK. If you visit a store with an Express Repair Centre, they can fix your phone on site and get it back to you in no time. If you think it might be a software issue and you're a Tech Support or Insurance customer, give Agents a call and they'll do their best to help over the phone. The service also offers a knowledge vault, free content to help you fix and master your technology: podcasts, tech news and device reviews.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10015</SourceId>
        <SourceName>ScooterMAN</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Everybody knows that you shouldn't drink and drive, but sometimes you'll have driven out and still had something to drink. ScooterMAN is a franchised service that fills a real niche in the market. It provides fully insured chauffeurs to drive customers home in their own cars. [Observations]: http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=scooterman+images&amp;hl=en&amp;rls=com.microsoft:en-US&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=XJBcUdvlJ8nQOdWlgegG&amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAQ&amp;biw=1280&amp;bih=633 [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.scooterman.co.uk/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Insured chauffeurs [SolutionDescription]: This is how it works: Customers have to become members of the ScooterMAN scheme. Then they can call up whenever they've had a drink and don't want to drive, a qualified and insured driver will be dispatched on a small scooter to pick them up. The scooter is small enough to be placed in the boot of the customer's car. The ScooterMAN chauffer will then take the customer back to their own home in their own car. The company claim that the service is cheaper than paying for a black cab for two journeys and, also, that they can answer 'emergency' call outs within 30 minutes. They have designed a fold away scooter and the bag into which it can be placed. Now they sell this, perhaps to people who wish to park their car outside the congestion zone and continue their journey by scooter.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10016</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Oyster Card</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The Oyster Card, developed as part of the 1.2billion pound Private Finance Initiative, was introduced for three reasons: first, to reduce queuing at ticket offices during peak periods; second, to make better use of staff; and third, to reduce fraud. Transport for London placed the contract with Transys, a consortium of specialist firms, for the provision of an advanced ticketing system. It was hoped that the Oyster Card would eventually replace most paper tickets. Fraud, estimated to be running at 43million pounds per year, was the main driver of the project. The main loss of revenue stemmed from customers either travelling without tickets or using tickets not valid for the whole journey. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.tfl.gov.uk/tickets/14836.aspx [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Fraud reduction [SolutionDescription]: A pre-paid card (that can be easily topped up) that is used around public transport in London. The Oyster Card not only speeds up the travel process for customers, it also makes it easy to check if the card is being used correctly through a portable hand-held machine used by ticket inspectors. The advantages are the speed and ease with which customers can get through barriers and on to the station, and also the savings that they make through using the Oyster Card. It can currently be used on the London Underground, London buses and trams, Docklands Light Railway and National Rail Services in London, providing 'seamless journeys across London'. In future, the Oyster Card will be linked to the provision of other services including shopping. This is a great example of advances in technology being applied to improve customer experience.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10017</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Federal Express</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: FedEx knew that its customers wanted to know where their packages were at every stage of their journey. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: https://www.fedex.com/fedextrack/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Tracking packages [SolutionDescription]: By adding web tracking of packages to its information systems FedEx saved itself money - an estimated $4million per year in answering telephone queries - and improved customer satisfaction. FedEx customers are automatically emailed to inform them of a package in transit, and the tracking number supplied enables the package to be tracked via the web if required.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10018</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Umpqua</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: A regional bank with over 65 branches located throughout Oregon, Umpqua was originally founded to provide loggers and farmers a banking alternative. A brand analysis revealed that Umpqua had a unique set of values: genuine, personal interactions, universal customer service, a willingness to take on the establishment, and a quirky, self-effacing style. However, these values were not being translated into the consumer experience when you walked into one of its existing branches. Umpqua's customers craved intimacy and community. They expected that if they didn't have a lot of money, they were not going to get great service. They were disenfranchised and wanted a bank that cared about them. At the time, technology was depersonalizing the banking process. Everything in the banking industry had become about efficiency and transaction. Nobody was thinking about banking as belonging or providing a sense of community. [Observations]: http://www.ziba.com/work/umpqua-bank/#/work/umpqua-bank/ [ObservedBehaviour]: https://www.umpquabank.com/Home.aspx [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Interior design [SolutionDescription]: Umpqua's innovative new store brings the human element back to an industry that had become impersonal and automated. A boutique hotel lobby where you know you can linger; they used visual cues found in retail environments such as display backlighting to highlight merchandise; and they sprinkled in a little bit of coffee shop. Consumers are invited to read the paper, enjoy a free cup of coffee, surf the internet and shop for banking products. Universal Banking Associates provide service with the care and proficiency of a boutique hotel concierge. They ensure that everyone receives first-class attention no matter the size of their bank account. A comfortable community event area, dedicated to achieving financial success, allows consumers to engage each other in a social setting. Parents even use the new store to teach their kids how to save and manage their money. Products and services are tastefully displayed to allow for easy, unpressured browsing. The space invites everyone to have an active understanding of banking. It also helps to learn how to accomplish their financial goals. Umpqua helps their consumers achieve a sense a financial comfort, this means they can afford not to think about money and enjoy their life.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10019</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Design and Sexual Health</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The UK has high rates of sexually transmitted infections (STIs) and the highest teenage pregnancy rate in Europe. Sexual health workers in Gateshead already take their contraception services out to the user; for example, workers make home visits or travel to schools and other public places to meet patients. However, Newcastle or South Shields are currently the nearest places with facilities for testing and treating sexually transmitted infections. This is a long way to travel for those without personal transport, or with limited time or low incomes. The result is that, often, the people who need the most help fall through the net. Ill-considered opening times, unwelcoming environments, a lack of information about the services available, poor transport links and concerns over privacy all discourage individuals from going to sexual health clinics. [Observations]: http://www.designcouncil.org.uk/Case-studies/DaSH/ [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.consumerfocus.org.uk/files/2012/09/DaSH-FULL-case-study.pdf [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Improve user experience [SolutionDescription]: Every PCT (Primary Care Trust) was tasked with ensuring everyone referred to a GUM (genito-urinary medicine) clinic was offered an appointment within 48 hours, including self-referrals. The new service recommendations included a hub and satellite model for service delivery supported by a mobile laboratory. Walk-in sessions available at the hub and satellite location throughout the week. Availability of extended opening hours twice a week (evening sessions) and Saturday sessions. Not themed or restricted sessions to any particular group of users. Service promotion and awareness raising through a tailored branding and publicity campaign, local television and radio broadcasts, take-away materials and health promotion presentations in schools and colleges. Development of a strong website, with online booking facilities. A single freephone number as the main portal for the telephone contact for the hub and satellite clinics. Offer of test results via text messaging. The sexual health hub/clinic should be located in central Gateshead with good connections to local transport. Design of the clinic space in such a way that the service user moves consecutively through spaces with clear and defined functions. The interior of the hub/clinic, and where possible satellite clinics, should be non-clinical, similar to the style of a hair salon or cafe. Soft furnishing should be used where possible. Colour and/or numbers should be used in different rooms to aid the feeling of progression through the service.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10020</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Streetcar</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: Car sharing is an emerging service. A car club is a service that offers members access to cars near to their homes, on a pay-as-you-drive basis. In order to persuade people to switch to this new way to using a car, the customer experience had to be better than that of buying and owning your own car. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.zipcar.co.uk/
http://liveworkstudio.com/the-customer-blah/volkswagens-quicar-is-on-the-road/
http://www.adaptivepath.com/ideas/e000896 [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: On-demand transportation [SolutionDescription]: The services are a combination of wireless technology and automobiles that are parked around cities, allowing user base to get access to a car 24 hours a day, seven days a week, for as little as an hour, without having to own a car. What they're providing is self-service, on-demand transportation. The design is meant to be simple in nature, elegant, and self-service focused. They focus on the lifetime experience that a member has with their service, from the first time they go to the web site through the last time they ever use one of the cars and decide not to be a member any more. They map that cycle and follow it; they're constantly trying to refine and improve that map, that architecture.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10021</SourceId>
        <SourceName>University of Sussex new brand identity</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: The University of Sussex was struggling to stand out from the hundreds of other institutions. To solve this problem they launched a distinctive new identity. This helped deliver a significant increase in applications from students. Universities have never had to work harder to attract funding and the best students. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.sussex.ac.uk/
http://www.designcouncil.org.uk/Case-studies/University-of-Sussex/Impact-and-results/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Distinctive identity [SolutionDescription]: The university's initials, the 'us' acronym, was designed to engage and draw people into the University with questions and invitations such as 'join us,' 'why us?' and 'discover us.' 'The 'us' acronym neatly encapsulates a sense of inclusivity', Gifford explains. 'It also allowed a significant degree of flexibility, because playing around with the word allowed the university to talk in different ways to different audiences. This keeps the identity and the relationship fresh. Blast also created a new typeface for the 'us' logo - a derivation from the Baskerville typeface that was more personal, rounded, and friendly. It identified a range of colours to be used, reflecting the natural landscape of Sussex, and a portfolio of inspirational photographic images which avoided university stereotypes such as students clutching books. This solution was inclusive, socially engaging and conveyed a sense of community. It could also be used to bring together all the schools, departments, courses and commercially focused entities under one unified brand.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10022</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Aeroportos de Portugal</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: ANA (Aeroportos de Portugal) is the state-owned company which operates Portugal's eight major airports. ANA had become specialists in operations and infrastructure to meet the needs of the airlines, their primary customers.
With rapidly changing economic conditions, increased competition, rising fuel prices and the millions of passengers using their airports, ANA realised they had to increase their offer for passengers and visitors and provide distinct and memorable customer services and initiate a shift in focus from infrastructure to service provider.
ANA asked Engine to help build a service brand and a strategy for implementation across their airports. Engine created a new role for the airport to play in passengers' experiences and outlined a sustainable customer service strategy. The new vision developed services and propositions to meet a range of customer needs, from business travellers to families, groups and connecting passengers. The project has been taken forward to have significant impact across the business, its environments, operations and culture. [Observations]: http://enginegroup.co.uk/work/ana-service-brand-strategy [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.ana.pt/en-US/Pages/Homepage.aspx [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: Distinct customer service [SolutionDescription]: The areas identified as real value propositions and customer needs were: travelling with children, airport environments, security, premium travellers and the use of technology and communications.
Family services:
Baby changing facilities
Family 'living room' spaces
Strollers provided after luggage check
ANA mascot and children's entertainer
A children's play area with seating and food preparation areas
Airport facilities and technology:
ANA 'PODs': mini-lounges where passengers can relax and access information.
ANA mobile and iPad app - to monitor flight status and more
MyAirport, a technology platform that enables all services to be accessed and subscribed to.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
    <MatchedSource>
        <SourceId>10023</SourceId>
        <SourceName>Service</SourceName>
        <Content>[Domain]: Service[ProblemDescription]: When a customer goes out for a meal, the customer should have a pleasant and memorable experience from the moment that the customer enters the restaurant to the moment the customer leaves the restaurant. Very often, in Nandos customers have to wait a while before the host greets them in a friendly manner and provides them with a table. This can be a little frustrating and acknowledging a new customer as soon as they arrive is challenging and even more so at busy times. [Observations]:  [ObservedBehaviour]: http://www.nandos.co.uk/ [TreatmentType]:  [DateOfIncident]:  [AilmentType]:  [TriggeringEvent]:  [Miscellaneous]: customer experience;greeting customers; restaurant; [SolutionDescription]: Nandos seeks to improve the customer's experience whilst in the restaurant by designating a special person to do nothing but serve the role of a host at busy times. Other Nandos employees are also encouraged to help by acknowledging customers regardless of their primary job role. An analogy used is that of Barcelona's football team to get the ball back within 6 seconds; staff are encouraged to constantly look out for new arriving customers and greet them in a friendly manner creating a warm and family atmosphere.</Content>
    </MatchedSource>
</MatchedSources>